[
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Ireland?",
    "answers":["Dublin"],
    "options":["Belfast", "Cork", "London", "Edinburgh"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of England?",
    "answers":["London"],
    "options":["Belfast", "York", "Dublin", "Edinburgh"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Idina Menzel sings 'let it go' 20 times in 'Let It Go' from Frozen",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["entertainment", "film"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Turkey?",
    "answers":["Ankara"],
    "options":["Antalya", "Istanbul", "Konya", "Islamabad"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"In what country is Catalhoyuk located?",
    "answers":["Turkey"],
    "options":["Pakistan", "Egypt", "Kosovo", "Nepal", "Brazil", "Liberia", "Ghana"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Catalhoyuk is located in which Turkish city?",
    "answers":["Konya"],
    "options":["Istanbul", "Antalya", "Ankara", "Bursa"],
    "difficulty":5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"'Mesopotamia' is translated as 'the land between two rivers', which rivers was it referring to?",
    "answers":["Tigris & Euphrates"],
    "options":["Aras & Tigris", "Seyhan River & Aras", "Euphrates & Aras"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"In which continent would you find the Yellow River?",
    "answers":["Asia"],
    "options":["Europe", "Africa", "North America", "Australia", "South America", "Antartica"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Lebanon?",
    "answers":["Beirut"],
    "options":["Tripoli", "Tyre", "Sidon", "Tehran", "Amman"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Kazakhstan?",
    "answers":["Nur-Sultan"],
    "options":["Asmara", "Amman", "Doha", "Sidon", "Aktau", "Kyzylorda"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which capital city was previously named Astana?",
    "answers":["Nur-Sultan"],
    "options":["Tehran", "Baghdad", "Doha", "Amman", "Sanaa", "Damascus", "Muscat", "Beijing", "Bangkok"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"'No one is fool enough to choose war instead of peace - in peace sons bury fathers, but in war fathers bury sons' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Herodotus"],
    "options":["Ronald Regan", "Plato", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Anazimander", "Heraclitus", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of India?",
    "answers":["New Delhi"],
    "options":["Mumbai", "Bengaluru", "Chennai", "Hyderabad", "Kolkata", "Ahmedabad", "Jaipur"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What does Buddha mean?",
    "answers":["Enlightened One"],
    "options":["Blessed One", "Patient One", "Holy One", "Chosen One"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["religion", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"How many days and nights did Buddha spend under a fig tree?",
    "answers":["49"],
    "options":["9", "29", "19", "39", "59", "69", "89", "1"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["religion", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"'Stay away from negative people. They have a problem for every solution' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Albert Einstein"],
    "options":["Ronald Regan", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Operah", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Marilyn Monroe", "Heraclitus", "Donald Trump", "Abhraham Lincoln", "C. S. Lewis", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'Everyone is a genius. But if you judge a fish by its ability to climb a tree, it will live its whole life believing that it is stupid' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Albert Einstein"],
    "options":["Ronald Regan", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Operah", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Marilyn Monroe", "Heraclitus", "Donald Trump", "Abhraham Lincoln", "C. S. Lewis", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Which Chinese ruler was famous for their Terracotta Army?",
    "answers":["Qin Shi Huang Zheng"],
    "options":["Sun Yat-sen", "Kublai Khan", "Mao Zedong", "Deng Xiaoping"],
    "difficulty":5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"In which country would you find the Tiber river?",
    "answers":["Italy"],
    "options":["France", "Nyanmar", "Russia", "Portugal", "French Guyana", "Croatia"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Black Death occur?",
    "answers":["1346 - 1353"],
    "options":["1246 - 1253", "1446 - 1453", "1646 - 1553", "1646 - 1653", "1146 - 1153"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which volcano caused the destruction of the Roman cities of Pompeii and Herculaneum?",
    "answers":["Mount Vesuvius"],
    "options":["Mount Etna", "Krakatoa", "Mount Fuji", "Mount Saint Helens", "Sakurajima"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["history", "geography", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find Mount Vesuvius?",
    "answers":["Italy"],
    "options":["Mexico", "Greece", "China", "Kazakhstan", "Barbados", "Bangladesh"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["geography", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Mount Vesuvius famously erupt and destroy Pompeii?",
    "answers":["79AD"],
    "options":["79BC", "162AD", "162BC", "20AD", "29BC", "138AD"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Mount Vesuvius erupted and destroyed Pompeii and which other city?",
    "answers":["Herculaneum"],
    "options":["Cathage", "Mediolanum", "Eboracum", "Nicomedia", "Aquileia", "Syracuse"],
    "difficulty":5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"According to the proverb, hindsight is what?",
    "answers":["Blinding"],
    "options":["Helpful", "Useful", "Steady", "Marginal", "Time consuming", "Not what you remember"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["language", "proverb"]
},
{
    "question":"'If you are depressed you are living in the past. If you are anxious you are living in the future. If you are at peace you are living in the present?', is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Lao Tzu"],
    "options":["Ronald Regan", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Operah", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Marilyn Monroe", "Heraclitus", "Donald Trump", "Abhraham Lincoln", "C. S. Lewis", "Albert Einstein"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'In a self-sufficient manner, thereby carrying all of one's food, shelter and equipment as one climbs' desribes which mountaineering style?",
    "answers":["Alpine style"],
    "options":["Expedition style", "Traditional Style", "Bouldering", "Free-Solo climbing", "Scrambling style"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who famously drew Vitruvian Man?",
    "answers":["Leonardo da Vinci"],
    "options":["Pablo Picasso", "Vincent van Gogh", "Claude Money", "Michelangelo", "Frida Kahlo"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"Who is credited with formulating the model of the universe that placed the Sun rather than the Earth at the center of the universe?",
    "answers":["Nicolaus Copernicus"],
    "options":["Albert Einstein", "Isaac Newton", "Euclid", "Alan Turing", "Galileo Galilei", "Aristotle", "Archimedes"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Edo is the former name of which capital city?",
    "answers":["Tokyo, Japan"],
    "options":["New dehli, India", "Kinshasa, Congo", "Abu Dhabi, United Arab Nations", "Kiev, Ukraine", "Hanoi, Vietnam"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Giordano Bruno was executed by the church for arguing what?",
    "answers":["That the sun was a star and the universe is infinite"],
    "options":["The bible should be translated into ordinary vernacular, for all to understand", "That his wife wasn't a witch", "The church shouldn't tax the poor", "Arguing that science was greated than God"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["history", "religion"]
},
{
    "question":"In which Indian city would you find the Taj Mahal?",
    "answers":["Agra"],
    "options":["New Dehli", "Mumbai", "Kolkata", "Bengaluru", "Chennai", "Hydrebad", "Lucknow"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["history", "religion"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the Taj Mahal commissioned by Shah Jahan?",
    "answers":["1631"],
    "options":["1731", "1531", "1600", "1700", "1500", "1431", "1400", "1100", "1131"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["history", "religion"]
},
{
    "question":"Who commissioned the Taj Mahal?",
    "answers":["Shah Jahan"],
    "options":["Samudragupta", "Ashoka Maurya", "Taj Mahal", "Maharana Pratap", "Maharana Mahal"],
    "difficulty":5,
    "categories":["history", "religion"]
},
{
    "question":"One of the most famous jewels in the world, also known as 'Le bleu de France', is called?",
    "answers":["The Hope Diamond"],
    "options":["The Beautiful Diamond", "The Blue Diamond", "The Green Diamond"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Who is an agricultural pioneer and the inventor of the seed drill, the horse drawn hoe, and an improved plough, many of the developments in the 18th century agricultural revolution?",
    "answers":["Jethro Tull"],
    "options":["Helen Sharman", "Edith Wilson", "Matthias Sindelar", "Percy Julian"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Chironex fleckeri is a of highly venomous species of what?",
    "answers":["Jellyfish"],
    "options":["Snake", "Frog", "Spider", "Octopus"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Erasmus Darwin is the grandfather of which famous scientist?",
    "answers":["Charles Darwin"],
    "options":["Marie Curie", "Isaac Newton", "Micheal Faraday"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"The word 'vaccine' comes from the Latin word 'vacca' meaning what?",
    "answers":["Cow"],
    "options":["Cure", "Health", "Immunity", "Waver", "Empty"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Who invented the world's first vaccine?",
    "answers":["Edward Jenner"],
    "options":["Galen", "Virginia Apgar", "Jonas Salk", "William Osler"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Edward Jenner created the first vaccine to combat which disease?",
    "answers":["Smallpox"],
    "options":["Bubonic plague", "Cholera", "Influenze", "Spanish Flu"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"What was issued by Abraham Lincoln on January 1, 1863?",
    "answers":["The Emancipation Proclamation"],
    "options":["Proclamation of Neutrality", "Thanksgiving Proclamation", "Proclamation of Amnesty"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the Emancipation Proclamation issued?",
    "answers":["January 1, 1863"],
    "options":["January 1, 1763", "January 1, 1895", "January 1, 1866", "January 1, 1861", "January 1, 1862", "January 1, 1869"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president issued the Emancipation Proclamation in 1863?",
    "answers":["Abraham Lincoln"],
    "options":["George Washington", "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "Theodore Roosevelt", "Thomas Jefferson", "Harry S. Truman"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which play was Abraham Lincoln attending when he was assassinated?",
    "answers":["Our American Cousin"],
    "options":["Death of a Salesman", "Our Town", "A Raisin in the Sun"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Abraham Lincoln assassinated?",
    "answers":["April 14, 1865"],
    "options":["April 14, 1963", "October 14, 1865", "October 14, 1865", "January 14, 1861", "September 14, 1861", "November 14, 1863", "November 14, 1861",  "May 14, 1861"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"In which theatre was Abraham Lincoln assassinated?",
    "answers":["Ford's Theatre"],
    "options":["Central City Opera House", "Fox Theatre", "Dock Street Theatre"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Who assassinated Abraham Lincoln?",
    "answers":["John Wilkes Booth"],
    "options":["James Earl Ray", "Derek Hymes", "Alfred Linklater"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Assassinated in 44BC, what was Caesar's full name?",
    "answers":["Gaius Julius Caesar"],
    "options":["Julius Caesar", "Julius Senneca Caesar", "Julius Albertus Caesar"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Julius Caesar born?",
    "answers":["13 July, 100 BC"],
    "options":["13 August 141 AD", "13 July, 141 BC", "13 August, 100 AD", "13 December, 41 AD", "13 January, 41 BC"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Julius Caesar die?",
    "answers":["15 March 44BC"],
    "options":["15 August 144 AD", "15 July, 144 BC", "15 August, 100 AD", "15 December, 44 AD", "15 January, 44 BC"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Hitler was named Chancellor?",
    "answers":["30th of January 1933"],
    "options":["1st of September 1939", "31st of October 1941", "16th of June 1935", "15th of December, 1920", "15th of January, 1929"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Both George Washington and Thomas Jefferson owned slaves",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the 28th U.S state?",
    "answers":["Texas"],
    "options":["Iowa", "California", "Maine", "Florida", "Alabama", "Missouri", "Arkansas", "Michigan", "Wisonsin"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Opium comes from the seeds of which plant?",
    "answers":["Poppy"],
    "options":["Guaco", "Pumpkin", "Bramble", "Chaguar", "Xate", "Mugwort"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the medical name for nearsightedness?",
    "answers":["Myopia"],
    "options":["Hyperopia", "Presbyopia", "Cataracts", "Underyopia", "Biyopia", "Amblyopia"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "medical"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the medical name for farsightedness?",
    "answers":["Hyperopia"],
    "options":["Myopia", "Presbyopia", "Cataracts", "Underyopia", "Biyopia", "Amblyopia"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "medical"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the medical name for  a 'lazy eye'?",
    "answers":["Amblyopia"],
    "options":["Myopia", "Presbyopia", "Cataracts", "Underyopia", "Biyopia", "Hyperopia"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "medical"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Hitler publish 'Mein Kampf'?",
    "answers":["1925"],
    "options":["1933", "1939", "1924", "1911", "1915"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "books"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the Wall Street Crash?",
    "answers":["1929"],
    "options":["1933", "1939", "1924", "1911", "1915", "1922", "1925"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Prohibitionin the United States?",
    "answers":["1920 - 1933"],
    "options":["1933 - 1945", "1919 - 1926", "1904 - 1911", "1911 - 1917", "1895 - 1901"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of the WW2 Project that produced the first atomic bombs?",
    "answers":["The Manhattan Project"],
    "options":["The Nuclear Project", "The Boom Project", "Project Orange", "Project Hydra", "Project Pigeon", "Project Medusa"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of the bomb used in the Trinity test in New Mexico?",
    "answers":["The Gadget"],
    "options":["Fatman", "Agent Orange", "Tiny Boy", "Little Boy"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of the bomb dropped on Nagasaki?",
    "answers":["Fatman"],
    "options":["The Gadget", "Agent Orange", "Tiny Boy", "Little Boy"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of the bomb dropped on Hiroshima?",
    "answers":["Little Boy"],
    "options":["The Gadget", "Agent Orange", "Tiny Boy", "Fatman"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Aldolf Hitler killed himself by gunshot?",
    "answers":["30 April 1945"],
    "options":["30 April 1944", "30 April 1943", "30 April 1946", "30 August 1944", "30 August 1943", "30 August 1946", "30 August 1945", "30 May 1944", "30 May 1943", "30 May 1946", "30 May 1945"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of Hitler's wife?",
    "answers":["Eva Braun"],
    "options":["Marie Müller", "Luarie Schneider", "Mia Fischer"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the first detonation of a nuclear weapon?",
    "answers":["July 16, 1945"],
    "options":["April 16, 1945", "October 16, 1945", "Decemeber 16, 1945", "April 16, 1944", "October 16, 1944", "Decemeber 16, 1944", "July 16, 1944"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"'If I need only one shirt to cover myself with but use two, I am guilty of stealing one from another. If five bananas are enough to keep me going, my eating a sixth one is a form of theft' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Mahatma Gandhi"],
    "options":["Albert Einstein", "Mother Teresa", "Martin Luther King Jr.", "Malcolm X", "Abraham Lincoln"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was assassinated on 30 January 1948?",
    "answers":["Mahatma Gandhi"],
    "options":["Indira Gandhi", "Franz Ferdinand", "Martin Luther King Jr.", "Malcolm X"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"IBM's Deep Blue chess-playing computer defeated which chess grandmaster in 1996 & 1997?",
    "answers":["Garry Kasparov"],
    "options":["Bobby Fischer", "Magnus Carlsen", "Anatoly Karpov", "Boris Spassky"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Alan Turing was convicted in 1952 for what?",
    "answers":["Gross Indecency"],
    "options":["Espionage", "Perjury", "Not fulfulling duties", "Theft"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Alan Turing die?",
    "answers":["1954"],
    "options":["1958", "1948", "1932", "1945", "1961", "1960", "1951"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of the hypothesis that the invention of artificial superintelligence will abruptly trigger runaway technological growth, resulting in unfathomable changes to civilization?",
    "answers":["The singularity"],
    "options":["Big Freeze", "The Technological Shadow", "Brink", "Runaway Computer Acceleration"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"'The universe is under no obligation to make sense to you' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Neil DeGrasse Tyson"],
    "options":["Marie Curie", "Isaac Newton", "Micheal Faraday", "Albert Einstein", "Elon Musk", "Alezia Banks"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Protons are an example of a hadron",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"A neutron is an example of a hadron",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"A Electron is an example of a hadron",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Where is the Large Hadron Collider located?",
    "answers":["Switzerland"],
    "options":["Poland", "The United States", "Britain", "Canada", "France", "Sweden", "Norway", "Denmark", "Belgium"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Approximately how far will light have travelled in a light-year?",
    "answers":["Ten trillion kilometers"],
    "options":["One year", "Ten billion kilometers", "Ten million kilometers", "Ten thousand kilometers"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"How many Voyager probes were launched?",
    "answers":["2"],
    "options":["1", "7", "13", "3", "5"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"When were Voyager 1 and Voyager 2 launched?",
    "answers":["1977"],
    "options":["1968", "1983", "1942", "1967", "1961", "1971", "1988"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Launched in 1977, Voyager 1 and Voyager 2 contained disks with music from which artist?",
    "answers":["Chuck Berry", "Beethoven"],
    "options":["Elvis Presley", "David Bowie", "Bob Dylan", "Mozart", "Bach", "Neil Young", "Aretha Franklin", "Stevie Wonder"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["music", "history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Nanosecond is a billionth of a second",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Nanosecond is a millionth of a second",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"How small is a picosecond?",
    "answers":["A trillionth of a second"],
    "options":["A millionth of a second", "A billionth of a second", "A thousandth of a second"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"How small is a nanosecond?",
    "answers":["A billionth of a second"],
    "options":["A millionth of a second", "A trillionth of a second", "A thousandth of a second"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Ulysses is a 1922 book written by whom?",
    "answers":["James Joyce"],
    "options":["Ernest Hemmingway", "Charles Dickens", "Jane Austen", "Leo Tolstoy", "Aldous Huxley", "Oscar Wilde", "F. Scott Fitzgerald"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books", "authors"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these James Joyce novels were published in 1922?",
    "answers":["Ulysses"],
    "options":["Dubliners", "Finnegans Wake", "Eveline"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books", "authors"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Edwin Hubble discovery that the universe is expanding?",
    "answers":["1929"],
    "options":["1946", "1900", "1915", "1897", "1885", "1873", "1899"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Who discovered that the universe is expanding?",
    "answers":["Edwin Hubble"],
    "options":["Galileo Galilei", "Nicolaus Copernicus", "Isaac Newton", "Carl Sagan", "Neil DeGrasse Tyson"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Who discovered that the universe is expanding?",
    "answers":["Edwin Hubble"],
    "options":["Galileo Galilei", "Nicolaus Copernicus", "Isaac Newton", "Carl Sagan", "Neil DeGrasse Tyson"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Approximately what is the square root of 2?",
    "answers":["1.4142"],
    "options":["1", "1.3141", "0.5231", "0.9248"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["math"]
},
{
    "question":"On which planet is Olympus Mons located?",
    "answers":["Mars"],
    "options":["Earth", "Neptune", "Jupiter", "Uranus", "Saturn", "Venus"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["astronomy", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"On which planet is Makalu located?",
    "answers":["Earth"],
    "options":["Mars", "Neptune", "Jupiter", "Uranus", "Saturn", "Venus"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["astronomy", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"The Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical radio Telescope is located in which country?",
    "answers":["China"],
    "options":["The United States", "Japan", "South Korea", "United Kingdom", "Russia", "Singapore"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["science", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"On the 18th of January 1778, British Explorer James Cook landed where?",
    "answers":["Hawaii"],
    "options":["Australia", "Jamaica", "Malaysia", "Tasmania"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did British Explorer James Cook reach Hawaii?",
    "answers":["18th of January 1778"],
    "options":["18th of January 1658", "18th of January 1709", "18th of January 1828", "18th of March 1438", "18th of March 1698"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Democratic Republic of the Congo?",
    "answers":["Kinshasa"],
    "options":["Goma", "Kinsangani", "Bukavu", "Mjubi-Mayi", "Conakry", "Accra", "Dakar", "Antananarivo"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1979, the World Health Organization declared what disease to be completely eradicated?",
    "answers":["Smallpox"],
    "options":["Ebola", "Rinderpest", "Malaria", "Polio", "Rubella"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["medicine", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"In 2013 Google introduced Calico, a company with the goal of solving what?",
    "answers":["Death"],
    "options":["Limited Search Results", "Internet Latency", "Every family not having access to the internet"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Finish the quote from Woody Allen, 'I don't want to achieve immortality through my work. I want to achieve it through ____'",
    "answers":["Not dying"],
    "options":["Making films until I die", "My children", "My character", "My work"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes", "entertainment"]
},
{
    "question":"'Sildenafil' is sold as what brand name?",
    "answers":["Viagra"],
    "options":["Reglan", "Zantac", "Aspirin"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1907 Oskar Pfungst investigated 'Clever Hans' an animal that could seemingly do math. What animal was Clever Hans?",
    "answers":["A horse"],
    "options":["A dog", "A cat", "A lion", "A dolphin", "An elephant", "A turtle"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Nicolae Ceausescu was former president of which country?",
    "answers":["Romania"],
    "options":["Hungary", "Bolivia", "Botswana", "Macedonia", "Kosovo", "Yemen", "Iran"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"On December 20th 2013, which country passed the Anti-Homosexuality Act?",
    "answers":["Uganda"],
    "options":["Brazil", "Bolivia", "Botswana", "Ghana", "Kosovo", "Yemen", "Democratic Republic of the Congo", "Iran", "Baghdad"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics", "law"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Narendra Damodardas Modi become Prime Minister of India?",
    "answers":["2014"],
    "options":["2016", "2012", "2013", "2011", "2015", "2017"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1917 what did Marcel Duchamps purchase, declare it art and named it Fountain?",
    "answers":["A urinal"],
    "options":["A bird feeder", "A pile of bibles", "A hose", "A pile of rubbish"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1917 what did Marcel Duchamps purchased a urinal, declared it art and named it what?",
    "answers":["Fountain"],
    "options":["Birth", "Profession", "Presence", "Signature", "Medicine", "Country"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Marcel Duchamps create 'Fountain'?",
    "answers":["1917"],
    "options":["1935", "1924", "1947", "1960", "1956", "1981"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"According to the proverb, beauty is in the eye of the what?",
    "answers":["Beholder"],
    "options":["Man", "Drunk", "Ugly", "Beautiful", "Stroke"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["proverb", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"'That 2,000-Yard Stare' by Tom Lea depicts a nameless Marine at which battle?",
    "answers":["The Battle of Peleliu"],
    "options":["The Battle of Tarawa", "The Battle of Guam", "The battle of Iwo Jima"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"The lyrics 'A little country boy' from Johnny B. Goode by Chuck Berry were originally what?",
    "answers":["A little coloured boy"],
    "options":["A little white boy", "A little happy boy", "A little lonely"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"Seoul is the capital of which country?",
    "answers":["South Korea"],
    "options":["North Korea", "Yemen", "Bangladesh", "Taiwan", "United Arab Emirates", "Qatar", "Ecaudor"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these it not a capital city?",
    "answers":["Istambul", "Geneva", "Marrakesh", "Auckland", "Rio de Janeiro", "Johannesburg", "Toronto"],
    "options":["Brasilia", "Ottawa", "Abuja", "New Dehli", "Bern", "Brussels", "Cairo"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these animals do not use echo locations?",
    "answers":["Octopuses"],
    "options":["Bats", "Whales", "Dolphins"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["nature", "animals"]
},
{
    "question":"A group of monkeys is known as a what?",
    "answers":["Troop"],
    "options":["Drove", "Pack", "Army"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["nature", "animals"]
},
{
    "question":"How many grams in 1 teaspoon?",
    "answers":["4.2 grams"],
    "options":["5 grams", "6.5 grams", "8.4 grams", "3.2 grams", "7.1 grams"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["nature", "animals"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Finland?",
    "answers":["Helsinki"],
    "options":["Copenhagen", "Oslo", "Stockholm", "Vilnius", "Turku", "Savonlinna"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Someone described as terse uses few what?",
    "answers":["Words"],
    "options":["Clues", "Technologies", "Muscles", "Of their abilities"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"The 'Molotov coctail' was named after the man who led the 1939-1940 Solveit campaign against Finland, what was his name?",
    "answers":["Vyacheslav Molotov"],
    "options":["Zarich iz Molo", "Moloslevak Tovluha", "Henri Molotov", "Molavio Abdulov", "Molein Kotov"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Norway gained independence from what country in 1905?",
    "answers":["Sweden"],
    "options":["Denmark", "Britain", "The United States", "Russia", "Finland"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Norway gain independence from Sweden?",
    "answers":["1905"],
    "options":["1962", "1931", "1959", "1899", "1875", "1913"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Norway?",
    "answers":["Oslo"],
    "options":["Copenhagen", "Stockholm", "Vilnius", "Stavanger", "Bergen", "Helsinki"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"The town of Babylon was located along the Euphrates River, about 50 miles south of which present-day capital city?",
    "answers":["Baghdad"],
    "options":["Tehran", "Ankara", "Damascus"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Operation Barbarossa was the code name for the invasion of the Soviet Union,during which war?",
    "answers":["World War 2"],
    "options":["World War 1", "The Russian Civil War", "Taiping Rebellion", "Mongol conquests"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the code name for the Axis invasion of the Soviet Union, during which World War 2?",
    "answers":["Operation Barbarossa"],
    "options":["Operation Yellow Snow", "Operation Thunder", "Operation Chimera", "Operation Anosmia"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Codenamed Barbarossa, when did the Axis invasion of the Soviet Union during World War II take place?",
    "answers":["22 June 1941"],
    "options":["22 June 1943", "22 June 1944", "22 June 1945", "22 June 1942", "22 June 1940", "22 October 1941", "22 October 1943", "22 October 1944", "22 October 1945", "22 October 1942"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the largest island in the world?",
    "answers":["Greenlands"],
    "options":["New Guinea", "Borneo", "Madagascar", "Baffin", "Sumatra", "Honshu", "Great Britain", "Victoria"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the second largest island in the world?",
    "answers":["New Guinea"],
    "options":["Greenlands", "Borneo", "Madagascar", "Baffin", "Sumatra", "Honshu", "Great Britain", "Victoria"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the third largest island in the world?",
    "answers":["Borneo"],
    "options":["Greenlands", "New Guinea", "Madagascar", "Baffin", "Sumatra", "Honshu", "Great Britain", "Victoria"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the fourth largest island in the world?",
    "answers":["Madagascar"],
    "options":["Greenlands", "New Guinea", "Borneo", "Baffin", "Sumatra", "Honshu", "Great Britain", "Victoria"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the fifth largest island in the world?",
    "answers":["Baffin"],
    "options":["Greenlands", "New Guinea", "Borneo", "Madagascar", "Sumatra", "Honshu", "Great Britain", "Victoria"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the sixth largest island in the world?",
    "answers":["Sumatra"],
    "options":["Greenlands", "New Guinea", "Borneo", "Madagascar", "Baffin", "Honshu", "Great Britain", "Victoria"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the seventh largest island in the world?",
    "answers":["Honshu"],
    "options":["Greenlands", "New Guinea", "Borneo", "Madagascar", "Baffin", "Sumatra", "Great Britain", "Victoria"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these islands is the smallest?",
    "answers":["Victoria", "Great Britain", "Honshu"],
    "options":["Greenlands", "New Guinea", "Borneo", "Madagascar", "Baffin", "Sumatra"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these islands is the largest?",
    "answers":["Greenlands", "New Guinea", "Borneo"],
    "options":["Madagascar", "Baffin", "Sumatra", "Honshu", "Great Britain"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries is not part of Borneo?",
    "answers":["Philippines", "Papa New Guinea"],
    "options":["Indonesia", "Malaysia", "Brunei"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Baffin is territory of which country?",
    "answers":["Canada"],
    "options":["The United States", "Malaysia", "Philipines", "Japan", "Indonesia", "Australia", "Great Britain"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Sumatra is part of which country?",
    "answers":["Indonesia"],
    "options":["The United States", "Malaysia", "Philippines", "Japan", "Australia", "Great Britain", "China"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Honshu is part of which country?",
    "answers":["Japan"],
    "options":["Malaysia", "Philippines", "Indonesia", "Vietnam", "Taiwan", "China"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Baffin is territory of which country?",
    "answers":["Canada"],
    "options":["The United States", "Malaysia", "Philippines", "Amsterdam", "Indonesia", "Australia", "Great Britain"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Baffin is territory of which country?",
    "answers":["Canada"],
    "options":["The United States", "Malaysia", "Philippines", "Amsterdam", "Indonesia", "Australia", "Great Britain"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the typical name for a ring with letters or a design carved into it?",
    "answers":["Signet ring"],
    "options":["Birthstone ring", "Purity ring", "Moissanite Ring", "Promise Ring"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["fashion"]
},
{
    "question":"Silent night was written originally in what language?",
    "answers":["German"],
    "options":["English", "French", "Latin", "Italian", "Egyptian"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Who originally wrote silent night?",
    "answers":["Joseph Mohr"],
    "options":["Ronald Leiber", "Woldemar Kadelburg", "Jonathan Suhren", "Daniel Warrick"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Joseph Mohr, the write of 'Silent Night' was originally from which country?",
    "answers":["Austria"],
    "options":["Germany", "Great Britain", "Ireland", "Australia", "The United States", "Amsterdam"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was superman first published?",
    "answers":["1938"],
    "options":["1948", "1924", "1905", "1914", "1883", "1876", "1868"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Azure is a shade of what colour?",
    "answers":["Blue"],
    "options":["Green", "White", "Purple", "Grey", "Brown"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["colours"]
},
{
    "question":"Bamako is the capital of which country?",
    "answers":["Mali"],
    "options":["Maldives", "Burkina Faso", "Malwai", "Angola", "Togo", "Eritrea", "Ghana", "Libya", "Gabon", "Tanzania", "Botzwana"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Kathmandu is the capital of which country?",
    "answers":["Nepal"],
    "options":["Maldives", "Qatar", "Malwai", "Angola", "Togo", "Oman", "Jordan", "Libya", "Gabon", "Yemen", "Botzwana"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is not a capital of South Africa?",
    "answers":["Johannesburg", "Durban"],
    "options":["Pretoria", "Bloemfontein", "Cape Town"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which city is South Africa's executive capital?",
    "answers":["Pretoria"],
    "options":["Bloemfontein", "Cape Town", "Durban", "Johannesburg"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which city is South Africa's judicial capital?",
    "answers":["Bloemfontein"],
    "options":["Pretoria", "Cape Town", "Durban", "Johannesburg"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which city is South Africa's legislative capital?",
    "answers":["Cape Town"],
    "options":["Pretoria", "Bloemfontein", "Durban", "Johannesburg"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which city is South Africa's largest?",
    "answers":["Johannesburg"],
    "options":["Pretoria", "Bloemfontein", "Durban", "Cape Town"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which city is South Africa's largest?",
    "answers":["Johannesburg"],
    "options":["Pretoria", "Bloemfontein", "Durban", "Cape Town"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which country was formerly known as Burma?",
    "answers":["Myanmar"],
    "options":["Bhutan", "Pakistan", "Qatar", "Sri Lanka", "Indonesia"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the ruling military junta change the Burma name to Myanmar?",
    "answers":["1989"],
    "options":["1961", "1955", "1911", "1873", "1998", "1907"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the ruling military junta change the Burma name to Myanmar?",
    "answers":["1989"],
    "options":["1961", "1955", "1911", "1873", "1998", "1907"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Rangoon was the previous name for which city?",
    "answers":["Yangon"],
    "options":["Istambul", "Saint Petersburg", "Guangzhou", "Mumbai", "Sanaa"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Naypyidaw is the capital of which country?",
    "answers":["Myanmar"],
    "options":["Cambodia", "Bangladesh", "Ghana", "Laos", "Turkmenistan", "Somalia", "Guyana", "Grenada", "Togo", "Comoros"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Tulips in Holland were originally imported from which present day contry?",
    "answers":["Turkey"],
    "options":["Brussels", "Cambodia", "Luxembourg", "Laos", "Turkmenistan", "Slovakia", "Guyana"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When did World War 2 begin?",
    "answers":["September 1, 1939"],
    "options":["February 1, 1938", "October 1, 1938", "April 1, 1939", "January 1, 1940", "January 1, 1939"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did World War 2 end?",
    "answers":["September 2, 1945"],
    "options":["February 1, 1945", "October 1, 1946", "April 1, 1945", "January 1, 1945", "January 1, 1944"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Nigeria?",
    "answers":["Abuja"],
    "options":["Niamey", "Accra", "Lagos", "Kano", "Enugu"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where did Eva Braun meet Hitler?",
    "answers":["Munich"],
    "options":["Berlin", "Bern", "Paris", "London"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Where did Eva Braun meet Hitler?",
    "answers":["Munich"],
    "options":["Berlin", "Bern", "Paris", "London"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"'For whoever has will be given more, and they will have an abundance. Whoever does not have, even what they have will be taken from them' comes from which bible verse?",
    "answers":["Matthew 25:29"],
    "options":["Isaiah 23:20", "Mark 21:2", "Psalm 29:10"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["religion", "quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'Here we must run as fast as we can, just to stay in place. And if you wish to go anywhere you must run twice as fast as that' comes from which book?",
    "answers":["Alice Adventures in Wonderland"],
    "options":["The Lord of the Rings", "The Last Unicorn", "The Name of the Wind", "The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe", "The Wonderful Wizard of OZ"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["books", "quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'He whose life has a why can bear almost any how?' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Friedrich Niezsche"],
    "options":["Ronald Regan", "Plato", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Lao Tzu", "Abhraham Lincoln", "C. S. Lewis"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"In 2018 Jordan B Peterson released his book with how many 'Rules for Life'?",
    "answers":["12"],
    "options":["5", "20", "1", "30", "10", "15", "100", "76"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"During World War II, B. F. Skinner's attempted to develop missiles guided by what?",
    "answers":["Pigeons"],
    "options":["Tornados", "Voice", "Radiowaves", "Heat", "GPS"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["science", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Socrates born?",
    "answers":["470 BC"],
    "options":["320 BC", "266 BC", "109 BC", "41 BC", "22 AD", "200 AD"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"How did Socrates die?",
    "answers":["By drinking poison"],
    "options":["A chariot crash", "Hanging", "By stabbing", "Natural causes"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Karl Marx said what is the opium of the people?",
    "answers":["Religion"],
    "options":["Opium", "Laziness", "Love", "The economy", "Money"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Karl Marx from?",
    "answers":["Germany"],
    "options":["Austria", "Belgium", "France", "United Kingdom", "Poland", "Russia"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'Cogito ergo sum' translates to what?",
    "answers":["I think, therefore I am"],
    "options":["Through adversity to the stars", "Seize the wine", "The die is cast", "Deeds, not words", "I believe because it is absurd"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"René Descartes was a philosopher from where?",
    "answers":["France"],
    "options":["Italy", "Greece", "Spain", "Belgium", "Finland"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"In which of these countries can you find Mount Everest",
    "answers":["China", "Nepal"],
    "options":["Bangladesh", "Russia", "India", "Loas", "Myanmar"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"A haiku consists of how many lines?",
    "answers":["3"],
    "options":["1", "7", "5", "15", "13", "21"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["poetry", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"The middle line of a haiku contains how many moras?",
    "answers":["7"],
    "options":["1", "3", "5", "15", "13", "21"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["poetry", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"The last line of a haiku contains how many moras?",
    "answers":["5"],
    "options":["1", "3", "7", "15", "13", "21"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["poetry", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"The first line of a haiku contains how many moras?",
    "answers":["5"],
    "options":["1", "3", "7", "15", "13", "21"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["poetry", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"A haiku is originally from which country?",
    "answers":["Japan"],
    "options":["China", "India", "Combodia", "Bhutan", "South Korea", "Philippines", "Indonesia", "Malaysia"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["poetry", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Who created the Renaissance piece, Pietá?",
    "answers":["Michelangelo"],
    "options":["Raphael", "Donatello", "Titian", "Alberto Giacometti"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"Who created the Renaissance piece, Pietá?",
    "answers":["Michelangelo"],
    "options":["Raphael", "Donatello", "Titian", "Alberto Giacometti"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the term for for deaths, injuries, or other damage inflicted on an unintended target?",
    "answers":["Collateral damage"],
    "options":["Whoopsy Whoops", "Misfire harm", "Friendly accident", "Lost fire"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"What ancient symbol depicting a serpent or dragon eating its own tail?",
    "answers":["Ouroboros"],
    "options":["La Sepienza", "Osmosis", "Ajna", "Seal of Shamash", "Alpha & Omega"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["misc", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"'Don't be a girly man' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Arnold Schwarzenegger"],
    "options":["Chuck Norris", "Hugh Jackman", "Angelina Jolie", "Harrison Ford", "Jackie Chan", "Elton John"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Which dog was originally known as a 'German Spitz'?",
    "answers":["American Eskimo Dog"],
    "options":["German Shepard", "Bulldog", "Beagle", "Rottweiler", "Dachshund", "Great Dane"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is a 'moniker'?",
    "answers":["A name"],
    "options":["An old Russian currency", "A tool", "One of Saturn's planets", "A priest"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"'Ask, and it shall be given to you; Seek, and ye shall' what?",
    "answers":["Find"],
    "options":["Discover", "Recover", "Get help", "Encounter"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["religion", "quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Which city was the capital of Nigeria before Abuja?",
    "answers":["Lagos"],
    "options":["Ibadan", "Port Harcout", "Benin City", "Kano"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which verse is 'Ask, and it shall be given to you; Seek, and ye shall find; Knock, and it shall be open unto you; For everyone who asks receives, the one who seeks find; and to one who knocks, the door will be open'?",
    "answers":["Matthew 7:7-7:8"],
    "options":["Matthew 7:25-7:31", "Isaiah 23:20-23:22", "Isaiah 7:25-7:31"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["religion", "quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was the 1943 Tehran Conference, attended by Franklin D. Roosevelt, Joseph Stalin, and Winston Churchil held?",
    "answers":["Iran"],
    "options":["Great Britain", "France", "Washington", "Russia"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["history", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Tehran Conference, attended by Franklin D. Roosevelt, Joseph Stalin, and Winston Churchil take place?",
    "answers":["1943"],
    "options":["1944", "1942", "1941", "1945", "1946", "1940", "1939", "1938"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["history", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Who did not attend the 1943 Tehran Conference?",
    "answers":["Harry S. Truman", "Aldolf Hitler", "Neville Chamberlain", "Richard Goebbels"],
    "options":["Franklin D. Roosevelt", "Joseph Stalin", "Winston Churchill"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Giovanni Gentile is sometimes called the philosopher of what?",
    "answers":["Fascism"],
    "options":["The old world", "The new world", "Stoicism", "Italian cuisine", "The youth", "Medicine"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["philosophy", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Dandelion comes from the French meaning what?",
    "answers":["Lion's Tooth"],
    "options":["Bright and Yellow", "Gift of Leon", "Bright Leaves"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["language", "flowers"]
},
{
    "question":"According to the proverb, fortune favors what?",
    "answers":["The bold"],
    "options":["The loner", "Friendship", "The famous", "The honest", "The rich"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["language", "flowers"]
},
{
    "question":"Pyongyang is the capital of which country?",
    "answers":["North Korea"],
    "options":["South Korea", "Taiwan", "Yemen", "Mongolia", "Bhutan"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"If your face is ruddy, it is what?",
    "answers":["Red"],
    "options":["Dirty", "Pale", "Ugly", "Beaten"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Havana is the capital of which country?",
    "answers":["Cuba"],
    "options":["Bolivia", "Chile", "Ghana", "South Africa", "Venezuela", "Puerto Rico"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Australia?",
    "answers":["Canberra"],
    "options":["Sydney", "Melbourne", "Perth", "Brisbaine"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"The word boycott originated in which country?",
    "answers":["Ireland"],
    "options":["England", "Spain", "Italy", "The United State", "Greece", "Australia", "Egypt"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["language", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Irish famine take place?",
    "answers":["1840's"],
    "options":["1820's", "1790's", "1800's", "1640's", "1690's", "1750's", "1830's"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Approximately how many Irish people migrated to America during the 1840's?",
    "answers":["1.5 million"],
    "options":["3 million", "500 thousand", "4.3 million", "3.7 million"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1845 the Irish blight affected which vedgetable?",
    "answers":["Potato"],
    "options":["Mushroom", "Peppers", "Carrots", "Onion"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["history", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1845 the Irish blight was caused by what microscopic fungus?",
    "answers":["Phytophthora infestans"],
    "options":["Lyria diseasus", "Microphirya sycness", "Black dethius", "Yersinia pestis"],
    "difficulty":5,
    "categories":["science", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Venezuela?",
    "answers":["Caracas"],
    "options":["Havana", "La Paz", "Barquisimeto", "Maracaibo", "Ciudad Bolívar", "Lima"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Ikigai is a Japanese word whose meaning roughly translates to:?",
    "answers":["'Reason for being'"],
    "options":["'A hope for the lost'", "'Freedom to work'", "'Vengance for the peoples'", "Death by Work"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Randolph Nesse of the University of Michigan in 2002, being what was the single largest demographic factor for early death?",
    "answers":["Male"],
    "options":["A smoker", "Young", "Old", "A heavy drinker", "A nurse"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["science", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Wellington is the capital of which country?",
    "answers":["New Zealand"],
    "options":["Falkland Islands", "Barbados", "Grenada", "Falkan Islands", "Philippines", "Nigeria"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Who famously said 'There is no great genious without a touch of madness'?",
    "answers":["Aristotle"],
    "options":["Herodotus", "Plato", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Anazimander", "Heraclitus", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"The 80/20 rule, that for many events roughly 80% of the effects come from 20% of the causes is also known as what?",
    "answers":["The Pareto principle"],
    "options":["The Thesues Ship Rule", "The Bianchi principle", "The Bruno principle", "The Gentil principle", "The Toscani principle"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Who famously said 'Men are disturbed not by things, but by the views which they take of things'?",
    "answers":["Epictetus"],
    "options":["Herodotus", "Plato", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Aristotle", "Anazimander", "Heraclitus", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Finish this Buddha quote, 'Three things cannot be hidden long: The sun, the moon and the', what?",
    "answers":["Truth"],
    "options":["The Earth", "The universe", "The stars", "God"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Who famously said 'Men are disturbed not by things, but by the views which they take of things'?",
    "answers":["Hippocrates"],
    "options":["Herodotus", "Plato", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Aristotle", "Anazimander", "Heraclitus", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu", "Epictetus"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Another Place is a piece of modern sculpture by Sir Antony Gormley, located where?",
    "answers":["Liverpool, England"],
    "options":["Doha, Qatar", "Chicago, Illinois", "Tel Aviv, Israel", "Athens, Greece", "Cork, Ireland", "Wellington, New Zealond"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["art", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"PFC is an acronym for which part of the brain?",
    "answers":["The prefrontal cortex "],
    "options":["The performance cranium", "The paramorobbi charter", "The paradox corrector", "The preelbum charge"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Harare is the capital of which country?",
    "answers":["Zimbabwe"],
    "options":["Zambia", "Nigeria", "Grenada", "Niger", "Ghana", "Guyana", "Ethiopia"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Numismatics is the study/collecting of what?",
    "answers":["Currency"],
    "options":["Numbers", "Trains", "Lint", "Door Handles", "Angles"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["science", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"Homo sapiens means what?",
    "answers":["Wise men"],
    "options":["Tall men", "Depleteing men", "Upright men", "Earthly men"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which if theses is an oxymoron?",
    "answers":["Living dead"],
    "options":["Racecar", "Happy Trucker", "Eskimo's Igloo", "Lone wolf"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"1 pound is equal to how much kilograms?",
    "answers":["0.45"],
    "options":["1.45", "2.45", "0.33", "1.33", "2.33", "1.60"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"According to British Anthropologist, Robin Dunbar, how many stable relations can a human comfortably maintain?",
    "answers":["150"],
    "options":["50", "250", "350", "450", "550", "As many friends as they have on Facebook", "650", "750", "850", "1,050"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Spain?",
    "answers":["Madrid"],
    "options":["Barcelona", "Cadiz", "Valencia", "Murcia"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of the hypothetical scenario where the universe continues to expand forever and eventually all matter reaches a final uniform state of absolute 0 temperature?",
    "answers":["Big Freeze"],
    "options":["Ice Age", "Frozen Yoghurt Theory", "Esla Paradox"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"When did US congress approve the final text of the Declaration of Independence?",
    "answers":["On July 4th 1776"],
    "options":["On July 4th 1777", "On July 4th 1779", "On July 4th 1775", "On October 4th 1777", "On October 4th 1779"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is a cross between a donkey jack and a horse mare?",
    "answers":["Mule"],
    "options":["Donkey", "Horse", "Hinny"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is a cross between a female donkey (jenny) and a male horse (stallion)?",
    "answers":["Hinny"],
    "options":["Donkey", "Horse", "Mule"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is a cross between a female donkey (jenny) and a male horse (stallion)?",
    "answers":["Hinny"],
    "options":["Donkey", "Horse", "Mule"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"From what animal's milk is the drink 'kumis' made from?",
    "answers":["Mare"],
    "options":["Goat", "Horse", "Frog", "Dog"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["drinks"]
},
{
    "question":"What type of food is Brioche?",
    "answers":["Bread"],
    "options":["Pasta", "Cheese", "Stew", "Pie", "Soup"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"Which country has a national bean dish called 'ful'?",
    "answers":["Egypt"],
    "options":["Syria", "Pakistan", "Venezuela", "Bolivia", "Liberia", "Morocco"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"Who directed the 2010 film 'Inception'?",
    "answers":["Christopher Nolan"],
    "options":["Quentin Tarantino", "Steven Spielgberg", "Martin Scorsese", "Wes Anderson", "Woody Alan", "Clint Eastwood"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Marie Curie was best known for her pioneering research on what?",
    "answers":["Radioactivity"],
    "options":["Atoms", "Electricity", "Protons", "Quantum mechanics"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Marie Curie born?",
    "answers":["Poland"],
    "options":["Britain", "Germany", "Austria", "Greece", "Lithuania", "Romania", "Italy"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What did Marie Curie die of?",
    "answers":["Aplastic anemia"],
    "options":["Suicide", "Respiratory illness", "Pneumonia", "The Spanish Flu", "Fatal insomnia"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Marie Curie born?",
    "answers":["1867"],
    "options":["1957", "1907", "1887", "1847", "1827"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Marie Curie die?",
    "answers":["1934"],
    "options":["1954", "1904", "1884", "1844", "1824", "1984"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the length of the circumfrence of the Earth?",
    "answers":["40,075km"],
    "options":["400,075km", "4,000,075km", "700,075km", "7,000,075km", "70,075km", "7,075km"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries does not use the 'dinar'?",
    "answers":["Morocco", "Sudan", "Chad", "Oman", "Yemen", "Azerbaijan", "Turkey"],
    "options":["Algeria", "Bahrain", "Iraq", "Jordan", "Kuwait", "Libya", "Tunisia"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Who wrote Don Quixote?",
    "answers":["Miguel de Cervantes"],
    "options":["Carlos Ruiz Zafón", "Javier Marías", "Camilo José Cela", "Mario Vargas Llosa"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Don Quixote published?",
    "answers":["1605"],
    "options":["1705", "1805", "1905", "1505", "1405", "1305"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"At what time was the first atom bomb detonated?",
    "answers":["5:29:45"],
    "options":["6:29:45", "8:29:45", "10:59:45", "11:59:45", "5:59:45"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"At what time was the first atomic bomb detonated?",
    "answers":["5:29:45"],
    "options":["6:29:45", "8:29:45", "10:59:45", "11:59:45", "5:59:45"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"In what month did Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin land the lunar module on the moon?",
    "answers":["July"],
    "options":["June", "January", "February", "March", "April", "May", "August", "September", "October", "November", "December"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin land the lunar module on the moon?",
    "answers":["20th of July 1969"],
    "options":["20th of July 1968", "20th of July 1960", "20th of July 1966", "1st of November 1968", "1st of November 1960", "1st of November 1966"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was the first person to walk on the Moon?",
    "answers":["Neil Armstrong"],
    "options":["Buzz Aldrin", "Michael Collins", "Yuri Gagarin"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was the lunar module pilot on the 1969 Apollo 11 mission?",
    "answers":["Buzz Aldrin"],
    "options":["Neil Armstrong", "Michael Collins", "Yuri Gagarin"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was the lunar module pilot on the 1969 Apollo 11 mission?",
    "answers":["Buzz Aldrin"],
    "options":["Neil Armstrong", "Michael Collins", "Yuri Gagarin"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Who flew the Apollo 11 command module Columbia around the Moon while his crewmates made the first crewed moon landing?",
    "answers":["Michael Collins"],
    "options":["Neil Armstrong", "Buzz Aldrin", "Yuri Gagarin", "Richard Finnegan"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which was the first mission to land humans on the moon?",
    "answers":["Apollo 11"],
    "options":["Apollo 8", "Apollo 9", "Apollo 10", "Apollo 12"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of the spacecraft that served as the crewed lunar lander of Apollo 11?",
    "answers":["Eagle"],
    "options":["Columbia", "Nightshift", "Orange", "Aberdine", "Alarm", "Ferry", "Net print"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Britain went to war with China in 1840, after China banned what?",
    "answers":["Opium"],
    "options":["Pepper", "Prostitution", "Alcohol", "Slavery", "Salt", "Homosexuality"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the first Opium war between Britain and China take place?",
    "answers":["1840-1842"],
    "options":["1880-1882", "1940-1942", "1980-1982", "1740-1742", "1780-1782", "1940-1942"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"After the First Opium War, Britain defeated China and took control of Hong Kong until when?",
    "answers":["1997"],
    "options":["1897", "1925", "1825", "1740", "1697", "1597", "1522"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography", "politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Meaning 'A minor irritation that spoils the success or enjoyment of something', the proverb says theres 'A fly in the' what?",
    "answers":["Ointment"],
    "options":["Champagne", "Soup", "1825", "1740-1742", "1780-1782", "1940-1942"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"According to the Martin Luther King Jr quote, 'Darkness cannot drive out darkness; only light can do that. Hate cannot drive out hate; only' what can do that?",
    "answers":["Love"],
    "options":["Friendship", "Protests", "Peace", "Equality"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was America named after?",
    "answers":["Amerigo Vespucci"],
    "options":["Ron R. America", "Almerica Andre", "Amer icaran", "Christopher Columbus"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Juan Rodriguez Bermejo of the Pinta spot what we now call the Bahamas?",
    "answers":["October 12th 1492"],
    "options":["October 12th 1392", "October 12th 1292", "Setpember 12th 1492", "September 13th 1392", "September 24th 1292"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Juan Rodriguez Bermejo of the Pinta spot what we now call the Bahamas?",
    "answers":["October 12th 1492"],
    "options":["October 12th 1392", "October 12th 1292", "Setpember 12th 1492", "September 13th 1392", "September 24th 1292"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"On October 12th 1492, Juan Rodriguez Bermejo of the Pinta spotted what we now call the Bahamas and reportedly shouted what?",
    "answers":["Land, Land"],
    "options":["I'm king of the world", "Were gonna need a bigger boat", "Its beautiful", "I call ye, America"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1519, Hernando Cortés landed in which modern country?",
    "answers":["Mexico"],
    "options":["Bahamas", "Peru", "Chile", "Panama"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1519, Hernando Cortés landed in Mexico and discovered which civilization?",
    "answers":["Aztec"],
    "options":["Inca"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Hernando Cortés land in Mexico for the first time?",
    "answers":["1519"],
    "options":["1492", "1522", "1452", "1561", "1421", "1498"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Who, in 1519, landed in Mexico to discover the Aztec civilization?",
    "answers":["Hernando Cortés"],
    "options":["Christopher Columbus", "Francisco Pizarro", "Amerigo Vespucci", "Marco Polo", "John Cabot"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Who, in 1522, landed in Peru to discover the Inca civilization?",
    "answers":["Francisco Pizarro"],
    "options":["Christopher Columbus", "Hernando Cortés", "Amerigo Vespucci", "Marco Polo", "John Cabot"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Francisco Pizarro land in Peru for the first time?",
    "answers":["1522"],
    "options":["1492", "1519", "1452", "1561", "1421", "1498"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1522, Francisco Pizarro landed in Peru and discovered which civilization?",
    "answers":["Inca"],
    "options":["Aztec"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1522, Francisco Pizarro landed in where to discover the Inca civilization?",
    "answers":["Peru"],
    "options":["Panama", "Bahamas", "Chile", "Bolivia", "Mexico"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"'All that I feel to be good is good; all that I feel to be bad is bad' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Jean-Jacques Rousseau"],
    "options":["Ronald Regan", "Plato", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Anazimander", "Heraclitus", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu", "Herodotus"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"When was aluminium discovered?",
    "answers":["1820's"],
    "options":["1620's", "1720's", "1920's", "1520's", "1320's", "1220's"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["science", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Some sharks must keep swimming in order to breath?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Mary Shelley publish Frankenstein?",
    "answers":["1st January 1818"],
    "options":["12th May 1860", "5th Match 1919", "2nd January 1943", "18th June 1878"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"What age was Mary Shelley when she wrote Frankenstein?",
    "answers":["19"],
    "options":["27", "33", "43", "58", "61", "70"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Mary Shelley born?",
    "answers":["England"],
    "options":["Ireland", "Switzerland", "Germany", "Poland", "Austria"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["authors"]
},
{
    "question":"Who wrote Frankenstein?",
    "answers":["Mary Shelley"],
    "options":["Edger Allan Poe", "George Eliot", "Walt Whitman", "Jane Austen", "Benjamin Constant"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["authors"]
},
{
    "question":"Where is Frankenstein set?",
    "answers":["Geneva, Switzerland"],
    "options":["London, England", "Leipzig, Germany", "Namur, Belgium", "Paris, France", "Den Bosch, Netherlands"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["books", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the temple of Apollo?",
    "answers":["Greece"],
    "options":["England", "Germany", "Belgium", "Italy", "Turkey", "Italy", "Egypt"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is inscribed at the entrance of the temple of Apollo?",
    "answers":["'Know thyself'"],
    "options":["'This too shall pass'", "'No entry'", "'No return'", "'God looks down upon ye'", "'Nevermore, never again'"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was paper money first used?",
    "answers":["China"],
    "options":["Turkey", "England", "Japan", "Taiwan", "India", "Egypt", "Holland"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Paper money was first used in China during what dynasty?",
    "answers":["The Tang Dynasty"],
    "options":["The Xia Dynasty", "The Shang Dynasty", "The Sui Dynasty", "The Han Dynasty"],
    "difficulty":5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Paper money was first used in China during what dynasty?",
    "answers":["The Tang Dynasty"],
    "options":["The Xia Dynasty", "The Shang Dynasty", "The Sui Dynasty", "The Han Dynasty"],
    "difficulty":5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Syria?",
    "answers":["Damascus"],
    "options":["Riyadh", "Jeddah", "Aleppo", "Homs", "Latakia"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of France?",
    "answers":["Paris"],
    "options":["Marseille", "Strasbourg", "Lyon", "Nice", "Bordeaux"],
    "difficulty":1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Bratislava is the capital of which country?",
    "answers":["Slovakia"],
    "options":["Slovenia", "Croatia", "Luxembourg", "Romania"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Bailey's Irish Cream founded?",
    "answers":["1971"],
    "options":["1954", "1901", "1856", "1783", "1726"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["drinks"]
},
{
    "question":"'First they ignore you, then they laugh at you, then they fight you, then you win?', is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Mahatma Gandhi"],
    "options":["Ronald Regan", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Operah", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Marilyn Monroe", "Heraclitus", "Donald Trump", "Abhraham Lincoln", "C. S. Lewis", "Albert Einstein", "Lao Tzu", "Mother Teresa", "Martin Luther King Jr."],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Pakistan?",
    "answers":["Islamabad"],
    "options":["Baghdad", "Tehran", "Lahore", "Karachi", "Multan"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Paraguay?",
    "answers":["Asunción"],
    "options":["Montevideo", "Tehran", "Bogota", "San Lorenzo", "Ciudad de Este", "Paraguay city", "Encarnacion"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Greenland?",
    "answers":["Nuuk"],
    "options":["Montevideo", "Ilulissat", "Sisimiut", "Qaqortoq", "Tasiilaq"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Jack Horner served as the technical advisor for all the Jurassic Park films, he also made a cameo which of them?",
    "answers":["Jurassic World"],
    "options":["Jurassic Park", "The Lost World: Jurassic Park", "Jurrasic Park 3"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which building has its address as 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue?",
    "answers":["The White House"],
    "options":["American Gothic House", "Franklin Court", "Benjamin Franklin House"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"The Chicxulub crater, which is believed to be left by the asteriod that killed the dinosaurs, is located where?",
    "answers":["Yucatán, Mexico"],
    "options":["Sao Paulo, Brazil", "Medeillín, Colombia", "Salvador, Brazil"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of the supercontinent that existed during the late Paleozoic and early Mesozoic eras?",
    "answers":["Pangea"],
    "options":["Pietas", "Loquor", "Amnis", "Aetas", "Quisque"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of the superocean that surrounded the supercontinent Pangaea?",
    "answers":["Panthalassa"],
    "options":["Pangea's ocean", "Antartalea", "Articuno", "Aguisque", "Volupat"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the U.S. state of New Mexico?",
    "answers":["Sante Fe"],
    "options":["Phoenix", "Albuquerque", "Las Cruces", "Roswell", "Taos"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Charles Darwin married his first cousin",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Albert Einstein married his first cousin",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Charlie Chaplin married his first cousin",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Isaac Newton married his first cousin",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find 'The Sea Organ'?",
    "answers":["Zadar, Croatia"],
    "options":["Alytus, Lithuania", "Sopron, Hungary", "Puno, Peru"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"The Mesozoic Era is divided into 3 periods, which of these is not one of them?",
    "answers":["The Curassic Period"],
    "options":["The Triassic", "The Jurassic", "The Cretaceous"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Approximately when did the Mesozoic Era take place?",
    "answers":["248 million to 65 million years ago"],
    "options":["539 million to 502 million years ago", "444 million to 345 million years ago", "64 million - 40 million years ago"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which Era is divided into three periods, the Triassic, the Jurassic, and the Cretaceou?",
    "answers":["Mesozoic"],
    "options":["Paleozoic", "Cenozoic", "Phanerozoic"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which animal has the strongest bite of any living creature?",
    "answers":["The Nile Crocodile"],
    "options":["Hippopotamus", "American Alligator", "Spotted Hyena"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of The United Republic Of Tanzania?",
    "answers":["Dodoma"],
    "options":["Dar es Salaam", "Mbeya", "Mwanza", "Tanga", "Harare", "Conakry"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Tyrannosaurus Rex's name translates to 'King Tyrant Lizard'",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Tyrannosaurus Rex's name translates to 'Reptile beast of pre world'",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Toenails grow 4 times faster than fingernails",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Fingernails grow 4 times faster than toenails",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Niger",
    "answers":["Niamey"],
    "options":["Abuja", "Maradi", "Zinder", "Agadez"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Albert Einstein born?",
    "answers":["14 March 1879"],
    "options":["14 March 1864", "14 March 1820", "14 Setpember 1879", "14 September 1864", "14 September 1820", "14 April 1901"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Albert Einstein die?",
    "answers":["April 18th 1955"],
    "options":["April 18th 1935", "April 18th 1945", "April 18th 1905", "April 18th 1895", "April 18th 1890", "April 18th 1885"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"The name Jeep comes from the army abbreviation of what?",
    "answers":["General purpose"],
    "options":["Jailed prisoner", "Absent without official leave", "Prisoner of war"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"'The distinction between past, present and future is only an illusion, however tenacious this illusion may be' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Albert Einstein"],
    "options":["Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marie Curie", "George Orwell"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the titanic sink?",
    "answers":["April 14 1912"],
    "options":["April 14 1910", "April 14 1908", "April 14 1904", "April 14 1901", "April 14 1810"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"'In times of universal deceit, telling the truth is a revolutionary act' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["George Orwell"],
    "options":["Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Which Latin phrase is 'used to refer to the fact that something has been done or repeated so often that it has become annoying or tiresome'?",
    "answers":["Ad nauseam"],
    "options":["Ad hoc", "Ad infinitum", "Ad hominem", "Ad interim"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"'The man who views the world at 50 the same as he did at 20 has wasted 30 years of his life' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Muhammad Ali"],
    "options":["Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Canada",
    "answers":["Ottawa"],
    "options":["Toronto", "Vancouver", "Montreal", "Calgary", "Winnipeg", "Quebec City"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"'Beware of false prophets, which come to you in sheep's clothing, but inwardly they are ravening wolves' is what bible verse?",
    "answers":["Matthew 7:15"],
    "options":["Matthew 9:2", "Leviticus 2:5", "Jeremiah 7:1"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes", "religion"]
},
{
    "question":"Who discovered Alzheimer's disease?",
    "answers":["Dr. Alois Alzheimer"],
    "options":["Dr. Andrew Alzheimer", "Dr. Alveris Alzheimer", "Dr. Alzheimer Muller"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Dr. Alois Alzheimer, the discoverer of Alzheimer's disease from?",
    "answers":["Germany"],
    "options":["Holland", "Austria", "Sweden", "Denmark", "Norway", "Finland", "Russia", "Lithuania", "Macedonia"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Dr. Alois Alzheimer discover Alzheimer's disease?",
    "answers":["1906"],
    "options":["1901", "1891", "1909", "1864", "1955", "1847"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["science", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"'Time and space are modes by which we think and not conditions in which we live' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Albert Einstein"],
    "options":["Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marie Curie", "George Orwell"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Biphasic sleep refers to sleep habits that involve a person sleeping for two segments per day?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Biphasic sleep refers to organisms that can allow half of their brains to sleep at different times?",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Inemuri is the Japenese practice of what?",
    "answers":["Sleeping on the job"],
    "options":["Dying alone", "Drinking while driving", "Smoking in crowded places", "Overeating"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of The Bahamas",
    "answers":["Nassau"],
    "options":["Bogotá", "Paramaribo", "Freeport", "West End", "Marsh Harbour", "Alice Town"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"'Sleep that knits up the ravell'd sleave of care, the death of each day's life, sore labour's bath, balm of hurt minds, great nature's second course, chief nourisher in life's feast' is a quote from which Shakespeare work?",
    "answers":["Macbeth"],
    "options":["Hamlet", "Romeo and Juliet", "The Tempest", "Measure for Measure"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes", "books"]
},
{
    "question":"Fatal Familiar Insomnia (FFI) is a rare sleep disorder that effects which part of the brain?",
    "answers":["Thalmus"],
    "options":["Hypothalamus", "Pituitary gland", "Cerebellum", "Cerebral cortex", "Amygdala", "Pineal gland", "Hippocampas"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Sleep habits that involve a person sleeping for two segments per day is known as what?",
    "answers":["Biphasic sleep"],
    "options":["Bilateral sleep", "Binaural sleep", "Bimetric sleep"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Amyloid beta are crucially involved in what?",
    "answers":["Alzheimer's disease"],
    "options":["Diabetes", "Herpes", "Bronchitis"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was assassinated on 28th of June 1914?",
    "answers":["Franz Ferdinand"],
    "options":["Mahatma Gandhi", "Mahatma Gandhi", "Martin Luther King Jr.", "Malcolm X"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Archduke Franz Ferdinand assassinated?",
    "answers":["28th of June 1914"],
    "options":["28th of June 1916", "28th of June 1910", "28th of June 1919", "28th of June 1917"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Archduke Franz Ferdinand assassinated?",
    "answers":["Sarajevo"],
    "options":["Berlin", "Vienna", "Riga", "Paris", "Amsterdam", "Vilnius"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Sarajevo is the capital of which country",
    "answers":["Bosnia and Herzegovina"],
    "options":["Bolivia", "Paraguay", "Lithuania", "Macedonia", "Luxembourg", "Malta", "Nepal"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these famous sports personalities died in 2020?",
    "answers":["Diego Maradona"],
    "options":["David Pearson", "Mel Hutchins", "Paul Sherwen", "Bob McNair"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Chuck Yeager was the first pilot to do what?",
    "answers":["Break the sound barrier"],
    "options":["Fly around the world in 80 days", "Fly the first manned flight", "To crash a plane", "Suicide by plane crash"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"In 2020, Senator Norma Durango proposed putting whose image on new banknotes?",
    "answers":["Diego Maradona"],
    "options":["Che Guevara", "Tulio Halperín Donghi", "Eva Peron"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"'You can fool all the people some of the time, and some of the people all the time, but you cannot fool all the people all the time' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Abraham Lincoln"],
    "options":["Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Marie Curie", "George Orwell", "Albert Einstein", "George Washington", "Winston Churchill"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'Democracy is the worst form of goverment, except for all the others' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Winston Churchill"],
    "options":["Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Marie Curie", "George Orwell", "Albert Einstein", "George Washington", "Abraham Lincoln"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these singers were born in 1982?",
    "answers":["Nicki Minaj"],
    "options":["Britney Spears", "Beyoncé", "Rihanna", "Katy Perry"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"In what game series would you play as Agent 47?",
    "answers":["Hitman"],
    "options":["Metal Gear Solid", "Halo", "Mortal Combat", "Far Cry", "Uncharted", "Watch Dogs"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["videogames"]
},
{
    "question":"In what year did the US enter WWII?",
    "answers":["1941"],
    "options":["1942", "1940", "1939", "1943", "1944", "1945", "1946", "1938"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these actors did not star in 'The Deer Hunter'?",
    "answers":["Joe pesci", "Anthony Hopkins", "Al Pacino", "Jack Nicholson"],
    "options":["Robert De Niro", "Christopher Walken", "Meryl Streep"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the American Civil War end?",
    "answers":["1965"],
    "options":["1961", "1959", "1979", "1983", "1944", "1931"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"'Do not seek revenge or bear a grudge against anyone among your people, but love your neighbor as you love yourself' is what bible verse?",
    "answers":["Leviticus 19:18"],
    "options":["Matthew 9:2", "Leviticus 2:5", "Jeremiah 7:1", "Matthew 7:15"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes", "religion"]
},
{
    "question":"Which country has a non-quadrilateral national flag?",
    "answers":["Nepal"],
    "options":["Guyana", "Marshall Islands", "Pakistan", "Macedonia", "Chad", "Malaysia", "Uruguay"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes", "religion"]
},
{
    "question":"Where were ATM's fisrt introduced?",
    "answers":["England"],
    "options":["China", "The United States", "Japan", "France", "Amsterdam"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What does ATM stand for?",
    "answers":["Automatic Teller Machine"],
    "options":["Automatically Tendered Money", "Automatic Tender Maker", "Automatic Til Market"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the first ATM introduced?",
    "answers":["1965"],
    "options":["1945", "1955", "1975", "1985"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Cornation Street start?",
    "answers":["1960"],
    "options":["1965", "1955", "1975", "1970", "1950", "1980", "1945"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"December 9 1978 saw the first women's professional league game of which sport?",
    "answers":["Basketball"],
    "options":["Baseball", "Rugby", "Soccer", "Tennis"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"On December 9, 1941, which country did China NOT formally declared war on?",
    "answers":["Britain", "Russia", "Hungary", "Romania", "Greece"],
    "options":["Japan", "Italy", "Germany"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Approximately how old is the universe?",
    "answers":["13.8 billion years old"],
    "options":[ "22.3 billion years old", "13.8 trillion years old", "22.3 trillion years old", "15.9 billion years old", "10.3 billion years old", "10.3 trillion years old"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Approximately how old is the Earth?",
    "answers":["4.5 billion years old"],
    "options":[ "12.3 billion years old", "13.8 million years old", "22.3 million years old", "7.9 billion years old", "10.3 billion years old", "10.3 million years old"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Mead is created by fermenting what with water?",
    "answers":["Honey"],
    "options":[ "Lime juice", "Ginger", "Lemon", "Poppy seeds"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["drinks"]
},
{
    "question":"Where did NASA use to run its tests because it has similar conditions to MARS?",
    "answers":["The Atacama desert"],
    "options":[ "Antarctica", "Mount Washington", "Sinabung Volcano", "Valley of Death", "Yellowstone"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Where is the Atacama desert?",
    "answers":["Chile"],
    "options":[ "Mongolia", "Mexico", "Antartica", "Namibia"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Virtually all bees have hair",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":[ "False"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Rosa Parks famously refused to give up her what, to a white man?",
    "answers":["Seat on a bus"],
    "options":[ "Children", "Secrets", "Diary"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Rosa Parks born?",
    "answers":["1913"],
    "options":[ "1933", "1889", "1873", "1852"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"A honeybee beats its wings around 10 times per second",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":[ "True"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"A honeybee beats its wings around 200 times per second",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":[ "False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Only male bees & wasps sting",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":[ "True"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Only female bees & wasps sting",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":[ "False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Which band had an album that's artwork is based on radio waves from pulsar CP 1919",
    "answers":["Joy Division"],
    "options":[ "Pink Flyod", "The Beatles", "The Artic Monkeys", "The Strokes", "AC/DC", "Bon Jovi"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"Which Joy Division album had artwork based on radio waves from pulsar CP 1919",
    "answers":["Unknown Pleasures"],
    "options":[ "Closer", "Let the Movie Begin", "Fractured Box"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"Which bees can sting?",
    "answers":["Female"],
    "options":[ "Male", "Both Male and Female", "Neither"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the paradox which describes the apparent contradiction between the lack of evidence and high possibility for extraterrestrial life?",
    "answers":["The Fermi Paradox"],
    "options":["The Expectation Paradox", "Fletcher's Paradox", "Socratic Paradox", "The Solavida Paradox"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the Big Mac debuted?",
    "answers":["1967"],
    "options":["1977", "1947", "1957", "1947", "1937", "1927", "1917", "1907", "1897"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"In which state was the Big Mac debuted?",
    "answers":["Pennsylvania"],
    "options":["Wyoming", "Florida", "Nebraska", "Kentucky", "Georgia", "Maine"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"What does Renaissance mean?",
    "answers":["Rebirth"],
    "options":["Reconstruct", "Reevaluate", "Revolution", "Reductionism"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language", "art"]
},
{
    "question":"A 'Sobriquet' is a what?",
    "answers":["A nickname"],
    "options":["A man who flirts", "A woman's hat", "A monacle", "A car part"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"'The important thing is not to stop questioning' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Albert Einstein"],
    "options":["Ronald Regan", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Operah", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Marilyn Monroe", "Heraclitus", "Donald Trump", "Abhraham Lincoln", "C. S. Lewis", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Afghanistan?",
    "answers":["Kabul"],
    "options":[ "Baghdad", "Herat", "Mazari Sharif", "Jalalabad", "Tehran"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the largest country in the world?",
    "answers":["Russia"],
    "options":[ "Canada", "China", "The United States", "Brazil"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the second largest country in the world?",
    "answers":["Canada"],
    "options":[ "Russia", "China", "The United States", "Brazil"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the third largest country in the world?",
    "answers":["United States"],
    "options":[ "Russia", "China", "Canada", "Brazil"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is largest of these countries?",
    "answers":["United States", "Russia", "Canada"],
    "options":[  "China", "Australia", "Brazil", "India"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries is the smallest?",
    "answers":["India", "Argentina", "Kazakhstan"],
    "options":["The United States", "China", "Brazil", "Australia"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which animal is the symbol of Russia?",
    "answers":["Bear"],
    "options":["A wolverine", "A lion", "A wolf", "A fox"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"The National Association for Stock Car Auto Racing (NASCAR) was founded in which state?",
    "answers":["Florida"],
    "options":["Texas", "California", "Pennsylvania", "Georgia", "Arizona"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"When was 'The National Association for Stock Car Auto Racing (NASCAR)' founded?",
    "answers":["1947"],
    "options":["1967", "1987", "1927", "1907", "1957", "1977"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the 'S' in NASCAR?",
    "answers":["Stock"],
    "options":["Shift", "Semi", "State", "Service"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the 'R' in NASCAR?",
    "answers":["Racing"],
    "options":["Rack", "Ramp", "Road", "Rear", "Rapid"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"With which sport would you assosiate Arthur Ashe?",
    "answers":["Tennis"],
    "options":["Nascar", "Soccer", "Golf", "Rugby", "Baseball"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1955 who released a single called 'Folsom Prison Blues'?",
    "answers":["Johnny Cash"],
    "options":["Bob Dylan", "Elvis", "Buddy Holly", "Ray Charles", "The Platters"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"When was The Berlin Wall built?",
    "answers":["1961"],
    "options":["1971", "1966", "1976", "1956", "1977"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was The Berlin Wall taken down?",
    "answers":["1989"],
    "options":["1971", "1966", "1976", "1956", "1987", "1986", "1986", "1990", "1992"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Ivan the Terrible from?",
    "answers":["Russia"],
    "options":["China", "Romania", "Poland", "England"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was the first tsar of Russia?",
    "answers":["Ivan the Terrible"],
    "options":["Vlad the Impaler", "Simeon Bekbulatovich", "Feodor I"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Estonia?",
    "answers":["Tallinn"],
    "options":["Tbilisi", "Bern", "Skopje", "Tirana", "Tartu", "Narva", "Vilijandi", "Kuressaare"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Vlad the Impaler from?",
    "answers":["Romania"],
    "options":["China", "Russia", "Poland", "England"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Vlad the Impaler was the inspiration for Dracula?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"Ivan the Terrible was the inspiration for Dracula?",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"Bogotá is the capital of which South American country?",
    "answers":["Columbia"],
    "options":["Venezuela", "Chile", "Ecuador", "Bolivia", "Guyana", "Suriname", "Paraguay"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Puerto Rico?",
    "answers":["San Juan"],
    "options":["Palau", "San José", "Santo Domingo", "Ponce", "Culebra", "Fajardo", "Puerto Rico City"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an example of a vestigial trait of a human?",
    "answers":["Wisdom Teeth", "Tail bone", "Palmar Grasp Reflex"],
    "options":["Eyesight", "Thumbs", "Nasal Bone", "Ulna"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is not an example of a vestigial trait of a human?",
    "answers":["Eyesight", "Thumbs", "Nasal Bone"],
    "options":["Wisdom Teeth", "Tail bone", "Palmar Grasp Reflex"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"'It always seems impossible until it's done' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Nelson Mandela"],
    "options":["Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Serbia?",
    "answers":["Belgrade"],
    "options":["Sarajevo", "Damascus", "Riyadh", "Novia Sad", "Kragujevac", "Subotica", "Petrovaradin"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Mark Twain famously stated that the reports of his what had been exaggerated?",
    "answers":["His death"],
    "options":["His success", "His affair", "His temperament", "His failures", "His sporting ability"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Who is Bart Simpson's best friend?",
    "answers":["Milhouse Van Houten"],
    "options":["Jimbo Jones", "Ralph Wiggum", "Nelson Muntz", "Martin Prince"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Lacrosse is the national sport of which country?",
    "answers":["Canada"],
    "options":["Australia", "The United Kingdom", "The United States"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these South American countries does not have Spanish as its official language?",
    "answers":["Brazil", "Falkland Islands", "Guyana", "Suriname"],
    "options":["Chile", "Peru", "Ecuador", "Argentina", "Uruguay", "Paraguay", "Bolivia", "Columbia"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these South American countries has Spanish as its official language?",
    "answers":["Chile", "Peru", "Ecuador", "Argentina", "Uruguay", "Paraguay", "Bolivia", "Columbia"],
    "options":["Brazil", "Falkland Islands", "Guyana", "Suriname"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Colombia?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Guyana?",
    "answers":["English"],
    "options":["French", "Spanish", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Suriname?",
    "answers":["Dutch"],
    "options":["French", "Spanish", "Portuguese", "English"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Antigua and Barbuda?",
    "answers":["English"],
    "options":["French", "Spanish", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Argentina?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Bahamas?",
    "answers":["English"],
    "options":["French", "Spanish", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Barbados?",
    "answers":["English"],
    "options":["French", "Spanish", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Barbados?",
    "answers":["English"],
    "options":["French", "Spanish", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Belize?",
    "answers":["English"],
    "options":["French", "Spanish", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Is Spanish the offical language of Bolivia?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Brazil?",
    "answers":["Portuguese"],
    "options":["French", "Spanish", "English", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Chile?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Costa Rica?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Cuba?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Dominica?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Dominican Republic?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Ecuador?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of El Salvador?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Grenada?",
    "answers":["English"],
    "options":["French", "Spanish", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Guyana?",
    "answers":["English"],
    "options":["French", "Spanish", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Honduras?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Mexico?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Panama?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is an official language of Uruguay?",
    "answers":["Spanish"],
    "options":["French", "English", "Portuguese", "Dutch"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Osama Bin Laden was from which country?",
    "answers":["Saudi Arabia"],
    "options":["Pakistan", "Iraq", "Iran", "Syria"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Osama Bin Laden was found in 2011 hiding in which country?",
    "answers":["Pakistan"],
    "options":["Saudi Arabia", "Iraq", "Iran", "Syria"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Osama Bin Laden was killed?",
    "answers":["2011"],
    "options":["2013", "2015", "2009", "2007", "2005", "2003"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the longest river in the world?",
    "answers":["Nile"],
    "options":["Amazon River", "Yangtze", "Yellow River"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the second longest river in the world?",
    "answers":["Amazon River"],
    "options":["Nile", "Yangtze", "Yellow River"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these rivers if the shortest?",
    "answers":["Niger", "Congo River"],
    "options":["Nile", "Yangtze", "Yellow River", "Amazon River"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries was not originally part of The European Coal & Steel Community, which eventually became the EU?",
    "answers":["The United Kingdom", "Spain", "Ireland"],
    "options":["Belgium", "France", "Netherlands", "Italy", "Luxembourg"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was The European Coal & Steel Community, which eventually became the EU, formed?",
    "answers":["1951"],
    "options":["1961", "1941", "1931", "1921", "1911"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"In what decade did the Cuban Missile Crisis take place?",
    "answers":["1960's"],
    "options":["1970's", "1950's", "1940's", "1930's"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Sudan?",
    "answers":["Khartoum"],
    "options":["Juba", "Kinsasha", "Port Sudan", "Omdurman", "Nyala"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"BRICS is an acronym for the major emerging national economies, which of these countries is not a part of it?",
    "answers":["Bolivia", "Romania", "Ireland", "Canada", "Chile", "Cameroon", "Saudi Arabia0"],
    "options":["Brazil", "Russia", "India", "China", "South Africa"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"How many countries start with the letter R?",
    "answers":["5"],
    "options":["3", "4", "6", "7", "8", "9", "10"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"'War is peace, Freedom is slavery, Ignorance is strength' is a quote from which George Orwell novel?",
    "answers":["1984"],
    "options":["Animal Farm", "Homage to Catalonia", "Burmese Days"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["quotes", "books"]
},
{
    "question":"'War is peace, Freedom is slavery, Ignorance is strength' is a quote from which George Orwell novel?",
    "answers":["1984"],
    "options":["Animal Farm", "Homage to Catalonia", "Burmese Days"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["quotes", "books"]
},
{
    "question":"Launched in 1980, what does CNN stand for?",
    "answers":["Cable News Network"],
    "options":["Controlled News Notifications", "Constant Neverending News", "Corroborated Nuetral News"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these artists released an album 'Born in the USA'?",
    "answers":["Bruce Springsteen"],
    "options":["Elvis Presley", "George Michael", "The Cure", "Elton John", "Guns N' Roses"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"Who created the Simpsons?",
    "answers":["Matt Groening"],
    "options":["Seth Macfarlane", "Trey Parker", "Matt Stone", "Justin Roiland", "Dan Harmon"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Who created the Simpsons?",
    "answers":["Matt Groening"],
    "options":["Seth Macfarlane", "Trey Parker", "Matt Stone", "Justin Roiland", "Dan Harmon"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Created by Justin Roiland and Dan Harmon, the main characters of the show are Rick and who?",
    "answers":["Morty"],
    "options":["Martin", "Markis", "Matt", "Marshall", "Mitchel"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Created by Justin Roiland and Dan Harmon, the main characters of the show are Morty and who?",
    "answers":["Rick"],
    "options":["Roiland", "Dan", "Chase", "Marshall", "Harry"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Created by Justin Roiland and Dan Harmon, the main characters of the show are Morty and who?",
    "answers":["Rick"],
    "options":["Roiland", "Dan", "Chase", "Marshall", "Harry"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Acrophobia is an extreme/irrational fear of what?",
    "answers":["Heights"],
    "options":["Clowns", "Farming", "Running", "Speed", "Spiders"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was the first person to journey into space?",
    "answers":["Yuri Gagarin"],
    "options":["Neil Armstrong", "Buzz Aldrin", "Alan Shepard"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Yuri Gagarin become the first person to journey into space?",
    "answers":["1961"],
    "options":["1969", "1965", "1957", "1953", "1950", "1949"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Simón Bolívar was a political leader during the independence wars from the Spanish empire, where was he from?",
    "answers":["Venezuela"],
    "options":["Columbia", "Panama", "Ecaudor", "Peru", "Chile", "Peru", "Brazil"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Simón Bolívar was a political leader who led countries to independence from which empire?",
    "answers":["The Spanish Empire"],
    "options":["The British Empire", "The Portuguese Empire", "The Roman Empire"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Simón Bolívar was a political leader who led countries to independence from which empire?",
    "answers":["The Spanish Empire"],
    "options":["The British Empire", "The Portuguese Empire", "The Roman Empire"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"'Laugh and the whole world laughs with you, weep and you weep alone' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Ella Wheller Wilcox"],
    "options":["Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Colony collapse disorder affects what organisms",
    "answers":["Bees"],
    "options":["Birds", "Ants", "Reef"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["nature", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Colony collapse disorder affects what organisms",
    "answers":["Bees"],
    "options":["Birds", "Ants", "Reef"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["nature", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"'To light a candle is to cast a shadow' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Ursula Le Guin"],
    "options":["Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"On which continent is Yellowstone National Park located?",
    "answers":["North America"],
    "options":["South America", "Europe", "Asia", "Antarctica", "Africa", "Australia"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"In which state is Yellowstone National Park located?",
    "answers":["Wyonming"],
    "options":["New Mexico", "Louisiana", "Connecticut", "South Carolina", "Nebraska", "Texas", "Iowa", "Arkansas", "Kentucky", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the most abundant element on the Earth's crust?",
    "answers":["Oxegen"],
    "options":["Silicon", "Aluminium", "Iron", "Calcium", "Sodium", "Magnesium", "Potassium", "Titanium", "Hydrogen"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the second most abundant element on the Earth's crust?",
    "answers":["Silicon"],
    "options":["Oxegen", "Aluminium", "Iron", "Calcium", "Sodium", "Magnesium", "Potassium", "Titanium", "Hydrogen"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the third most abundant element on the Earth's crust?",
    "answers":["Aluminium"],
    "options":["Oxegen", "Silicon", "Iron", "Calcium", "Sodium", "Magnesium", "Potassium", "Titanium", "Hydrogen"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which element has the Symbol 'H'?",
    "answers":["Hydrogen"],
    "options":["Helium", "Hafnium", "Hassium"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which element has the Symbol 'He'?",
    "answers":["Helium"],
    "options":["Hydrogen", "Hafnium", "Hassium"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which element has the Symbol 'Li'?",
    "answers":["Lithium"],
    "options":["Iron", "Lanthanum", "Lead"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which element has the Symbol 'Be'?",
    "answers":["Berylium"],
    "options":["Boron", "Lanthanum", "Bromine"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which element has the Symbol 'B'?",
    "answers":["Boron"],
    "options":["Barium", "Berylium", "Bromine", "Berkelium"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which element has the Symbol 'C'?",
    "answers":["Carbon"],
    "options":["Calcium", "Cerium", "Cadmium", "Chlorine"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which element has the Symbol 'N'?",
    "answers":["Nitrogen"],
    "options":["Neon", "Nickel", "Niobium"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which element has the Symbol 'O'?",
    "answers":["Oxegen"],
    "options":["Orium", "Osmium", "Oganesson"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of flourine?",
    "answers":["F"],
    "options":["Fl", "Fe", "Ao"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of sodium?",
    "answers":["Na"],
    "options":["S", "So", "Sl", "No", "Cl"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of magnesium?",
    "answers":["Mg"],
    "options":["M", "Ma", "Mm"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of aluminium?",
    "answers":["Al"],
    "options":["A", "Au", "Am"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of silicon?",
    "answers":["Si"],
    "options":["S", "Sl", "Sn", "Ti", "Sc"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of phosphorus?",
    "answers":["P"],
    "options":["Ph", "Ps", "Fe", "G"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of sulfur?",
    "answers":["S"],
    "options":["Su", "Sl", "Sf"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which element has the Symbol 'S'?",
    "answers":["Sulfur"],
    "options":["Silicon", "Silver", "Sodium"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of chlorine?",
    "answers":["Cl"],
    "options":["C", "Ce", "Sf"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of argon?",
    "answers":["Ar"],
    "options":["Ag", "A", "An", "V"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of potassium?",
    "answers":["K"],
    "options":["P", "Pm", "Po", "Ge"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which element has the Symbol 'K'?",
    "answers":["Potassium"],
    "options":["Krypton", "Kiridium", "Kilium"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of calcium?",
    "answers":["Ca"],
    "options":["C", "Cl", "Cm", "No"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of titanium?",
    "answers":["Ti"],
    "options":["T", "Pm", "Tm", "Tt"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of chromium?",
    "answers":["Cr"],
    "options":["C", "Cm", "Ch", "Go"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of iron?",
    "answers":["Fe"],
    "options":["Ir", "I", "In", "Ni"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of cobalt?",
    "answers":["Co"],
    "options":["C", "Cm", "Cb", "Ct"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of nickel?",
    "answers":["Ni"],
    "options":["N", "Nk", "Nl"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of copper?",
    "answers":["Cu"],
    "options":["C", "Cp", "Cr", "Ge", "Ga"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of zinc?",
    "answers":["Zn"],
    "options":["Z", "Zi", "Po", "Ge"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of krypton?",
    "answers":["Kr"],
    "options":["K", "Kn", "Nb", "Kp"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of silver?",
    "answers":["Ag"],
    "options":["S", "Sl", "Si", "Sv", "Sb", "Cd"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of Tin?",
    "answers":["Sn"],
    "options":["S", "T", "Ti", "Tn"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of iodine?",
    "answers":["I"],
    "options":["Io", "Id", "La", "Tc"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of iridium?",
    "answers":["Ir"],
    "options":["I", "Im", "Ii", "Hg"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Is krypton a real chemical element?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of platinum?",
    "answers":["Pt"],
    "options":["P", "Pm", "Pu", "Pl", "Ir"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of gold?",
    "answers":["Au"],
    "options":["G", "Gl", "Gd", "Ao", "Na"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of mercury?",
    "answers":["Hg"],
    "options":["My", "M", "Me", "Mr", "Pb"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of lead?",
    "answers":["Pb"],
    "options":["L", "Le", "Ld", "Rn"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of radium?",
    "answers":["Ra"],
    "options":["R", "Rd", "Rm", "Pu", "Bi"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of uranium?",
    "answers":["U"],
    "options":["Ur", "Pa", "Un", "Po"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the chemical symbol of plutonium?",
    "answers":["Pu"],
    "options":["P", "Pm", "Pl", "Bk"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was born on 12th February 1809?",
    "answers":["Charles Darwin", "Abraham Lincoln"],
    "options":["Albert Einstein", "Thomas Edison", "Robert E. Lee", "Clara Barton"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Abraham Lincoln was born on 12th February 1809, who else was born on the exact same day?",
    "answers":["Charles Darwin"],
    "options":["Albert Einstein", "Thomas Edison", "Robert E. Lee", "Clara Barton"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Abraham Lincoln born?",
    "answers":["Kentucky"],
    "options":["New Mexico", "Louisiana", "Connecticut", "South Carolina", "Nebraska", "Texas", "Iowa", "Arkansas", "Florida", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"According to the decleration of independence, what is not an unalienable right of men?",
    "answers":["Love", "Privacy", "Vote"],
    "options":["Life", "Liberty", "The persuit of happiness"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Macedonia?",
    "answers":["Skopje"],
    "options":["Riga", "Macedonia city", "Bitola", "Ohrid", "Veles", "Prilep", "Tetovo"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Mother Teresa born?",
    "answers":["Macedonia"],
    "options":["Poland", "Russia", "India", "Austria", "Romania", "Serbia", "Albania", "Montenegro"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Mother Teresa born?",
    "answers":["1910"],
    "options":["1930", "1940", "1890", "1870", "1850"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Mother Teresa die?",
    "answers":["1997"],
    "options":["1987", "2007", "1977", "1967", "1957"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"'Of course it is happening inside your head, Harry, but why on earth should that mean that it is not real' is a quote from which Harry Potter character?",
    "answers":["Albus Dumbledore"],
    "options":["Hagrid", "Hermione Grange", "Luna Lovegood", "Ron Weasley"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Mary Schmich 'worrying is as effective as trying to solve an algebra equation by' doing what?",
    "answers":["Chewing gum"],
    "options":["Consulting a monkey", "Wasting time", "Hiring a troop of monkeys to solve it", "Watching TV", "Muttering nonsensically"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Will a fresh egg will sink in water?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"Will a fresh egg will float in water?",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"'The weak can never forgive. Forgiveness is an attribute of the strong' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Mohandas Gandhi"],
    "options":["Ursula Le Guin", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the tallest building in the world?",
    "answers":["Dubai"],
    "options":["Shanghai", "Tokyo", "Al Haram", "Shenzhen"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography", "architecture"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the tallest building in the world?",
    "answers":["Burj Khalifa"],
    "options":["Shanghai Tower", "Makkah Clock Tower", "Lotte World Tower", "Empire State Building"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["misc", "architecture"]
},
{
    "question":"How tall is the Burj Khalifa?",
    "answers":["828m"],
    "options":["878m", "1028m", "1078m", "626m", "678m", "1228m", "1278m"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc", "architecture"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the Burj Khalifa built?",
    "answers":["2009"],
    "options":["2004", "2000", "2012", "2016", "1997", "1991", "1993", "1897"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc", "architecture"]
},
{
    "question":"What did Anne Frank name her diary?",
    "answers":["Kitty"],
    "options":["Minnie", "Lucky", "The Frank secret memory box", "Tigger", "Aiva", "Domino"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Ludwig Van Beethoven born?",
    "answers":["Germany"],
    "options":["Romania", "Austria", "Poland", "Greece", "The United Kingdom"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Ludwig Van Beethoven born?",
    "answers":["Germany"],
    "options":["Romania", "Austria", "Poland", "Greece", "The United Kingdom"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Ludwig Van Beethoven born?",
    "answers":["1770"],
    "options":["1870", "1670", "1570", "1470", "1370"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"'Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Arthur C. Clarke"],
    "options":["Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Who wrote '2001:A Space Odyssey'?",
    "answers":["Arthur C. Clarke"],
    "options":["Isaac Asimov", "Ray Bradbury", "Philip K. Dick", "Orson Scott Card", "Harlan Ellison"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the furthest point on Earth from Earth's center?",
    "answers":["Mount Chimborazo's peak"],
    "options":["K2's peak", "Mount Everest's peak", "Burj Khalifa's peak"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the highest mountain on Earth?",
    "answers":["Mount Everest"],
    "options":["K2", "Kangchenjunga", "Lhotse", "Makalu"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Where is Mount Chimborazo located?",
    "answers":["Ecuador"],
    "options":["Chile", "India", "China", "Bhutan", "Antartica", "Nepal", "Tajikstan", "Afghanistan", "Andorra", "Lesotho"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Ecaudor?",
    "answers":["Quito"],
    "options":["Belmopan", "Ecaudor city", "Equalia", "Cuenca", "Manta"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Was Ecaudor was named after the Equator?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Was Ecaudor was named after an equinox?",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When was radium discovered?",
    "answers":["1928"],
    "options":["1907", "1946", "1894", "1749", "1856", "1822", "1827"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was Walt Disney's first feature-length animated film?",
    "answers":["Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs"],
    "options":["Pinocchio", "Fantasia", "Dumbo", "Cinderella", "Treasure Island"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1968 which Glen Campell album went to no.1 in the United States?",
    "answers":["Wichita Lineman"],
    "options":["Galveston", "That Christmas Feeling", "True Grit", "Hey Little One"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"Huckleberry Finn escaped his foster family by sailing on a rift on which river?",
    "answers":["Missouri River"],
    "options":["Mississippi River", "Yukon River", "Rio Grande", "Snake River"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Solveit Union lauched Sputnik 1, the first artificial satelite?",
    "answers":["October 4th 1957"],
    "options":["October 4th 1961", "October 4th 1951", "October 4th 1947", "October 4th 1941", "April 7th 1957", "April 7th 1961", "April 7th 1951", "April 7th 1947", "April 7th 1941"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Launched in 1957, what was the name of the first artificial satelite?",
    "answers":["Sputnik 1"],
    "options":["Internation Space Station", "Explorer 1", "Skylab", "Telstar 1", "Aryabhata"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"How long does it take the Sun's light to reach Earth?",
    "answers":["8 minutes and 20 seconds"],
    "options":["82 seconds", "1 day", "8 hours 20 minutes", "24 minutes 50 seconds", "24 seconds", "24 hours and 50 minutes", "3.5 minutes"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Assassinated alongside him, what was the name of Franz Ferdinand's wife?",
    "answers":["Sophie"],
    "options":["Katie", "Maggie", "Maddie", "Averie", "Ellie", "Sadie", "Valerie"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Croatia?",
    "answers":["Zagreb"],
    "options":["Dubrovnik", "Split", "Zadar", "Pula", "Rijeka"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the first motorized flight?",
    "answers":["December 17, 1903"],
    "options":["December 17, 1913", "December 17, 1923", "December 17, 1933", "December 17, 1943", "December 17, 1953", "December 17, 1893"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"On November 17 2020, Barak Obama published his memoir entitled what?",
    "answers":["A Promised Land"],
    "options":["Yes We Can", "Hard Choices", "Long Walk to Freedom", "Open", "Change We Need", "Change We Can Believe in"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"Golden Delicious is which type of fruit?",
    "answers":["Apple"],
    "options":["Grape", "Banana", "Pineapple", "Orange", "Lemon", "Mango", "Peach", "Passion fruit"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"Written by Edwin Abbott and published in 1992, what is the name of his book about a 2 dimenional love story?",
    "answers":["Flatland"],
    "options":["2D World", "3 Dimensional heart", "Flatline", "2D"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"On July 1914, Germany offered unconditional support for Austria-Hungary in an event that has become known as the what?",
    "answers":["Blank cheque"],
    "options":["Clean slate", "Blind Eye", "Bitten bullet", "Blue moon", "Blind treaty"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Germany offer unconditional support for Austria-Hungary, known as the 'Blank Cheque'?",
    "answers":["July 5 1914"],
    "options":["July 5 1915", "July 5 1916", "July 5 1917", "July 5 1913", "July 5 1912", "October 23 1914", "October 23 1915", "October 23 1916", "October 23 1917", "October 23 1913", "October 23 1912", "April 11 1914", "April 11 1915", "April 11 1916", "April 11 1917", "April 11 1913", "April 11 1912"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Haiti?",
    "answers":["Port-au-prince"],
    "options":["Bridgetown", "Suva", "Cap-Haitien", "Jacmel", "Les Cayes", "Petion-Ville"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Henry Ford famously said 'A customer can have their car painted any colour he wants, as long as its' what colour?",
    "answers":["Black"],
    "options":["White", "Silver", "Green", "Blue"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Henry Ford famously said 'A customer can have their car painted any colour he wants, as long as its' what?",
    "answers":["Black"],
    "options":["Cheap", "Easy on the eyes", "Bright", "A colour of the American flag", "Possible"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Which series of car is regarded as the first affordable car?",
    "answers":["Ford T Model"],
    "options":["BMC Mini", "Citroen DS", "Volkswagen Beetle", "Ford Model BB", "Volkswagen Golf Mk1"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["transport", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1956, Colo became the first what to be born into captivity?",
    "answers":["Gorilla"],
    "options":["Elephant", "Seal", "Giraffe", "Penguin", "Lion"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["misc", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1956, the first gorilla to be born into capitivity was named what?",
    "answers":["Colo"],
    "options":["Rolo", "Molo", "Yolo", "Solo", "Bolo", "Dolo", "Lolo", "Nolo"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["misc", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these TV shows was not created by Matt Groening?",
    "answers":["Rick and Morty", "Big Mouth", "Metalocalypse", "The Awesomes", "Daria"],
    "options":["Futurama", "The Simpsons", "Disenchantment"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"What is 36 x 3?",
    "answers":["108"],
    "options":["138", "112", "102", "96", "118"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["math"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the square root of 64?",
    "answers":["8"],
    "options":["2", "4", "6", "12"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["math"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the square root of 121?",
    "answers":["11"],
    "options":["7", "9", "13"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["math"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the square root of 256?",
    "answers":["16"],
    "options":["12", "13", "18", "8", "14"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["math"]
},
{
    "question":"What is three fifths as a decimal?",
    "answers":["0.6"],
    "options":["0.8", "0.2", "0.34", "6"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["math"]
},
{
    "question":"How many months are there in 5 years?",
    "answers":["60"],
    "options":["80", "58", "48", "84", "64"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["math"]
},
{
    "question":"What is 3 - 7 x 4?",
    "answers":["-25"],
    "options":["25", "-24", "-16", "16", "-29"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["math"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Uganda?",
    "answers":["Kampala"],
    "options":["Harare", "Dodoma", "Nicosia", "Entebbe", "Gulu", "Jinja"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"'Rough diamonds may sometimes be mistaken for worthless pebbles' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Thomas Browne"],
    "options":["Ursula Le Guin", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'Trouble shared is trouble halved' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Lee Lacocca"],
    "options":["Ursula Le Guin", "Thomas Browne", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Certain land snails can sleep for up to three years",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Certain land snails can sleep for up to eight years",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the only country to have a square flag",
    "answers":["Switzerland"],
    "options":["Myanimar", "Nepal", "Saudi Arabia", "Slovakia", "Ghana", "Tanzania", "Lethoso", "Nauru", "Fiji"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Switzerland",
    "answers":["Bern"],
    "options":["Zurich", "Geneva", "Basel", "Lucerne"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"In the 2009 film 'Public Enemies' Johnny Depp portrays which gangster?",
    "answers":["John Dillinger"],
    "options":["Baby Face Nelson", "Al Capone", "Bugsy Siegel", "Pretty Boy Floyd", "Jesse James"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"On July 22nd 1934, Federal agents shot which criminal in Chicago?",
    "answers":["John Dillinger"],
    "options":["Baby Face Nelson", "Al Capone", "Bugsy Siegel", "Pretty Boy Floyd", "Jesse James"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did federal agents shoot and kill John Dillinger in Chicago?",
    "answers":["July 22nd 1934"],
    "options":["July 22nd 1954", "July 22nd 1914", "July 22nd 1894", "December 22nd 1934", "December 22nd 1954", "December 22nd 1914", "December 22nd 1894"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was John Dillinger exiting when he was shot and killed in 1934?",
    "answers":["Theatre"],
    "options":["Casino", "His home", "A bank", "A phone booth"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was John Dillinger when he was shot and killed by federal agents in 1934?",
    "answers":["Chicago, Illinois"],
    "options":["Los Angeles, California", "San Francisco, California", "Boston, Massachusetts", "Seattle, Washingston", "Philadelphia, Pennsylvania", "Detroit, Michigan", "New Orleans, Louisiana", "Denver, Colorado", "San Antonio, Texas", "Portland, Oregan", "Houston, Texas", "Austin, Texas", "Phoenix, Arizona", "Nashville, Tennessee", "San Jose, California", "Miami, Florida", "Charlotte, North Carolina", "Atlanta, Georgia", "Minneapolis, Minnesota", "Las Vegas, Nevada", "Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Chicago?",
    "answers":["Illinois"],
    "options":["California", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Texas", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Los Angeles?",
    "answers":["California"],
    "options":["Illinois", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Texas", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of San Francisco?",
    "answers":["California"],
    "options":["Illinois", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Texas", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Boston?",
    "answers":["Massachusetts"],
    "options":["Illinois", "California", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Texas", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Seattle?",
    "answers":["Washingston"],
    "options":["Illinois", "California", "Pennsylvania", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Texas", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Philadelphia?",
    "answers":["Pennsylvania"],
    "options":["Illinois", "California", "Washingston", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Texas", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Detroit?",
    "answers":["Michigan"],
    "options":["California", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Texas", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of New Orleans?",
    "answers":["Louisiana"],
    "options":["California", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Colorado", "Texas", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Denver?",
    "answers":["Colorado"],
    "options":["California", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Texas", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of San Antonio?",
    "answers":["Texas"],
    "options":["California", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Portland?",
    "answers":["Oregan"],
    "options":["California", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Texas", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Houston?",
    "answers":["Texas"],
    "options":["California", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Austin?",
    "answers":["Texas"],
    "options":["California", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Phoenix?",
    "answers":["Arizona"],
    "options":["California", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Oregan", "Texas", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Nashville?",
    "answers":["Tennessee"],
    "options":["California", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Oregan", "Texas", "Arizona", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of San Jose?",
    "answers":["California"],
    "options":["Tennessee", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Oregan", "Texas", "Arizona", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Miami?",
    "answers":["Florida"],
    "options":["Tennessee", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Oregan", "Texas", "Arizona", "California", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Charlotte?",
    "answers":["North Carolina"],
    "options":["Tennessee", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Oregan", "Texas", "Arizona", "California", "Florida", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Atlanta?",
    "answers":["Georgia"],
    "options":["Tennessee", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Oregan", "Texas", "Arizona", "California", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Minneapolis?",
    "answers":["Minnesota"],
    "options":["Tennessee", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Oregan", "Texas", "Arizona", "California", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Las Vegas?",
    "answers":["Nevada"],
    "options":["Tennessee", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Oregan", "Texas", "Arizona", "California", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Pittsburgh?",
    "answers":["Pennsylvania"],
    "options":["Tennessee", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Nevada", "Illinois", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Oregan", "Texas", "Arizona", "California", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Bernard Shaw born?",
    "answers":["Ireland"],
    "options":["England", "The United States", "Germany", "Austria", "Australia"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Bernard Shaw born?",
    "answers":["1856"],
    "options":["1956", "1756", "1656", "1801", "1901", "1701", "1601"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Bernard Shaw die?",
    "answers":["1950"],
    "options":["1951", "1751", "1651", "1801", "1901", "1701", "1601"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the chernobyl disaster occur?",
    "answers":["26 April 1986"],
    "options":["26 October 1986", "26 April 1982", "26 October 1982", "26 April 1976",  "26 October 1976", "26 April 1971", "26 October 1971", "26 April 1979", "26 October 1979"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Chevon is the meat of which animal?",
    "answers":["Goat"],
    "options":["Calf", "Pigeon", "Deer", "Turkey"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"Squad is the meat of which animal?",
    "answers":["Pigeon"],
    "options":["Calf", "Goat", "Deer", "Turkey"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"Venison is the meat of which animal?",
    "answers":["Deer"],
    "options":["Calf", "Goat", "Pigeon", "Turkey"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"'You can't shake hands with a clenched fist' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Indira Gandi"],
    "options":["Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What does the title 'King' tell you about a snake?",
    "answers":["They eat other snakes"],
    "options":["Theyre the biggest of their family", "Theyre venemous", "They have 2 heads", "They can spit"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What president was JFK?",
    "answers":["35th"],
    "options":["37th", "36th", "38th", "39th", "34th"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["misc", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"When did JFK become president?",
    "answers":["1961"],
    "options":["1967", "1964", "1955", "1957", "1950", "1949"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was JFK assassinated?",
    "answers":["1963"],
    "options":["1961", "1969", "1965", "1954", "1950", "1967"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"'Man - A being in search of meaning' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Plato"],
    "options":["Ronald Regan", "Herodotus", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Anazimander", "Heraclitus", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'Many a trip continues long after movement in time and space have ceased' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["John Steinbeck"],
    "options":["Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'That which does not kill us makes us stronger' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Freidrich Nietzche"],
    "options":["Plato", "Ronald Regan", "Herodotus", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Anazimander", "Heraclitus", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'You must be the change you wish to see in the world' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Mohandas Gandhi"],
    "options":["Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "John Steinbeck", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"The distress code 'Mayday' comes from what French phrase?",
    "answers":["M'aide"],
    "options":["M'aime", "m'aller", "M'être"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Insider, Which of these words has the most definitions in English?",
    "answers":["Set", "Run"],
    "options":["Go", "Take", "Stand", "Get", "Turn", "Put", "Fall"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"'Wars begin when you will, but they do not end when you please' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Nicoló Machiavelli"],
    "options":["Plato", "Ronald Regan", "Herodotus", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Anazimander", "Heraclitus", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Nicoló Machiavelli is from which country?",
    "answers":["Italy"],
    "options":["Greece", "France", "Austria", "Amsterdam"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Nicoló Machiavelli born?",
    "answers":["1469"],
    "options":["1569", "1669", "1369", "1269", "1479"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Nicoló Machiavelli born?",
    "answers":["1527"],
    "options":["1427", "1627", "1327", "1227", "1427"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What percentage of the Earth's surface is covered by water?",
    "answers":["71%"],
    "options":["61%", "81%", "93%", "87%", "67%", "77%", "63%", "53%", "73%", "83%"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"71% of the Earths surface is covered by water, of the remaining 29%, 33% is what?",
    "answers":["Desert"],
    "options":["Forest", "Mountain", "More water"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Persia is now which modern country?",
    "answers":["Iran"],
    "options":["Egypt", "Turkey", "Suadi Arabia", "Pakistan", "Nepal", "Bhutan"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Persia changed its name to Iran in what century?",
    "answers":["20th"],
    "options":["21st", "19th", "18th", "17th", "16th", "15th"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Persia changed its name to Iran?",
    "answers":["1935"],
    "options":["1945", "1955", "1965", "1925", "1915", "1905", "1895", "1885", "1875"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"CT scans and MRIs are both used to capture images within your body",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science", "medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"What does an MRIs stand for",
    "answers":["Magnetic resonance imaging"],
    "options":["Magnetic relative imaging", "Medical resonance imaging", "Medical relative imaging", "Magentic real-time imaging", "Medical real-time imaging"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"What does a CT scan stand for",
    "answers":["Computer tomography"],
    "options":["Computer topography", "Critical topography", "Cathode topography", "Cathode tomography", "Clustered tomography", "Clustered topography"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these uses X-rays",
    "answers":["CT scan"],
    "options":["MRI"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these uses radio waves",
    "answers":["MRI"],
    "options":["CT scan"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"The word origin of which profession comes from the Greek for 'star sailor'",
    "answers":["Astronaut"],
    "options":["Astronomer", "Astrophysicist", "Astrosailor"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science", "medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Patrick Henry famously said 'Give me liberty or give me' what?",
    "answers":["Death"],
    "options":["Nothing", "Freedom", "Hope", "A clenched fist", "Olympus"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Which founding father famously said 'Give me liberty or give me death'?",
    "answers":["Patrick Henry"],
    "options":["James Madison", "George Washington", "John Adams", "Benjamin Franklin", "Thomas Jefferson", "Alexander Hamilton", "Thomas Paine", "Samuel Adams"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Which founding father has the largest signature on the Decleration of Independence?",
    "answers":["John Hancock"],
    "options":["Patrick Henry", "James Madison", "George Washington", "John Adams", "Benjamin Franklin", "Thomas Jefferson", "Alexander Hamilton", "Thomas Paine", "Samuel Adams"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Which founding father has the largest signature on the Decleration of Independence?",
    "answers":["John Hancock"],
    "options":["Patrick Henry", "James Madison", "George Washington", "John Adams", "Benjamin Franklin", "Thomas Jefferson", "Alexander Hamilton", "Thomas Paine", "Samuel Adams"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What does does the S in SCUBA stand for?",
    "answers":["Self"],
    "options":["Submerged", "Seamless", "SLL", "Standalone", "Surface"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"What does does the U in SCUBA stand for?",
    "answers":["Underwater"],
    "options":["Ultra", "Utility", "Ultimate", "User"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"What does does the A in SCUBA stand for?",
    "answers":["Apparatus"],
    "options":["Accelerator", "Adapter", "Air", "Amplifier"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Notre-Dame catherdral catch fire?",
    "answers":["15th of April 2019"],
    "options":["15th of April 2018", "15th of April 2017", "15th of April 2020", "15th of March 2019", "15th of March 2018"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Where is the Notre-Dame catherdral located?",
    "answers":["France"],
    "options":["Germany", "Brussels", "Austria", "Amstderdam"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where is the Notre-Dame catherdral located?",
    "answers":["Paris"],
    "options":["Marseille", "Strasbourg", "Nice", "Lyon", "Lille"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of France?",
    "answers":["Paris"],
    "options":["Marseille", "Strasbourg", "Nice", "Lyon", "Lille"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What did Vincent van Gogh cut off after an argument?",
    "answers":["His ear"],
    "options":["His nose", "His big toe", "His middle finger", "Hand"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Did Vincent van Gogh cut off his right ear after an argument?",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Did Vincent van Gogh cut off his left ear after an argument?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was the first kidney transplant done?",
    "answers":["Massachusetts"],
    "options":["Illinois", "California", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Texas", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["science", "medicine", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was the first kidney transplant done?",
    "answers":["The United States"],
    "options":["England", "Canada", "Australia", "Austria", "Amsterdam", "Germany", "France"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "medicine", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which organ was sucessfully transplanted in 1954?",
    "answers":["Kidney"],
    "options":["Lung", "Pancreas", "Eye", "Skin"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "medicine", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which organ was sucessfully transplanted in 1869?",
    "answers":["Skin"],
    "options":["Lung", "Pancreas", "Eye", "Kidney"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "medicine", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which organ was sucessfully transplanted first?",
    "answers":["Skin"],
    "options":["Lung", "Pancreas", "Eye", "Kidney"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "medicine", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did England win the world cup?",
    "answers":["1966"],
    "options":["1970", "1974", "1978", "1962", "1976", "1972"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries has not won a World Cup?",
    "answers":["Belgium", "Holland"],
    "options":["Uruguay", "France", "Spain", "England"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries has not won a World Cup?",
    "answers":["Belgium", "Holland", "Croatia"],
    "options":["Uruguay", "France", "Spain", "England"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who won the 2018 World Cup?",
    "answers":["France"],
    "options":["Uruguay", "Spain", "England", "Croatia", "Belgium"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who hosted the 2018 World Cup?",
    "answers":["Russia"],
    "options":["Brazil", "South Africa", "Germany", "South Korea, Japan", "France", "United States", "Mexico", "Italy"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who won the 2014 World Cup?",
    "answers":["Germany"],
    "options":["Brazil", "France", "Spain", "Italy", "Argentina"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who hosted the 2014 World Cup?",
    "answers":["Brazil"],
    "options":["Russia", "South Africa", "Germany", "South Korea, Japan", "France", "United States", "Mexico", "Italy"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who won the 2010 World Cup?",
    "answers":["Spain"],
    "options":["Brazil", "France", "Spain", "Germany", "Argentina"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who hosted the 2010 World Cup?",
    "answers":["South Africa"],
    "options":["Russia", "Brazil", "Germany", "South Korea, Japan", "France", "United States", "Mexico", "Italy"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who won the 2006 World Cup?",
    "answers":["Italy"],
    "options":["Brazil", "France", "Spain", "Germany", "Argentina"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who hosted the 2006 World Cup?",
    "answers":["Germany"],
    "options":["Russia", "Brazil", "South Africa", "South Korea, Japan", "France", "United States", "Mexico", "Italy"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who won the 2002 World Cup?",
    "answers":["Brazil"],
    "options":["Italy", "France", "Spain", "Germany", "Argentina"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who hosted the 2002 World Cup?",
    "answers":["South Korea, Japan"],
    "options":["Russia", "Brazil", "South Africa", "Germany", "France", "United States", "Mexico", "Italy"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who won the 1998 World Cup?",
    "answers":["France"],
    "options":["Italy", "Brazil", "Spain", "Germany", "Argentina"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who hosted the 1998 World Cup?",
    "answers":["France"],
    "options":["Russia", "Brazil", "South Africa", "Germany", "South Korea, Japan", "United States", "Mexico", "Italy"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who won the 1994 World Cup?",
    "answers":["Brazil"],
    "options":["Italy", "France", "Spain", "Germany", "Argentina"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who hosted the 1994 World Cup?",
    "answers":["United States"],
    "options":["Russia", "Brazil", "South Africa", "Germany", "South Korea, Japan", "France", "Mexico", "Italy"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who won the 1990 World Cup?",
    "answers":["Germany"],
    "options":["Italy", "France", "Spain", "Brazil", "Argentina"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who hosted the 1990 World Cup?",
    "answers":["Italy"],
    "options":["Russia", "Brazil", "South Africa", "Germany", "South Korea, Japan", "France", "Mexico", "United States"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who won the 1986 World Cup?",
    "answers":["Argentina"],
    "options":["Italy", "France", "Spain", "Brazil", "Germany"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Who hosted the 1986 World Cup?",
    "answers":["Mexico"],
    "options":["Russia", "Brazil", "South Africa", "Germany", "South Korea, Japan", "France", "Mexico", "United States", "Italy"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"In 2020, Joe Rogan announced his podcast would move from Youtube to what platform?",
    "answers":["Spotify"],
    "options":["Itunes", "Netflix", "Hulu", "Facebook", "Amazon", "Vimeo"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["misc", "entertainment"]
},
{
    "question":"Ricky Martin, singer of 'Livin' La Vida Loca' is from what country?",
    "answers":["Puerto Rico"],
    "options":["Columbia", "Barbado", "Spain", "Cuba", "Mexico"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"Who is the singer of 'Livin' La Vida Loca'?",
    "answers":["Ricky Martin"],
    "options":["Luis Fonsi", "Enrique Iglesias", "Shakira", "Selena", "Los Fabulosos Cadillacs"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"Stephenie Meyer is known for which series of books?",
    "answers":["Twilight"],
    "options":["The Hunger Games", "The Princess Diaries", "Divergent"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"Who wrote the Lord of the Rings?",
    "answers":["J. R. R. Tolkien"],
    "options":["J. K. Rowling", "George R. Martin", "C. S. Lewis"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"Akihito was en emporer of which country?",
    "answers":["Japan"],
    "options":["China", "Korea", "Jordan", "Cambodia"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was the founder of The Latter Day Saint movement?",
    "answers":["Joseph Smith"],
    "options":["Thomas S. Monson", "Joseph Fielding Smith", "Emma Hale", "Thomas S. Monson"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Vincent van Gogh cut off his ear?",
    "answers":["1888"],
    "options":["1988", "1788", "1688", "1672", "1772", "1872", "1972"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["art", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1982 Time Magazine's Man of the Year was a computer?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1982 Time Magazine's Man of the Year was a dog?",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the first horror film to be nominated for Best Picture at the Academy Awards?",
    "answers":["The Exorcist"],
    "options":["Silence of the Lambs", "Misery", "Jaws", "Alien", "Psycho", "Birds"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the only horror film to win Best Picture at the Academy Awards?",
    "answers":["Silence of the Lambs"],
    "options":["Exorcist", "Misery", "Jaws", "Alien", "Psycho", "Birds"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"In The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy, an enormous supercomputer calculates the meaning of life. What answer does it give?",
    "answers":["42"],
    "options":["Cake", "Make as many relationships as possible", "Find peace at home", "Find God", "Love"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books", "film"]
},
{
    "question":"'He is happiest, be king or peasant, who finds peace at home' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Johann Wolfgang von Goethe"],
    "options":["John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Joan of Arc faught in which war?",
    "answers":["Hundred Years' War"],
    "options":["Wars of the Roses", "German–Polish War", "Despenser War", "War of the Two Peters"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the Hundred Years' War faught?",
    "answers":["1337-1453"],
    "options":["1227-1327", "1427-1527", "1137-1237", "1527-1627", "1549-1623"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What age was Joan of Arc when she died?",
    "answers":["19"],
    "options":["26", "34", "41", "47", "52", "61", "37", "31"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"How did Joan of Arc die?",
    "answers":["She was burned at the stake"],
    "options":["She took an arrow to the knee during battle", "She died in the Queen's prison", "Her horse kicked her", "She drank poison", "She was thrown off a cliff to see if she would fall or fly"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What does IQ stand for?",
    "answers":["Intelligence quotient"],
    "options":["Intelligence qualifier", "Intelligence Query", "Intelligence Query", "Intelligence Quicktime", "Intelligence Quantum", "Intelligence Quest"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Heliophobia is the fear of what?",
    "answers":["The sun"],
    "options":["Helium", "Floating away from Earth", "Cheese", "Clowns", "Workout", "Feet"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Guinness founded?",
    "answers":["1759"],
    "options":["1859", "1889", "1659", "1459", "1359"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["drinks"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Guinness founded?",
    "answers":["Dublin"],
    "options":["Cork", "London", "Galway", "Paris"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["drinks"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1664, the English renamed the city to New York City, what was it called before?",
    "answers":["New Amsterdam"],
    "options":["New Columbia", "Housten", "Yorktown", "Lyria", "El cuppo"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"'Anything that can go wrong will go wrong' is typically known as what?",
    "answers":["Murphy's Law"],
    "options":["Hanlon's Razor", "Occam's Razor", "The Pareto principle", "The 80/20 rule"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"'The growth of wisdom can be accurately measured by the decline of ill-temper' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Friedrich Nietzche"],
    "options":["Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1994, what caused a blackout in L.A?",
    "answers":["An Earthquake"],
    "options":["A bomb", "A flood", "A hurricane", "A pulsar sent from the sun"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"The largest known eyes in the world belong to what type of animal?",
    "answers":["Squid"],
    "options":["Shark", "Ostrich", "Chameleon", "Camel"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"The collosal squid has the largest eyes in the animal kingdom, how big are they?",
    "answers":["27cm"],
    "options":["15cm", "21cm", "32cm", "13cm", "9cm", "5cm", "37cm", "39cm"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Cyprus?",
    "answers":["Nicosia"],
    "options":["Paphos", "Larnaca", "Limassol", "Famagusta", "Paralimni"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where is insulin produced in the body?",
    "answers":["Pancreas"],
    "options":["Kidney", "Spleen", "Liver", "Appendix"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["medicine", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"'Its not the fall that kills you, its the sudden stop at the end' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Douglas Adams"],
    "options":["Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Friedrich Nietzche", "John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Hitler & Charlie Chaplin were born just 4 days apart",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Charles Darwin & Charlie Chaplin were born just 4 days apart",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Albert Einstein & Charlie Chaplin were born just 4 days apart",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Hitler born?",
    "answers":["1889"],
    "options":["1899", "1909", "1979", "1969", "1919", "1929"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Charlie Chaplin?",
    "answers":["1889"],
    "options":["1899", "1909", "1979", "1969", "1919", "1929"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the March on Rome occur?",
    "answers":["1922"],
    "options":["1892", "1902", "1972", "1962", "1912", "1932", "1942"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"'Hell is empty and all the devils are here' is a Shakespeare quote from which of his works?",
    "answers":["The Tempest"],
    "options":["Hamlet", "Macbeth", "Romeo and Juliet", "Orthello", "King Lear"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"Addis Ababa is the capital of which country?",
    "answers":["Ethiopia"],
    "options":["Benin", "Rwanda", "Eritrea", "Togo", "Zimbabwe", "Gabon", "Comoros"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president was Harry S. Truman?",
    "answers":["33rd"],
    "options":["37th", "36th", "38th", "39th", "34th", "32nd", "31st", "30th", "35th"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Berarus?",
    "answers":["Minsk"],
    "options":["Bucharest", "Brest", "Grondo", "Pinsk", "Mogilev", "Bratislava", "Baku"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Kosovo?",
    "answers":["Pristina"],
    "options":["Prizen", "Peja", "Gjakova", "Mitrovica", "Baku", "Gjilan"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"'Great things are done by a series of small things brought together' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Vincent Van Gough"],
    "options":["Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Douglas Adams", "Friedrich Nietzche", "John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Venezuela means little what?",
    "answers":["Venice"],
    "options":["Venison", "Venus", "Vendiagram", "Seller", "Green"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is Venezuela's currency?",
    "answers":["Venezuelan bolívar"],
    "options":["Venezuelan peso", "Venezuelan florin", "Venezuelan dollar", "Venezuelan lempira", "Venezuelan pound"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography", "currency"]
},
{
    "question":"What gas makes up approximately 21% of the air in the Earth's atmosphere?",
    "answers":["Oxegen"],
    "options":["Carbon Dioxide", "Nitrogen", "Neon", "Hydrogen"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What gas makes up approximately 78% of the air in the Earth's atmosphere?",
    "answers":["Nitrogen"],
    "options":["Carbon Dioxide", "Oxegen", "Neon", "Hydrogen"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"'The reward of suffering is experience' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Harry S. Truman"],
    "options":["Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Vincent Van Gough", "Douglas Adams", "Friedrich Nietzche", "John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Lao Tzu", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Rosalind Franklin was best known for what?",
    "answers":["Her role in the discovery of the structure of DNA"],
    "options":["Refusing to give up her seat to a white man on a bus", "Observing primates using tools", "Supposedly contacting spirits from another dimension", "Her role in the discovery of uranium"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Rosalind Franklin was alive during which century?",
    "answers":["20th"],
    "options":["21st", "19th", "18th", "17th", "16th"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What was Jane Goodall best known for?",
    "answers":["Observing primates using tools"],
    "options":["Refusing to give up her seat to a white man on a bus", "Her role in the discovery of the structure of DNA", "Supposedly contacting spirits from another dimension", "Her role in the discovery of uranium"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Comoros?",
    "answers":["Moroni"],
    "options":["Fomboni", "Domoney", "Mutsamudu", "Ouani", "Koni-Djodjo"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was the lead actor in 'The Great Dictator'?",
    "answers":["Charlie Chaplin"],
    "options":["Sacha Baron Cohen", "Robert De Niro", "Hal Holbrook", "Humphrey Bogart"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Who wrote 'Beyond Good and Evil'?",
    "answers":["Friedrich Nietzche"],
    "options":["René Descartes", "Immanuel Kant", "Karl Marx", "John Locke"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["philosophy", "books"]
},
{
    "question":"When was 'Beyond Good and Evil' published?",
    "answers":["1886"],
    "options":["1986", "1786", "1686", "1586", "1486"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["philosophy", "books"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Azerbaijan?",
    "answers":["Baku"],
    "options":["Ganja", "Sheki", "Sumqayit", "Lankaran"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What does NATO stand for?",
    "answers":["North Atlantic Treaty Organization"],
    "options":["North Atlantic Trade Organization", "North Atlantic Totalitarian Organization", "North Atlantic Tax Organization", "North Atlantic Trustee Organization"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was NATO formed",
    "answers":["4th April 1949"],
    "options":["4th April 1945", "4th April 1959", "4th April 1955", "4th April 1969", "4th April 1965"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Slovenia",
    "answers":["Ljubljana"],
    "options":["Bratislava", "Maribor", "Koper", "Piran", "Kranj", "Bled", "Ptuj", "Celje", "Novo mesto"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries is landlocked?",
    "answers":["Afghanistan", "Andorra", "Armenia", "Austria", "Azerbaijan", "Belarus", "Bhutan", "Bolivia", "Botswana", "Burkina Faso", "Burundi", "Central African Republic", "Chad", "Czech Republic", "Eswatini", "Ethiopia", "Hungary", "Kazakhstan", "Kyrgyzstan", "Laos", "Lesotho", "Liechtenstein", "Luxembourg", "Malawi", "Mali", "Moldova",
    "Mongolia", "Nepal", "Niger", "Macedonia", "Paraguay", "Rwanda", "San Marino", "Serbia", "Slovakia", "South Sudan", "Switzerland", "Tajikistan", "Turkmenistan", "Uganda", "Uzbekistan", "Vatican City", "Zambia", "Zimbabwe"],
    "options":["Albania", "Algeria", "Angola", "Argentina", "Bahamas", "Bahrain", "Bangladesh", "Belgium", "Belize", "Montenegro", "Mozambique", "Myanimar", "Namibia", "Nauru", "New Zealand", "Nicaragua", "Oman", "Pakistan", "Samoa", "Senegal", "Tunisia", "Turkey", "Yemen", "Venezuela", "Mauritius", "Mauritania", "Estonia", "Guinea", "Guinea-Bissau"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"On August 16th 1962, who was kicked out of the Beatles?",
    "answers":["Pete Best"],
    "options":["Ringo Starr", "John Lennon", "Paul McCartney", "George Harrison", "Tommy Moore"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Pete Best kicked out of the Beatles?",
    "answers":["1962"],
    "options":["1972", "1982", "1992", "1952"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"What is a blue moon?",
    "answers":["A second full moon in one month"],
    "options":["When the moon changes colour due to a shadow from the Earth", "When it appears a slender crescent, shortly after its conjunction with the sun", "When the suns light reflects a blue colour from the oceans onto the moon"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the first planet to be discovered by maths prediction before being observed?",
    "answers":["Neptune"],
    "options":["Venus", "Uranus", "Jupiter", "Saturn"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "math"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the first planet to be discovered by maths prediction before being observed?",
    "answers":["Neptune"],
    "options":["Venus", "Uranus", "Jupiter", "Saturn"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "math"]
},
{
    "question":"'It is the mark of an educated mind to entertain a thought without accepting it' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Aristotle"],
    "options":["Herodotus", "Plato", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Anazimander", "Heraclitus", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"In normal conditions a lot of adenosine in your body will make you feel what?",
    "answers":["Sleepy"],
    "options":["Hungry", "Thirsty", "Aroused", "Happy"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"The Rosetta Stone is used to understand what?",
    "answers":["Egyptian hieroglyphs"],
    "options":["Greek alphabet", "Cuneform", "Maya script", "Written Chinese"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"What stone is used to understand Egyptian hieroglyphs?",
    "answers":["The Rosetta Stone"],
    "options":["The Philosopher's Stone", "Blarney Stone", "The Black Stone of the Kaaba"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Iceland",
    "answers":["Reykjavík"],
    "options":["Akureyri", "Hafnarfjordour", "Vik", "Selfoss"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Malawi",
    "answers":["Lilongwe"],
    "options":["Blantyre", "Mzuzu", "Zomba", "Karonga", "Mangochi"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Who wrote 'On the Origin of Species'",
    "answers":["Charles Darwin"],
    "options":["Albert Einstein", "Isaac Newton", "Marie Curie", "Galileo Galilei"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"When was 'On the Origin of Species' published",
    "answers":["1859"],
    "options":["1949", "1929", "1919", "1889", "1979", "1839", "1809", "1789"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Sheryl Crow sang the title track for which James Bond film?",
    "answers":["Tomorrow Never Dies"],
    "options":["The World Is Not Enough", "Die Another Day", "GoldenEye", "License to Kill"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film", "music"]
},
{
    "question":"'The journey of a thousand miles begins with one step' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Lao Tzu"],
    "options":["Harry S. Truman", "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Vincent Van Gough", "Douglas Adams", "Friedrich Nietzche", "John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Who famously delivered the 'I Have a Dream' speech?",
    "answers":["Martin Luther King Jr"],
    "options":["Harry S. Truman", "Friedrich Nietzche", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "Muhammad Ali", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"In his 'I Have a Dream' Martin Luther King Jr wanted his children not to be judged by the colour of their skin but by what?",
    "answers":["The content of their character"],
    "options":["The ability that lies in their potential", "Their heart and personality", "Their deeds and growth", "Their capacity for change", "Their platitudes of grace"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Moldova",
    "answers":["Chisinau"],
    "options":["Valletta", "Tiraspol", "Balti", "Comrat", "Cahul", "Orhei"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the term for an uncastrated, adult male horse",
    "answers":["Stallion"],
    "options":["Saddlebred", "Warm blood", "Light Horse", "Gelding"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the term for an castrated, adult male horse",
    "answers":["Gelding"],
    "options":["Saddlebred", "Warm blood", "Light Horse", "Stallion"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Gambia",
    "answers":["Bangul"],
    "options":["Windhoek", "Serrekunda", "Bakau", "Brikama", "Basse Santa Su"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"The Earth's rotation is overall slowing down",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"The Earth's rotation is overall speeding up",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1981, which NHL player became the fastest ever to get to 100 points",
    "answers":["Wayne Gretzky"],
    "options":["Mario Lemieux", "Joe Thornton", "Jean Ratelle", "John Cullen"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Where are the ruins of Macchu Picchu located",
    "answers":["Peru"],
    "options":["Chile", "Mexico", "Malaysia", "Philippines", "Indonesia"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which would not typically be a feature of a male turtle compared to females",
    "answers":["Drie skin"],
    "options":["Larger shells", "Wider Tails", "Longer Tails", "Concave plastron (shell on the belly)"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["nature", "animals"]
},
{
    "question":"The 3 wise monkeys originated from what country?",
    "answers":["Japan"],
    "options":["India", "Peru", "China", "Taiwan"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is not one of the 3 wise monkeys?",
    "answers":["Pizaru", "Winazaru", "Litzaru"],
    "options":["Kikazaru", "Mizaru", "Iwazaru"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Mizaru...does what",
    "answers":["Sees no evil"],
    "options":["Hears no evil", "Speaks no evil", "Feels no evil"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Kikazaru...does what",
    "answers":["Hears no evil"],
    "options":["Sees no evil", "Speaks no evil", "Feels no evil"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Iwazaru...does what",
    "answers":["Speaks no evil"],
    "options":["Hears no evil", "Sees no evil", "Feels no evil"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was the first African American to win an Oscar",
    "answers":["Hattie McDaniel"],
    "options":["Sidney Poitier", "Louis Gossett", "Denzel Washington", "Whoopi Goldberg", "Cuba Gooding, Jr."],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Hattie McDaniel became the first African American to win an Oscar for her role in which film?",
    "answers":["Gone with the Wind"],
    "options":["A Star is Born", "Scarface", "Freaks", "Citizen Kane", "It's a Wonderful Life"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Liechtenstein",
    "answers":["Vaduz"],
    "options":["Schaan", "Balzers", "Triesenberg", "Triesen", "Ruggell"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"'I would rather be hated for who I am, than loved for who I am not' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Kurt Kobain"],
    "options":["Lao Tzu", "Harry S. Truman", "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Vincent Van Gough", "Douglas Adams", "Friedrich Nietzche", "John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "Nelson Mandela", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Fiji",
    "answers":["Suva"],
    "options":["Nadi", "Lautoka", "Lveuka", "Savusavu", "Sigatoka"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"'A winner is a dreamer who never gives up' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Nelson Mandela"],
    "options":["Kurt Kobain", "Lao Tzu", "Harry S. Truman", "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Vincent Van Gough", "Douglas Adams", "Friedrich Nietzche", "John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Malcolm in the Middle premier?",
    "answers":["2000"],
    "options":["2004", "2006", "2002", "1998", "2001", "2005"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Who played Malcolm in 'Malcolm in the Middle'?",
    "answers":["Frankie Muniz"],
    "options":["Justin Berfield", "Erik Per Sullivan", "Kyle Massey", "Shad Moss", "Jeremy Sumpter", "Josh Peck"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Was is the first name of the James Bond villian Goldfinger?",
    "answers":["Auric"],
    "options":["Erin", "Hans", "Mike", "Norman", "Anthony"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these Venezuelan presidents was impeached?",
    "answers":["Carlos Andrés Pérez"],
    "options":["Nicolás Maduro", "Hugo Chavez", "Luis Herrera Campins"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Juan Pablo Pérez Alfonzo, a Venezuelan politician referred to what, as 'The Devils excrement'?",
    "answers":["Oil"],
    "options":["Rum", "Heroine", "Corn", "Icecream"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics", "quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Austria's currency?",
    "answers":["Schilling"],
    "options":["Pound", "Kroon", "Lats", "Tolar"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Belgium's currency?",
    "answers":["Franc"],
    "options":["Schilling", "Pound", "Kroon", "Lats", "Tolar"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Cyprus's currency?",
    "answers":["Pound"],
    "options":["Franc", "Schilling", "Kroon", "Lats", "Tolar"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Estonia's currency?",
    "answers":["Kroon"],
    "options":["Franc", "Schilling", "Lats", "Tolar"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Finland's currency?",
    "answers":["Markka"],
    "options":["Kroon", "Franc", "Schilling", "Lats", "Tolar"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, which of these countries did not have the Franc as its currency?",
    "answers":["Malta", "Greece", "Slovakia"],
    "options":["Monaco", "France", "Luxembourg", "Belgium"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was France's currency?",
    "answers":["Franc"],
    "options":["Kroon", "Markka", "Schilling", "Lats", "Tolar"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was German's currency?",
    "answers":["Deutschmark"],
    "options":["Kroon", "Franc", "Markka", "Schilling", "Lats", "Tolar"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Greece's currency?",
    "answers":["Drachma"],
    "options":["Kroon", "Franc", "Markka", "Schilling", "Lats", "Tolar"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Ireland's currency?",
    "answers":["Pound"],
    "options":["Kroon", "Drachma", "Franc", "Markka", "Schilling", "Lats", "Tolar"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, which of these countries did not have the Lira as its currency?",
    "answers":["Malta", "Greece", "Slovakia"],
    "options":["Italy", "San Marino", "Vatican City"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Italy's currency?",
    "answers":["Lira"],
    "options":["Kroon", "Drachma", "Franc", "Markka", "Schilling", "Lats", "Tolar", "Pound"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Latvia's currency?",
    "answers":["Lats"],
    "options":["Kroon", "Drachma", "Franc", "Markka", "Schilling", "Lira", "Tolar", "Pound"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Lithuania's currency?",
    "answers":["Litas"],
    "options":["Kroon", "Drachma", "Franc", "Markka", "Schilling", "Lira", "Lats", "Tolar", "Pound"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Luxembourg's currency?",
    "answers":["Franc"],
    "options":["Kroon", "Drachma", "Litas", "Markka", "Schilling", "Lira", "Lats", "Tolar", "Pound"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Malta's currency?",
    "answers":["Lira"],
    "options":["Kroon", "Drachma", "Litas", "Markka", "Schilling", "Franc", "Lats", "Tolar", "Pound"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Netherlands' currency?",
    "answers":["Guilder"],
    "options":["Kroon", "Lira", "Drachma", "Litas", "Markka", "Schilling", "Franc", "Lats", "Tolar", "Pound"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Portugal's currency?",
    "answers":["Escudo"],
    "options":["Guilder", "Kroon", "Lira", "Drachma", "Litas", "Markka", "Schilling", "Franc", "Lats", "Tolar", "Pound"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Slovakia's currency?",
    "answers":["Koruna"],
    "options":["Guilder", "Escudo", "Kroon", "Lira", "Drachma", "Litas", "Markka", "Schilling", "Franc", "Lats", "Tolar", "Pound"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Slovenia's currency?",
    "answers":["Tolar"],
    "options":["Guilder", "Escudo", "Kroon", "Lira", "Drachma", "Litas", "Markka", "Schilling", "Franc", "Lats", "Koruna", "Pound"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Before the Euro, what was Spain's currency?",
    "answers":["Peseta"],
    "options":["Tolar", "Guilder", "Escudo", "Kroon", "Lira", "Drachma", "Litas", "Markka", "Schilling", "Franc", "Lats", "Koruna", "Pound"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Pol Pot was Prime Minister of which country?",
    "answers":["Cambodia"],
    "options":["Canada", "Britain", "India", "Australia", "Ghana"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Pol Pot was leader of the which regime?",
    "answers":["Khmer Rouge"],
    "options":["Khmer Blanche", "Khmer Noir", "Khmer Verde", "Khmer Marron", "Khmer Jaune"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Botswana?",
    "answers":["Gaborone"],
    "options":["Francistown", "Maun", "Lobaste", "Serowe", "Molepolole"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these animals sleeps longer per day?",
    "answers":["Koala", "Sloth"],
    "options":["Armadillo", "Possum", "Lemur", "Squirrel", "Hamster"],
    "difficulty":2,
    "categories":["nature", "animals"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these animals sleepss least?",
    "answers":["Hamster", "Squirrel"],
    "options":["Armadillo", "Possum", "Lemur", "Sloth", "Koala"],
    "difficulty":3,
    "categories":["nature", "animals"]
},
{
    "question":"'Life is what happens when you are busy making other plans' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["John Lennon"],
    "options":["Nelson Mandela", "Kurt Kobain", "Lao Tzu", "Harry S. Truman", "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Vincent Van Gough", "Douglas Adams", "Friedrich Nietzche", "John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Prohibition was which Amendment to the U.S. Constitution?",
    "answers":["The 18th"],
    "options":["The 19th", "The 20th", "The 21st", "The 16th", "The 15th"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["law", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Prohibition officially go into effect?",
    "answers":["January 17, 1920"],
    "options":["January 17, 1930", "January 17, 1940", "January 17, 1950", "January 17, 1910", "January 17, 1900", "January 17, 1890"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["law", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"'It is during our darkest moments that we must focus to see the light' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Plato"],
    "options":["Herodotus", "Karl Marx", "Socrates", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Anazimander", "Heraclitus", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Mozambique?",
    "answers":["Maputo"],
    "options":["Beira", "Chimoio", "Quelimane", "Matola", "Lichinga", "Pemba"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Cambodia?",
    "answers":["Phnom Penh"],
    "options":["Kron Siem Reap", "Preah Sihanouk", "Krong Battambang", "Kratié Province", "Krong Poi Pet"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Malta?",
    "answers":["Valletta"],
    "options":["Mdina", "Birgu", "Victoria", "Senglea", "Marsaxlokk", "Cospicua"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of Bob Marley's first child?",
    "answers":["Ziggy"],
    "options":["Damian", "Cedella", "Stephen", "Rohan", "Karen", "Ky-Mani"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is not a Call of Duty title?",
    "answers":["Call of Duty: Frontline", "Call of Duty: Combat Evolved"],
    "options":["Call of Duty: World at War", "Call of Duty: Modern Warfare", "Call of Duty: Black Ops", "Call of Duty: Ghosts", "Call of Duty: Advanced Warfare", "Call of Duty: WWII"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["videogames"]
},
{
    "question":"In what type of resturaunt would you be likely to find soba noodles?",
    "answers":["Japanese"],
    "options":["Chinese", "Indian", "Thai", "Korean", "Vietnamese"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"Witing for the Rolling Stone, Matt Taibbi called which organization a 'Great vampire squid wrapped around the face of humanity'?",
    "answers":["Goldman Sachs"],
    "options":["Electronic Arts", "Amazon", "Fox Entertainment Group", "NFL", "The Trump Organization", "Uber", "Facebook"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["journalism", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Montenegro?",
    "answers":["Podgorica"],
    "options":["Nikšić", "Pljevlja", "Herceg Novi", "Bar", "Cetinje"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Belize?",
    "answers":["Belmopan"],
    "options":["Belize City", "San Ignacio", "San Pedro", "Punta Gorda", "Orange Walk"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is interesting about the island of Bermeja?",
    "answers":["It is a phantom island"],
    "options":["All the residents are deaf", "It's located in the South Pole", "It is 1 meter long", "Everyone who visits it dies", "All the residents vanished in the 16th century"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Jordan?",
    "answers":["Amman"],
    "options":["Aqaba", "Jerash", "Madaba", "Kerak", "Irbid", "Zarqa"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"LeBron James is famous for playing which sport?",
    "answers":["Basketball"],
    "options":["Hockey", "Baseball", "Tennis", "Badminton", "Wrestling"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"In which state was Tiger Woods born?",
    "answers":["California"],
    "options":["Illinois", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Texas", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"What is Tiger Woods real first name?",
    "answers":["Eldrick"],
    "options":["Anthony", "Aziz", "Arnold", "David", "Tyreke", "Dawid", "Jade"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the British equivalent of molasses?",
    "answers":["Treacle"],
    "options":["Golden syrup", "Suet", "Sultana", "Parkin", "Butterscotch"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"What is Ecaudor's currency?",
    "answers":["United States dollar"],
    "options":["Ecaudorian peso", "Ecaudorian florin", "Ecaudorian dollar", "Ecaudorian lempira", "Ecaudorian pound"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is Zimbabwe's currency?",
    "answers":["United States dollar"],
    "options":["Zimbabwean peso", "Zimbabwean florin", "Zimbabwean dollar", "Zimbabwean lempira", "Zimbabwean pound"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries does not have the United States Dollar as its currency?",
    "answers":["Ethiopia", "Gabon", "Finland", "Mauritania"],
    "options":["Ecaudor", "Zimbabwe", "The United States"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["currency", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the tallest above ground waterfall?",
    "answers":["Venezuela"],
    "options":["South Africa", "Norway", "Hawaii", "Canada"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the tallest above ground waterfall?",
    "answers":["Angel Falls"],
    "options":["Tugela Falls", "Pu'uka'oku Falls", "Mongefossen", "Gocta Waterfall"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find Tugela Falls?",
    "answers":["South Africa"],
    "options":["Libya", "Hawaii", "Canada", "Peru", "Chile"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find Mongefossen Falls?",
    "answers":["Norway"],
    "options":["Libya", "Hawaii", "Canada", "Peru", "Chile", "South Africa", "Finland"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find Gocta Waterfall?",
    "answers":["Peru"],
    "options":["Libya", "Hawaii", "Canada", "Norway", "Chile", "South Africa", "Finland"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Armenia?",
    "answers":["Yerevan"],
    "options":["Gyumri", "Vanadzor", "Vagharshapat", "Kapan", "Artashat", "Masis"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"'The only true wisdom is in knowing that you know nothing' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Socrates"],
    "options":["Herodotus", "Plato", "Karl Marx", "Aristotle", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Anazimander", "Heraclitus", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"In telecoms, a call that cuts off just as the phone rings, leaving a missed call, usually from an unknown number is known as what?",
    "answers":["Wangiri"],
    "options":["Inemuri", "Otaku", "Fugu", "Ikigai"],
    "difficulty":4,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Philippines?",
    "answers":["Manila"],
    "options":["Quezon City", "Cebu city", "Davao City", "Baguio", "Makati", "Zamboanga"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Barbados?",
    "answers":["Bridgetown"],
    "options":["St. Johns", "Holetown", "Oistins", "Speightstown", "Bathsheba", "Saint James"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"'History repeats itself, first as tragedy, second as farce' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Karl Marx"],
    "options":["Nelson Mandela", "John Lennon", "Kurt Kobain", "Lao Tzu", "Harry S. Truman", "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Vincent Van Gough", "Douglas Adams", "Friedrich Nietzche", "John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Muhammad Ali", "Albert Einstein", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Barbados?",
    "answers":["St. Johns"],
    "options":["Bridgetown", "Codrington", "Bolands", "Piggotts", "Potters Village", "All Saints", "Falmouth"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When did The Six Day war take place?",
    "answers":["5 - 10th of June 1967"],
    "options":["5 - 10th of June 1937", "5 - 10th of June 1917", "5 - 10th of June 1867", "5 - 10th of June 1837", "5 - 10th of June 1817", "5 - 10th of June 1767", "5 - 10th of June 1717"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "war"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries did not fight in the Six Day War?",
    "answers":["Angola", "Iran", "Iraq", "Tunisia", "Libya"],
    "options":["Israel", "Syria", "Egypt", "Jordan"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "war"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the head of Jewish Agency, proclaimed the establishment of the state of Israel?",
    "answers":["1948"],
    "options":["1918", "1967", "1837", "1854", "1875", "1777", "1757"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Saudi Arabia?",
    "answers":["Riyadh"],
    "options":["Damascus", "Jeddah", "Medina", "Dammam", "Mecca", "Tabuk"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the Challenger Deep?",
    "answers":["In the Mariana Trench"],
    "options":["In Space", "On Chimborazo", "In the Grand Canyon", "On Mars", "On the moon"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"The Challenger Deep in the Mariana Trench is the deepest known point in the Earth's ocean, how deep is it?",
    "answers":["10,994 metres"],
    "options":["100,994 metres", "1,994 metres", "1,000,994 metres", "500,994 metres", "5,994 metres", "5,000,994 metres", "50,994 metres"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"According to the Gospel, where was Jesus crucified?",
    "answers":["Golgotha"],
    "options":["Gethsemane", "Kidron Valley", "Cenacle", "Mount Zion"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["religion"]
},
{
    "question":"Finish the Stephen Hawking quote, 'In space no one can hear you scream; and in a black hole, no one can see you', what?",
    "answers":["Disappear"],
    "options":["At all", "Implode", "Dissipate", "Shout"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of the cult leader who directed a mass suicide in 1978?",
    "answers":["Jim Jones"],
    "options":["Jack Jones", "Jeffery Jones", "Joshua Jones", "Jeremiah Jones", "Gilbert Jones"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["religion", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Jim Jones directed a mass suicide in 1978 in his settlement, Jonestown, located where?",
    "answers":["Guyana"],
    "options":["Canada", "Venezuela", "Chile", "Angola", "Germany", "Austria", "The United States"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["religion", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Jim Jones orchestrate a mass suicide?",
    "answers":["1978"],
    "options":["1988", "1998", "1968", "1958", "1948"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["religion", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the term for the boundary around a black hole",
    "answers":["Event horizon"],
    "options":["Aperture", "Dobsonian", "Black Hole Shine", "Ephemeris", "Sunspot", "Twilight"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"Spa in an acronym",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Spa stands for the latin 'Sanus Per Aquam', meaning what",
    "answers":["Health through water"],
    "options":["Purity per body", "Body for water", "Surrounded by water", "Sanitation through water"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Who became known as the 'Father of chemical warfare' during World War 1",
    "answers":["Fritz Haber"],
    "options":["Robert Oppenhiemer", "Ernst Junger", "Georges Painvin", "John Keegan", "Klaus Fuchs"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["war", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"'The stuff you own ends up owning you. It's only after you lose everything that you're free to do anything' is a quote from which movie?",
    "answers":["Fight Club"],
    "options":["Pulp Fiction", "Deep Impact", "Falling Down", "Good Will Hunting", "Fargo", "The Fifth Element"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film", "quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the first name of Brad Pitt's character in 'Fight Club'?",
    "answers":["Tyler"],
    "options":["Chad", "Marcus", "Freddy", "Brad", "Noah", "Lucas"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the oldest-known living tree in the world?",
    "answers":["The United States"],
    "options":["Canada", "Russia", "China", "Brazil", "Paraguay", "Syria"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["trees", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"In 2020, which founding journalist left 'The Intercept' due to censorship?",
    "answers":["Glenn Greenwald"],
    "options":["Matt Taibbi", "Lester Holt", "Fredricka Whitfield", "Christiane Amanpour", "Hu Shuli"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["journalism", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"In 2019, who published their autobiography entitled 'Permanent Record'?",
    "answers":["Edward Snowden"],
    "options":["Noam Chomsky", "Julian Assange", "John McAfee", "Chelsea Manning", "Jacob Appelbaum"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"When did World War 1 start?",
    "answers":["28th July 1914"],
    "options":["28th July 1913", "28th July 1912", "28th July 1915", "28th July 1916", "28th July 1917", "28th September 1914", "28th September 1913", "28th September 1912", "28th September 1915", "28th September 1916", "28th September 1917"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["war", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did World War 1 end?",
    "answers":["November 11th, 1918"],
    "options":["November 11th, 1917", "November 11th, 1916", "November 11th, 1919", "November 11th, 1915", "January 11th, 1918", "January 11th, 1917", "January 11th, 1916", "January 11th, 1919", "January 11th, 1915"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["war", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Central African Republic?",
    "answers":["Bangui"],
    "options":["Bambari", "Bouar", "Bossangoa", "Bimbo", "Kaga-Bandoro"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Ghana?",
    "answers":["Accra"],
    "options":["Kumasi", "Tema", "Takoradi", "Tamale", "Cape Coast", "Obuasi"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Yemen?",
    "answers":["Sana'a"],
    "options":["Taizz", "Aden", "Zabid", "Ibb", "Al Hudaydah", "Al Mukalla"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"L. Ron Hubbard was the founder of what?",
    "answers":["Scientology"],
    "options":["Yahoo!", "WordPress", "The United States", "Architecture"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was the founder of Scientology?",
    "answers":["L. Ron Hubbard"],
    "options":["Guy Ballard", "John Slocum", "Frank Buchman", "Paul Twitchell", "Mark L. Prophet"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["religion"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Vietnam?",
    "answers":["Hanoi"],
    "options":["Ho Chi Minh City", "Da Nang", "Nha Trang", "Hue"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"The Philips Company was founded in 1891, mainly selling what?",
    "answers":["Lightbulbs"],
    "options":["Radios", "TVs", "Healthcare Products", "Doorbells"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["technology", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was The Philips Company founded?",
    "answers":["Amsterdam"],
    "options":["Britain", "Ireland", "The United States", "Germany", "Belgium", "Austria"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["technology", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Vanuatu?",
    "answers":["Port Vila"],
    "options":["Luganville", "Lakatoro", "Isangel", "Sola", "Port Olry"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Zambia?",
    "answers":["Lusaka"],
    "options":["Kitwe", "Livingstone", "Ndola", "Solwezi"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Algeria?",
    "answers":["Algiers"],
    "options":["Oran", "Annaba", "Constantine", "Setif"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Johann Wolfgang Von Goethe from?",
    "answers":["Germany"],
    "options":["Austria", "Romania", "The United States", "Russia", "Latvia", "Macedonia"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["authors", "books", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Tuvula?",
    "answers":["Funafuti"],
    "options":["Alapi", "Lolua", "Vaiaku"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"During what century did the first Crusades take place?",
    "answers":["11th"],
    "options":["12th", "10th", "9th", "13th", "14th"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["religion", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which pope ordered the first Crusade?",
    "answers":["Urban II"],
    "options":["Victor III", "Pschal II", "Alexander II", "Damasus II"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["religion", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Suriname?",
    "answers":["Paramaribo"],
    "options":["Nieuw Nickerie", "Nieuw Amsterdam", "Albina", "Lelydorp", "Moengo"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Soloman Islands?",
    "answers":["Honiara"],
    "options":["Gizo", "Auki", "Buala", "Lata", "Kirakira"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Togo?",
    "answers":["Lomé"],
    "options":["Tsevie", "Atakpame", "Sokode", "Kpalime", "Dapaong"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which is a capital of the Sri Lanka?",
    "answers":["Sri Jayawardenepura Kotte", "Colombo"],
    "options":["Kandy", "Galle", "Jaffna", "Anuradhapura"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Honduras?",
    "answers":["Tegucigalpa"],
    "options":["San Pedro Sula", "La Ceiba", "Comayagua", "Puerto Cortes", "Choluteca"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Papau New Guinea?",
    "answers":["Port Moresby"],
    "options":["Lae", "Goroka", "Mount Hagen", "Madang"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of the Qatar?",
    "answers":["Doha"],
    "options":["Al Rayyan", "Al Khor", "Ar Ruways", "Al Wakrah"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Facebook launched?",
    "answers":["2004"],
    "options":["2006", "2002", "2000", "2008", "2005", "2001", "2007"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["technology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Amazon founded?",
    "answers":["1994"],
    "options":["1997", "1991", "2001", "2003", "2005", "2001", "1992"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["technology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Youtube founded?",
    "answers":["2005"],
    "options":["1997", "2000", "2001", "2003", "2004", "2007", "2006", "2008", "1999"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["technology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Ebay founded?",
    "answers":["1995"],
    "options":["1997", "2000", "2001", "2003", "1993", "1991", "1999", "2004", "2006", "2007"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["technology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Netflix founded?",
    "answers":["1997"],
    "options":["1991", "1993", "1995", "1999", "2000", "2003", "2007", "2009", "2006", "2002"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["technology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these was founded first?",
    "answers":["Ebay", "Amazon"],
    "options":["Netflix", "Facebook", "Youtube", "Google", "LinkedIn", "Instagram"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["technology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Google founded?",
    "answers":["1998"],
    "options":["1991", "1993", "1995", "1999", "2000", "2003", "2007", "2009", "2006", "2002"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["technology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was LinkedIn founded?",
    "answers":["2002"],
    "options":["1991", "1993", "1995", "1999", "2000", "2003", "2007", "2009", "2006", "1998"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["technology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Instagram founded?",
    "answers":["2010"],
    "options":["1991", "1993", "1995", "1999", "2000", "2003", "2007", "2009", "2006", "1998", "2013", "2015"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["technology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"With what sport would you assosiate Kent Desormeaux?",
    "answers":["Horse Racing"],
    "options":["Ice Hockey", "Baseball", "American football", "Football (Soccer)", "Basketball", "Golf"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"In 2017, a Washington Post ad called Lorde a bigot for cancelling her show in which country?",
    "answers":["Israel"],
    "options":["Turkey", "Iran", "Venezuela", "Syria"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the biggest selling UK album of 2005?",
    "answers":["Back To Bedlam - James Blunt"],
    "options":["X & Y - Coldplay", "Robbie Wailliam - Intensive Care", "Demon Days - Gorillaz", "Face to Face - Westlife", "Hot Fuss - The Killers"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"Who had the biggest selling UK album of 2005 with 'Back To Bedlam'?",
    "answers":["James Blunt"],
    "options":["Coldplay", "Robbie Wailliam", "Gorillaz", "Westlife", "The Killers"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Madagascar",
    "answers":["Antananarivo"],
    "options":["Toamasina", "Antsirabe", "Mahajanga", "Tianarantsoa", "Toliara"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Seychelles",
    "answers":["Victoria"],
    "options":["Beau Vallon", "Baie Ste Anne", "La Passe"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Malaysia",
    "answers":["Kuala Lumpur"],
    "options":["Kuching", "Georgetown", "Johor Bahru", "Ipoh", "Malacca", "Kota Kinabalu"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Brunei",
    "answers":["Bandar Seri Begawan"],
    "options":["Kuala Belait", "Seria", "Bangar", "Tutong", "Muara"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Angola",
    "answers":["Luanda"],
    "options":["Lobito", "Lubango", "Huambo", "Saurimo"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Indonesia",
    "answers":["Jakarta"],
    "options":["Bandung", "Surabaya", "Medan", "Makassar", "Semarang"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Ivory Coast",
    "answers":["Yamoussoukro"],
    "options":["Abidjan", "Bouake", "San-Pedro", "Man", "Korhogo"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of St. Lucia",
    "answers":["Castries"],
    "options":["Soufriere", "Vieux Fort", "Laborie", "Gros Islet"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Sierra Leone",
    "answers":["Freetown"],
    "options":["Makeni", "Kenema", "Koidu", "Bo", "Lunsar"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Chad",
    "answers":["N'Djamena"],
    "options":["Abeche", "Sarh", "Moundou", "Kelo"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"The large ice sheets of Earth reflecting light from the sun which causes them to grow further is known as what?",
    "answers":["The albedo effect"],
    "options":["The adobe effect", "The Fermi effect", "The big freeze effect", "The domino effect"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"March 10th 1876 saw the first what?",
    "answers":["Phone call"],
    "options":["Radio station", "Vaccine use", "Sewing machine", "Plane crash"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["technology", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the first phone call made?",
    "answers":["1876"],
    "options":["1886", "1896", "1906", "1916", "1866", "1856", "1846"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "technology", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Nicaragua",
    "answers":["Managua"],
    "options":["León", "Granada", "Masaya", "Esteli"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of St. Kitts & Nevis",
    "answers":["Basseterre"],
    "options":["Charlestown", "Sandy Point Town", "Cayon", "Trinity"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Complete the name of this country. Saint Kitts and ",
    "answers":["Nevis"],
    "options":["Levis", "Pevis", "Mevis", "Revis", "Kevis", "Bevis"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Mongolia",
    "answers":["Ulaanbaatar"],
    "options":["Choibalsan", "Zuunmod", "Tsetserleg", "Uliastai"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Tajikistan",
    "answers":["Dushanbe"],
    "options":["Khujand", "Qurgonteppa", "Kulob", "Istaravshan"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries is not real",
    "answers":["Nairobistan", "Murkistan"],
    "options":["Tajikistan", "Uzbekistan", "Kyrgyzstan", "Turkmenistan"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is a capital of Benin",
    "answers":["Porto-Novo"],
    "options":["Parakou", "Abomey", "Ouidah", "Djougou", "Bohicon"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Kiribati",
    "answers":["South Tarawa"],
    "options":["Bikenibeu", "Eita", "Bairiki"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What horror film featured the character Samara Morgan?",
    "answers":["The Ring"],
    "options":["Hellraiser", "The Mist", "Oculus", "The Silence of the Lambs"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Chekhov's what is a principle in storytelling that states that every element in a story must be necessary, any irrelevant elements should be removed?",
    "answers":["Chekhov's gun"],
    "options":["Chekhov's ring", "Chekhov's law", "Chekhov's scroll", "Chekhov's flower", "Chekhov's chain", "Chekhov's piano", "Chekhov's trap", "Chekhov's loop"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["misc", "film"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Taiwan",
    "answers":["Taipei"],
    "options":["Tainan", "Taichung City", "New Taipei City", "Hsinchu", "Keelung City"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Nauru",
    "answers":["Yaren"],
    "options":["Boe", "Denigomodu", "Anibare", "Meneng"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Kenya",
    "answers":["Nairobi"],
    "options":["Mombasa", "Kisumu", "Nakuru", "Eldoret", "Malindi"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Georgia",
    "answers":["Tbilisi"],
    "options":["Batumi", "Kutaisi", "Rustavi", "Mtskheta", "Poti"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Guinea",
    "answers":["Conakry"],
    "options":["Kankan", "Nzerekore", "Labe", "Kissidougou", "Kamsar"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Eritrea",
    "answers":["Asmara"],
    "options":["Kitsiwa", "Assab", "Dekemhare", "Barentu", "Adi Ugri"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Kyrgyzstan",
    "answers":["Bishkek"],
    "options":["Osh", "Karakol", "Balykchy", "Tokmok", "Kara Balta"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Cape Verde",
    "answers":["Praia"],
    "options":["Mindelo", "Cidade Velha", "Sao Filipe", "Santa Maria", "Tarrafal"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Samoa",
    "answers":["Apia"],
    "options":["Asua", "Afega", "Vailima", "Lufi-lufi"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Mauritius",
    "answers":["Port Louis"],
    "options":["Curepipe", "Quatre Bornes", "Grand Baie", "Mahebourg"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Turkmenistan",
    "answers":["Ashgabat"],
    "options":["Turkmenabat", "Balkanabat", "Dashoguz"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Rwanda",
    "answers":["Kigali"],
    "options":["Kamembe", "Butare", "Gisenyi", "Nyanza", "Nyamata"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Gabon",
    "answers":["Libreville"],
    "options":["Port-Gentil", "Franceville", "Lambarene", "Oyem", "Mouila"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Namibia",
    "answers":["Windhoek"],
    "options":["Swakopmund", "Walvis Bay", "Otijwarongo", "Keetmanshoop", "Okahandja"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Bahrain",
    "answers":["Manama"],
    "options":["Riffa", "Muharraq", "Isa Town", "Hamad Town"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Uzbekistan",
    "answers":["Tashkent"],
    "options":["Samarkand", "Bukhara", "Khiva", "Nukus", "Andijan"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Oman",
    "answers":["Muscat"],
    "options":["Salalah", "Nizwa", "Sohar", "Sur", "Khasab"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of East Timor",
    "answers":["Dili"],
    "options":["Maliana", "Lospalos", "Suai", "Baucau", "Aileu"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Laos",
    "answers":["Vientiane"],
    "options":["Luang Prabang", "Vang Vieng", "Pakse", "Phonsavan", "Thakhek"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Senegal",
    "answers":["Dakar"],
    "options":["Saint Louis", "Kaolack", "Touba", "Ziguinchor"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Maldives",
    "answers":["Malé"],
    "options":["Addu City", "Maroshi", "Funadhoo", "Gan", "Veymandhoo", "Gan", "Hithadhoo"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Where did the Arab spring start its first protests?",
    "answers":["Tunisia"],
    "options":["Libya", "Yemen", "Egypt", "Syria", "Bahrain"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"'O it is excellent to have a giant's strength; but it is tyrannous to use it like a giant', comes from which Shakespeare work?",
    "answers":["Measure for Measure"],
    "options":["Hamlet", "Romeo and Juliet", "Macbeth", "King Lear", "The Tempest"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes", "books"]
},
{
    "question":"Jeff Bezos is the CEO of which company?",
    "answers":["Amazon"],
    "options":["Ebay", "Apple", "Google", "Tiktok", "Tesla", "Sony", "Samsung", "LG"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["technology"]
},
{
    "question":"Jamal Khashoggi was a journalist and dissident from what country?",
    "answers":["Saudi Arabia"],
    "options":["Iran", "North Korea", "China", "Russia", "Yemen", "Serbia", "Iraq"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Leonardo Da Vinci born?",
    "answers":["April 15 1452"],
    "options":["April 15 1552", "April 15 1652", "April 15 1752", "April 15 1352", "April 15 1252"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["art", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Leonardo Da Vinci die?",
    "answers":["May 2, 1519"],
    "options":["May 2 1519", "May 2 1619", "May 2 1719", "May 2 1319", "May 2 1219"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["art", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of Peppa Pig's brother?",
    "answers":["George"],
    "options":["Stephen", "Mike", "Randy", "Karl", "Max", "Ron"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"What is Stan's second name in South Park?",
    "answers":["Marsh"],
    "options":["Cartman", "Smith", "Dixon", "Myers", "Willis", "Collins"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"What is Stan's father's name in South Park?",
    "answers":["Randy"],
    "options":["Lance", "Darryl", "Mateo", "Ronan", "Steve", "Cory"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was artists Sandro Botticelli from?",
    "answers":["Italy"],
    "options":["Greece", "The United States", "France", "Libya"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"Who painted 'The Birth of Venus'?",
    "answers":["Sandro Botticelli"],
    "options":["Michelangelo", "Leonardo da Vinci", "Raphael", "Donatello", "Caravaggio", "Titian"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"Who painted 'Saint Jerome in the Wilderness'?",
    "answers":["Leonardo da Vinci"],
    "options":["Michelangelo", "Sandro Botticelli", "Raphael", "Donatello", "Caravaggio", "Titian"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"St Jerome was famous for his translation of the Bible into what language?",
    "answers":["Latin"],
    "options":["English", "French", "Italian", "Greek"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["religion"]
},
{
    "question":"Who became pope in 1978?",
    "answers":["Pope John Paul II"],
    "options":["Pope Benedict XVI", "Pope Francis", "Pope John Paul I"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["religion"]
},
{
    "question":"Who became pope in 2005?",
    "answers":["Pope Benedict XVI"],
    "options":["Pope John Paul II", "Pope Francis", "Pope John Paul I"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["religion"]
},
{
    "question":"Who became pope in 2013?",
    "answers":["Pope Francis"],
    "options":["Pope John Paul II", "Pope Benedict XVI", "Pope John Paul I"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["religion"]
},
{
    "question":"What was Michelangelo's surname?",
    "answers":["Buonarroti"],
    "options":["Lucciano", "Di Traglia", "Schiavone", "Presutti"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Michelangelo born?",
    "answers":["March 6th 1475"],
    "options":["March 6th 1375", "March 6th 1275", "March 6th 1575", "March 6th 1675"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["art", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Michelangelo die?",
    "answers":["Feb 18th 1564"],
    "options":["Feb 18th 1664", "Feb 18th 1764", "Feb 18th 1464", "Feb 18th 1364", "Feb 18th 1264"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["art", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"'A single death is a tragedy, a million deaths are a statistic' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Joseph Stalin"],
    "options":["Adolf Hitler", "Joseph Goebbels", "Fritz Haber", "Jim Jones"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["art", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, what is the void state preceding the creation of the universe?",
    "answers":["Chaos"],
    "options":["Dissarray", "Havoc", "Aidos", "Monos"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["mythology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"The Ring of Gyges is a mythical magical artifact that grants its owner what power?",
    "answers":["Invisibility"],
    "options":["Invincibility", "Flight", "Superstrength", "X-ray vision", "Telepathy"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["mythology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What mythical magical artifact grants its owner invisibility?",
    "answers":["The Ring of Gyges"],
    "options":["The Cloak of Gyges", "The Hood of Gyges", "The Orb of Gyges", "The Hand of Gyges"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["mythology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Glaucon is the brother of which philosopher?",
    "answers":["Plato"],
    "options":["Aristotle", "Socrates", "Epicurus", "Heraclitus"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["philosophy", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of Plato's brother?",
    "answers":["Glaucon"],
    "options":["Aegeus", "Agnes", "Alejandro", "Elpis", "Erato"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["philosophy", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"One of the 5 tastes, umami is often known as what?",
    "answers":["Savory"],
    "options":["Sweet", "Sour", "Bitter", "Salty"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Where is Area 51 located?",
    "answers":["Nevada"],
    "options":["New Mexico", "Louisiana", "Connecticut", "South Carolina", "Nebraska", "Texas", "Iowa", "Arkansas", "Kentucky", "Wyonming"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What brain cell reacts both when a particular action is performed & when its only observed?",
    "answers":["Mirror nueron"],
    "options":["Copy nueron", "Reflexive nueron", "Motor nueron", "Dupe nueron"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"'Ask not what your country can do for you, ask what you can do for your country' is a quote from which American President?",
    "answers":["John F. Kennedy"],
    "options":["Ronald Reagan", "George W. Bush", "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "Harry S. Truman", "Franklin D. Roosevelt"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Yakuza is a mafia originating in which country?",
    "answers":["Japan"],
    "options":["China", "North Korea", "Taiwan", "Vietnam", "Yemen"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Where is the source of the Rhine river",
    "answers":["Switzerland"],
    "options":["Germany", "Belgium", "Amsterdam"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"In World War 2 which of these countries were part of 'The Big Three'",
    "answers":["The United States", "The Solviet Union", "The United Kingdom"],
    "options":["Poland", "Mexico", "Germany"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["war", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Michael Schumacher was born in which country?",
    "answers":["Germany"],
    "options":["Poland", "England", "France", "Austria", "Italy", "Germany"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["sports"]
},
{
    "question":"Which Japenese emporer announced Japan's surrender to the Allied Forces in 1945?",
    "answers":["Hirohito"],
    "options":["Akihito", "Yoshihito", "Mutsuhito", "Osahito"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["war", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Shangri-La is a fictional place described in the 1933 novel?",
    "answers":["Lost Horizon"],
    "options":["Brave New World", "Gulliver's Travels", "The Giver", "The Dispossessed"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"'Lost Horizon' is a 1933 novel by which British autor?",
    "answers":["James Hilton"],
    "options":["George Orwell", "Thomas Hardy", "E. M. Forester", "C. S. Lewis", "Virginia Woolf"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["authors", "books"]
},
{
    "question":"Atoms for Peace was the title of a speech by which U.S president?",
    "answers":["Dwight D. Eisenhower"],
    "options":["Ronald Reagan", "George W. Bush", "John F. Kennedy", "Harry S. Truman", "Franklin D. Roosevelt"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, who is credited with the creation of humanity",
    "answers":["Prometheus"],
    "options":["Apollo", "Ares", "Hades", "Artemis", "Poseidon", "Zeus"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["mythology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, Prometheus created humanity out of what",
    "answers":["Clay"],
    "options":["Diamond", "Dirt", "Coal", "Feather", "Gold"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["mythology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, Prometheus defies the gods by stealing what and giving it to humanity as civilization?",
    "answers":["Fire"],
    "options":["Lightning", "Dirt", "Coal", "Feather", "Gold", "Diamond"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["mythology", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Which laws were state and local laws that enforced racial segregation in the Southern United States?",
    "answers":["Jim Crow laws"],
    "options":["Jim Marsh laws", "Jim Jones laws", "Jim Jack laws", "Jim Lykes laws"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["law", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Jim Crow laws were enforced until when?",
    "answers":["1965"],
    "options":["1975", "1985", "1955", "1945", "1935", "1925"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["law", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is a common mathematical ratio found in nature?",
    "answers":["The Golden Ratio"],
    "options":["The Silver Ratio", "The Bronze Ratio", "The Diamond Ratio", "The Iron Ratio"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["math"]
},
{
    "question":"Which reactor exploded in Chernobyl in 1986?",
    "answers":["The fourth reactor"],
    "options":["The first reactor", "The second reactor", "The third reactor", "The fifth reactor"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of the structure built to confine the remains of the number 4 reactor unit at the Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant?",
    "answers":["The New Safe Confinement"],
    "options":["The Internation Effort at Safe Confinement", "The Nuclear Failure Confinement", "The Reactor Conrete Confinement"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the New Safe Confinement, the structure built to confine the remains of the Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant, finished?",
    "answers":["2019"],
    "options":["2016", "2012", "1986", "1993", "1997", "2001", "2005"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Which is not one of the 4 C's of diamonds?",
    "answers":["Character", "Curvature", "Cabbage"],
    "options":["Cut", "Colour", "Clarity", "Carat"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1983 a solviet air force pilot accidentally shot down an airliner from which country?",
    "answers":["Korea"],
    "options":["The United States", "Iran", "China", "Germany", "France", "Egypt"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is a Veblen good?",
    "answers":["A good for which demand increases as the price increases"],
    "options":["A good for which demand decreases as the price increases", "A good for which demand increases as the price decreases", "A good for which demand decreases as the price decreases"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["economics", "misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What was taken to mean increased openness and transparency in government institutions and activities in the Soviet Union?",
    "answers":["Glasnost"],
    "options":["Glavlit", "Gosplan", "Gulag", "Voenkomat", "Zemstvo", "Boyar", "Blat", "Cheka", "Cossacks", "Duma"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"DNA stands for what?",
    "answers":["Deoxyribonucleic acid"],
    "options":["Dioxidizing nueron acid", "Dextrix neon acid", "Diode nueral acid", "Determental nylon acid"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"The Great Barrier Reef is located off the coast of which country?",
    "answers":["Australia"],
    "options":["Spain", "Sri Lanka", "Canada", "Russia", "Greece", "Mexico"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"The Great Barrier Reef is visible from space?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, who was described as a winged females with living venemous snake hair?",
    "answers":["Medusa"],
    "options":["Cassandra", "Amazons", "Aphrodite", "Atlanta", "Pandora"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["mythology"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, looking into Medusa's eyes would turn a person into what?",
    "answers":["Stone"],
    "options":["Diamond", "Dirt", "Iron", "Sand", "Pandora"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["mythology"]
},
{
    "question":"The lining of eyes contains two kinds of differently shaped cells, which is responsible for perceiving colour?",
    "answers":["Cones"],
    "options":["Rods", "Cylinders", "Cubes", "Torus"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"The lining of eyes contains two kinds of differently shaped cells, cones and what?",
    "answers":["Rods"],
    "options":["Cylinders", "Cubes", "Torus"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"An abundance of what element in a layer of rock at the Cretaceuos - Paleogene boundary all around the world was evidence of an asteroid wiping out the dinosaurs?",
    "answers":["Iridium"],
    "options":["Potassium", "Nickel", "Niobium", "Praseodymium", "Hydrogen", "Lead"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"What fish uses a shiny lure to bring prey within range of its sharp teeth?",
    "answers":["Anglerfish"],
    "options":["Zander", "Megalodon", "Catfish", "Swordfish"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["animals", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"When Pangea broke up, its northern continent is referred to as what?",
    "answers":["Laurasia"],
    "options":["Americasia", "Norasia", "Sorasia", "Antarasia"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When Pangea broke up, its southern continent is referred to as what?",
    "answers":["Gondwana"],
    "options":["Laurafrica", "Europassa", "Sorasia", "Panthalassa", "Golgotha"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is a group of lions called?",
    "answers":["A pride"],
    "options":["A troop", "An army", "A mob", "A herd", "A pack"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["animals", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"What is a group of wombats called?",
    "answers":["A wisdom"],
    "options":["A troop", "An army", "A mob", "A herd", "A pack", "A pride", "A scurry", "A prickle", "A cavern"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["animals", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which planet is closest to the Sun?",
    "answers":["Mercury"],
    "options":["Venus", "Earth", "Mars", "Jupiter", "Saturn", "Uranus", "Neptune"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"In order of closest to the sun, which planet comes second?",
    "answers":["Venus"],
    "options":["Mercury", "Earth", "Mars", "Jupiter", "Saturn", "Uranus", "Neptune"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"In order of closest to the sun, which planet comes third?",
    "answers":["Earth"],
    "options":["Mercury", "Venus", "Mars", "Jupiter", "Saturn", "Uranus", "Neptune"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"In order of closest to the sun, which planet comes fourth?",
    "answers":["Mars"],
    "options":["Mercury", "Venus", "Earth", "Jupiter", "Saturn", "Uranus", "Neptune"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"In order of closest to the sun, which planet comes fifth?",
    "answers":["Jupiter"],
    "options":["Mercury", "Venus", "Earth", "Mars", "Saturn", "Uranus", "Neptune"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"In order of closest to the sun, which planet comes sixth?",
    "answers":["Saturn"],
    "options":["Mercury", "Venus", "Earth", "Mars", "Jupiter", "Uranus", "Neptune"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"In order of closest to the sun, which planet comes seventh?",
    "answers":["Uranus"],
    "options":["Mercury", "Venus", "Earth", "Mars", "Jupiter", "Saturn", "Neptune"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"In order of closest to the sun, which planet comes eigth?",
    "answers":["Neptune"],
    "options":["Mercury", "Venus", "Earth", "Mars", "Jupiter", "Saturn", "Uranus"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"How many white keys are there on a normal piano?",
    "answers":["52"],
    "options":["58", "64", "72", "80", "56", "42", "46", "38", "32", "66"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"How many black keys are there on a normal piano?",
    "answers":["36"],
    "options":["38", "44", "52", "30", "46", "32", "26", "28", "42", "66"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["music"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these films won an Oscar for best picture?",
    "answers":["Forrest Gump", "Ordinary People", "Rain Man", "Rocky", "The Godfather"],
    "options":["Fargo", "Shawshank Redemption", "Pulp Fiction", "Goodfellas", "Raging Bull", "2001: A Space Odyssey", "Psycho", "Citizen Kane", "Saving Private Ryan"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2019 (92nd) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["Parasite"],
    "options":["Ford v Ferrari", "The Irishman", "Joker", "Marriage Story", "1917", "Once Upon a Time in Hollywood"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2018 (91st) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["Green Book"],
    "options":["Black Panther", "BlacKkKlansman", "Bohemian Rhapsody", "The Favourite", "Roma", "A Star Is Born"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2017 (90th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["The Shape of Water"],
    "options":["Call Me by Your Name", "Darkest Hour", "Dunkirk", "Get Out", "Phantom Thread", "Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2016 (89th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["Moonlight"],
    "options":["Arrival", "Hacksaw Ridge", "Hell or High Water", "Hidden Figures", "La La Land", "Manchester by the Sea"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2015 (88th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["Spotlight"],
    "options":["The Big Short", "Bridge of Spies", "Brooklyn", "Mad Max: Fury Road", "The Revenant", "Room"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2014 (87th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["Birdman or (The Unexpected Virtue of Ignorance)"],
    "options":["American Sniper", "Boyhood", "The Grand Budapest Hotel", "The Imitation Game", "The Theory of Everything", "Whiplash"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2013 (86th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["12 Years a Slave"],
    "options":["American Hustle", "Captain Phillips", "Dallas Buyers Club", "Gravity", "Her", "The Wolf of Wall Street"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2012 (85th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["Argo"],
    "options":["Amour", "Django Unchained", "Les Misérables", "Life of Pi", "Lincoln", "Zero Dark Thirty"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2011 (84th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["The Artist"],
    "options":["The Descendants", "The Help", "Hugo", "Midnight in Paris", "Moneyball", "The Tree of Life"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2010 (83rd) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["The King's Speech"],
    "options":["127 Hours", "Black Swan", "The Fighter", "Inception", "The Social Network", "Toy Story 3"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2009 (82nd) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["The Hurt Locker"],
    "options":["Avatar", "The Blind Side", "District 9", "Inglourious Basterds", "A Serious Man", "Up"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2008 (81st) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["Slumdog Millionaire"],
    "options":["The Curious Case of Benjamin Button", "Frost/Nixon", "Milk", "The Reader"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2007 (80th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["No Country for Old Men"],
    "options":["Atonement", "Juno", "Michael Clayton", "There Will Be Blood"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2006 (79th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["The Departed"],
    "options":["Babel", "Letters from Iwo Jima", "The Queen", "Little Miss Sunshine"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2005 (78th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["Crash"],
    "options":["Brokeback Mountain", "Capote", "Good Night, and Good Luck", "Munich"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2004 (77th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["Million Dollar Baby"],
    "options":["The Aviator", "Finding Neverland", "Ray", "Sideways"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2003 (76th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King"],
    "options":["Lost in Translation", "Master and Commander: The Far Side of the World", "Mystic River", "Seabiscuit"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2002 (75th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["Chicago"],
    "options":["Gangs of New York", "The Hours", "The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers", "The Pianist"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2001 (74th) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["A Beautiful Mind"],
    "options":["Moulin Rouge!", "Gosford Park", "In the Bedroom", "The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which film won the 2000 (73rd) Oscar for 'Best Picture'",
    "answers":["Gladiator"],
    "options":["Chocolat", "Traffic", "Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon", "Erin Brockovich"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Who hosted the 2019 Grammys",
    "answers":["Alicia Keys"],
    "options":["James Corden", "Will Smith", "Chris Rock", "Joseph Gordon-Levitt", "Seth Macfarlane", "Neil Patrick Harris"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Who Played Barney Stinson in 'How I Met Your Mother'?",
    "answers":["Neil Patrick Harris"],
    "options":["Jason Segel", "Josh Radnor", "Bob Saget", "Matthew Perry"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"From the popular videogame, who is Ratchet's companion?",
    "answers":["Clank"],
    "options":["Daxter", "Tails", "Cortana", "Solas"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["videogames"]
},
{
    "question":"Which Halo charcater later became the name for Microsoft's virtual assistant?",
    "answers":["Cortana"],
    "options":["Alexa", "Tails", "Pixel", "Ava", "Abigail", "Mia", "Talulla", "Fay"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["videogames", "technology"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is one of Mars' moons?",
    "answers":["Phobos", "Deimos"],
    "options":["Europa", "Titan", "Ganymede", "Enceladus", "Io", "Triton", "Callisto"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"When did scientists discovered the virus that causes AIDS?",
    "answers":["1983"],
    "options":["1993", "1973", "1963", "1986", "1966", "1996", "1976"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["medicine", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"In what month in 2020 did Italy go on lockdown for the first time due to COVID-19?",
    "answers":["February"],
    "options":["January", "March", "April", "May"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"When in 2020 did Ireland go on full lockdown for the first time due to COVID-19?",
    "answers":["March 27th"],
    "options":["February 27th", "April 27th", "May 27th", "January 27th", "June 27th"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"In what month in 2020 did we reach 1 million people confirmed to have COVID-19?",
    "answers":["April"],
    "options":["January", "March", "February", "May", "June", "July"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"When in 2020 did the WHO declare COVID-19 a pandemic?",
    "answers":["March 11th"],
    "options":["January 11th", "Febuary 11th", "April 11th", "May 11th", "June 26th", "March 26th", "January 26th", "Febuary 26th", "April 26th", "May 26th", "June 26th"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Who is credited with the discover of penicillin?",
    "answers":["Sir Alexander Fleming"],
    "options":["Edward Jenner", "Joseph Lister", "Virginia Apgar", "William Osler", "Andreas Vesalius"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["medicine", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Sir Alexander Fleming discover penicillin?",
    "answers":["1928"],
    "options":["1918", "1908", "1898", "1888", "1938", "1948"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["medicine", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Where was Alexander Fleming from?",
    "answers":["Scotland"],
    "options":["Ireland", "Germany", "England", "France", "Austria", "Greece", "Malta"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"What Vitamin does our body produce when exposed directly to the sun?",
    "answers":["D"],
    "options":["A", "C", "E", "K"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"According to the quote, 'Hard times create strong men. Strong men create good times. Good times create' what?",
    "answers":["Weak men"],
    "options":["Hard men", "Hard times", "Weak times"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was assassinated on April 4 1968?",
    "answers":["Martin Luther King Jr."],
    "options":["Indira Gandhi", "Franz Ferdinand", "Martin Luther King Jr.", "Malcolm X", "Mahatma Gandhi"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these famous figures was not born in 1929?",
    "answers":["Adam West", "Shirley Temple", "Marilyn Monroe", "David Attenborough"],
    "options":["Martin Luther King Jr.", "Anne Frank", "Audrey Hepburn"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these famous figures was not born in 1926?",
    "answers":["Malcolm X", "Margaret Thatcher", "Sten Lee"],
    "options":["Marilyn Monroe", "David Attenborough", "Fidel Castro"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Martin Luther King Jr. born?",
    "answers":["January 15 1929"],
    "options":["January 15 1924", "January 15 1934", "January 15 1939", "January 15 1914", "January 15 1919"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Jan 27, 1967, when a flash fire swept through which Apollo mission?",
    "answers":["Apollo 1"],
    "options":["Apollo 4", "Apollo 11", "Apollo 8", "Apollo 9", "Apollo 5"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of the Solviet space dog who became one of the first animals in space?",
    "answers":["Laika"],
    "options":["Alexei", "Katya", "Svetlana", "Viktor", "Feliks", "Fyodor", "Pyotr", "Oleg"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Laika, was the Solveit space dog who went into space in 1957. What does Barker translate to?",
    "answers":["Barker"],
    "options":["Rock", "Watchful", "Progressor", "Defender of mankind", "Wolf"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"What animal was the first to orbit Earth?",
    "answers":["A dog"],
    "options":["A chimpanzee", "A duck", "A hamster", "A cat"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Laika, became one of the first animals to orbit the Earth in what year?",
    "answers":["1957"],
    "options":["1967", "1947", "1977", "1961", "1951", "1971", "1941"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the Red Square?",
    "answers":["Moscow, Russia"],
    "options":["Beijing, China", "Rome, Italy", "Nampo , North Korea"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was the first American to travel into space?",
    "answers":["Alan Shepard Jr."],
    "options":["Neil Armstrong", "Michael Collins", "Buzz Aldrin"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Alan Shepard Jr. become the first American to travel into space?",
    "answers":["1961"],
    "options":["1965", "1969", "1972", "1974", "1959", "1957", "1954"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Alan Shepard Jr. became the first America to travel into space in 1961. He has also walked on the Moon",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of the chimpanzee and the first hominid launched into space in 1961",
    "answers":["Ham"],
    "options":["Laika", "Colo", "Aldo", "Lazlo", "Bingo", "Winston"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Genji, Widowmaker and Mercy are all characters of which videogame?",
    "answers":["Overwatch"],
    "options":["Halo", "League of Legends", "Fortnite", "Team Fortress 2"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["videogames"]
},
{
    "question":"Ham, was a chimpanzee and the first hominid launched into space, when did he go into space?",
    "answers":["1961"],
    "options":["1958", "1956", "1953", "1951", "1962", "1948"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Approximately how hot is the surface of the sun?",
    "answers":["10,000 degrees Farenheit"],
    "options":["100,000 degrees Farenheit", "1,000,000 degrees Farenheit", "1,000 degrees Farenheit", "5,000 degrees Farenheit", "50,000 degrees Farenheit", "500,000 degrees Farenheit"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Owls only live in dead trees?",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["trees", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is not a colour of the rainbow?",
    "answers":["Brown", "Turquoise"],
    "options":["Red", "Orange", "Yellow", "Green", "Blue", "Indigo", "Violet"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["colours", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is not a colour prime colour?",
    "answers":["Green", "White", "Black"],
    "options":["Red", "Yellow", "Blue"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["colours"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is not a colour secondary color?",
    "answers":["Red", "White", "Black", "Blue", "Yellow", "Brown"],
    "options":["Green", "Orange", "Violet"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["colours"]
},
{
    "question":"Theodore Roosevelt in 1901 invited who into the White House, causing controversy for doing so?",
    "answers":["Booker T. Washington"],
    "options":["Henry Ford", "Martin Luther King, Jr.", "Klara Hitler", "Ibn Saud", "Joseph Stalin", "Pancho Villa"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president in 1901 invited Booker T. Washington into the White House, causing controversy for doing so?",
    "answers":["Theodore Roosevelt"],
    "options":["William Howard Taft", "Woodrow Wilson", "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "William McKinley"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president was Theodore Roosevelt?",
    "answers":["The 26th"],
    "options":["The 27th", "The 28th", "The 29th", "The 25th", "The 24th", "The 30th", "The 31st"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president was Franklin D Roosevelt?",
    "answers":["The 32nd"],
    "options":["The 33rd", "The 34th", "The 29th", "The 35th", "The 36th", "The 30th", "The 31st"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president was Harry S. Truman?",
    "answers":["The 33rd"],
    "options":["The 34th", "The 29th", "The 35th", "The 36th", "The 30th", "The 31st", "The 32nd"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president was Dwight D. Einsenhower?",
    "answers":["The 34th"],
    "options":["The 33rd", "The 35th", "The 36th", "The 30th", "The 31st", "The 32nd", "The 37th"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president was John F. Kennedy?",
    "answers":["The 35th"],
    "options":["The 33rd", "The 34th", "The 36th", "The 30th", "The 31st", "The 32nd", "The 37th"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president was Lyndon B. Johnson?",
    "answers":["The 36th"],
    "options":["The 33rd", "The 34th", "The 35th", "The 38th", "The 31st", "The 32nd", "The 37th"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president was Richard D Nixon?",
    "answers":["The 37th"],
    "options":["The 33rd", "The 34th", "The 35th", "The 38th", "The 39th", "The 32nd", "The 36th"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president was Donald Trump?",
    "answers":["The 45th"],
    "options":["The 43rd", "The 44th", "The 46th", "The 48th", "The 39th", "The 42nd", "The 47th"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Nasa founded?",
    "answers":["On October 1 1958"],
    "options":["On October 1 1968", "On October 1 1978", "On October 1 1948", "On October 1 1938", "On October 1 1928", "On October 1 1918"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["science", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Vietnam war start?",
    "answers":["November 1, 1955"],
    "options":["November 1, 1965", "November 1, 1975", "November 1, 1985", "November 1, 1945", "November 1, 1935", "November 1, 1925"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["war", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Vietnam war end?",
    "answers":["April 30, 1975"],
    "options":["April 30, 1965", "April 30, 1955", "April 30, 1945", "April 30, 1985"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["war", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Tét is the New Year of which country?",
    "answers":["Vietnam"],
    "options":["Taiwan", "Angola", "Yemen", "Brunei", "Bhutan", "Brussles", "Finlald", "Denmark", "Austria", "Norway", "China"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What occured on February 8, 1968?",
    "answers":["The Orangeburg massacre"],
    "options":["The Blueburg massacre", "The Redburg massacre", "The Violetburg massacre", "The Azureburg massacre", "The Greenburg massacre"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"The Orangeburg massacre, after black customers where refused from where?",
    "answers":["A bowling alley"],
    "options":["An arcade", "A video rental store", "A laundromat", "A bath house", "A roller disco", "A nightclub"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of a condition caused by a rapid substantial decrease in atmospheric pressure, as in high-altitude flying and coming up from deep-sea diving?",
    "answers":["The Bends"],
    "options":["The Warps", "Laughing Death", "Fizzle out syndrome", "Alice in Wonderland syndrome", "Progeria"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medical", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"In a lake, there is a patch of lily pads. Every day, the patch doubles in size. If it takes 20 days for the patch to cover the entire lake, how long would it take for the patch to cover half of the lake?",
    "answers":["19 days"],
    "options":["10 days", "1 day", "20 days", "15 days"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["riddles"]
},
{
    "question":"A bat and ball cost €1.10. The bat costs one dollar more than the ball. How much does the ball cost?",
    "answers":["€1.05"],
    "options":["€1.00", "10c", "20c"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["riddles"]
},
{
    "question":"If it takes 5 machines 5 minutes to make 5 widgets, how long would it take 100 machines to make 100 widgets?",
    "answers":["5 minutes"],
    "options":["100 minutes", "50 minutes", "20 minutes"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["riddles"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of a condition in which one type of stimulation evokes the sensation of another?",
    "answers":["Synthesia"],
    "options":["The Warps", "Laughing Death", "Fizzle out syndrome", "Alice in Wonderland syndrome", "Progeria", "The Bends"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["medical", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Synthesia is a condition in which one type of stimulation evokes the sensation of another, the only people who have is are women",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medical", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Tetrachromacy is the condition of possessing four types of cone cell in the eye, the only people who have it are women",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["medical", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Tetrachromacy is the condition of possessing how many types of cone cell in the eye?",
    "answers":["4"],
    "options":["2", "1", "3", "5", "6"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["medical", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the alcohol used in alcoholic drinks?",
    "answers":["Ethonal"],
    "options":["Isopropyl", "Methonal", "Miranal"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["drinks"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the alcohol used as rubbing alcohol?",
    "answers":["Isopropyl"],
    "options":["Ethonal", "Methonal", "Miranal"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["medical"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is not an alcohol?",
    "answers":["Tetrachonal", "Synthenal"],
    "options":["Ethonal", "Methonal", "Isopropyl"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these people died on August 5th, 1962?",
    "answers":["Marilyn Monroe"],
    "options":["Erwin Schrodinger", "Walt Disney", "Joseph Stalin", "Humphrey Bogart", "George Orwell"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these people died in 1950?",
    "answers":["George Orwell"],
    "options":["Erwin Schrodinger", "Walt Disney", "Joseph Stalin", "Humphrey Bogart", "Marilyn Monroe"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"According to the death certificate, which of these overdosed from Barbiturate?",
    "answers":["Marilyn Monroe"],
    "options":["Philip Seymour Hoffman", "Heath Ledger", "Amy Winehouse", "Michael Jackson", "Judy Garland"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these people died in 1950?",
    "answers":["George Orwell"],
    "options":["Erwin Schrodinger", "Walt Disney", "Joseph Stalin", "Humphrey Bogart", "Marilyn Monroe"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Albert Homann invent LSD?",
    "answers":["1938"],
    "options":["1948", "1928", "1918", "1908", "1898", "1888", "1958"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1938, chemist Albert Homann invented LSD, where was he from?",
    "answers":["Sweden"],
    "options":["Scotland", "Germany", "Austria", "Finland", "Denmark", "Ireland"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Which Chinese dynasty lasted from 206BC to 220AD?",
    "answers":["The Han dynasty"],
    "options":["Sui Dynasty", "Tang Dynasty", "Qin Dynasty", "Zhou Dynasty", "Shang Dynasty"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which letter is derived from the Phoenician letter samekh, meaning 'fish'?",
    "answers":["X"],
    "options":["F", "S", "T", "Q", "Y"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"X is derived from the Phoenician letter samekh, meaning what?",
    "answers":["Fish"],
    "options":["Fire", "Stampede", "Extreme", "Toil", "Queen", "Year"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"X is derived from the letter samekh, from which civilization?",
    "answers":["Phoenicians"],
    "options":["Persians", "Assyrians", "Babylonians", "Choson", "Egyptians", "Hittites", "Greeks", "Minoans", "Yamato"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these was not part of Yugoslavia?",
    "answers":["Slovakia", "Bulgaria", "Albania"],
    "options":["Bosnia and Herzegovina", "Croatia", "Macedonia", "Montenegro", "Serbia", "Slovenia"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of the politician who served as the President of Serbia from 1989 to 1992?",
    "answers":["Slobodan Miloševic"],
    "options":["Nicolae Ceaușescu", "Bogdan Filov", "Nikola Mikhov", "Todor Pavlov", "Rafael Boban"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Until his death in 1980, who was serving as the president of Yugoslavia?",
    "answers":["Josip Broz Tito"],
    "options":["Slobodan Miloševic", "Nicolae Ceaușescu", "Bogdan Filov", "Nikola Mikhov", "Todor Pavlov", "Rafael Boban"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Zoran Dindic, the Prime Minister of Serbia was assassinated for fighting organized crime. He was often known as the what of the Balkans?",
    "answers":["Kennedy"],
    "options":["King", "Luther", "Mother Teresa", "Angel"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is this missing word in this quote from Andrew Yang, 'Humans need ___ more than ___ needs us'?",
    "answers":["Work"],
    "options":["The Earth", "America", "Extraterrestrial life", "The Sun", "Fun"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name for a member of the group of English workers who destroyed machinery, especially in cotton and woollen mills, that they believed was threatening their jobs?",
    "answers":["Luddite"],
    "options":["Theorist", "Darwinite", "Luricker", "Meliorist"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the economic term that describes a good whose demand drops when people's incomes rise?",
    "answers":["Inferior good"],
    "options":["Veblen good", "Normal good", "Luxury good", "Giffen good"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["economics"]
},
{
    "question":"Lunatic comes from the Latin word for what?",
    "answers":["Moon"],
    "options":["Mind", "Peace", "Normality", "Sponge", "Nut", "Lace"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries does not have mandated time off work for new mothers?",
    "answers":["United States", "Lethoso", "Papa New Guinea", "Eswatini"],
    "options":["Switzerland", "Macedonia", "Japan", "Sudan", "Yemen", "Eritrea", "Philippines", "Singapore"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["economics", "politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Pre day, you blink more than you breath",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["medical", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Approximately how many times do you blink per day",
    "answers":["14,000"],
    "options":["1,400", "140,000", "29,000", "2,900", "290,000"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["medical", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Approximately how many breaths do you take per day",
    "answers":["20,000"],
    "options":["2000", "29,000", "200,000", "2,900", "290,000"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["medical", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"The full chemical name for the human protein titin is 189,819 letters long",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medical", "science", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"The full chemical name for the human protein titin is 1,897 letters long",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medical", "science", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"The name of a city in Ghana is 1,897 letters long",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medical", "science", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"Ephelide is the scientific word for what?",
    "answers":["A freckle"],
    "options":["A mole", "An ingrowing toenail", "A wart", "A blister", "A blackhead"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medical", "science", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"Ephelide is the scientific term for what?",
    "answers":["Goose bumps"],
    "options":["A mole", "An ingrowing toenail", "A wart", "A blister", "A blackhead", "A freckle"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medical", "science", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"Adermatoglyphia is a condition that means a patient won't have what?",
    "answers":["Fingerprints"],
    "options":["Nails", "Earlobes", "Skin", "Facial hair"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["medical", "science", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries did no join the EU on 1 January 1973?",
    "answers":["Greece", "Spain", "Portugal"],
    "options":["Denmark", "The UK", "Ireland"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics", "economics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"On 1 January 1981 which country became the 10th to join the EU?",
    "answers":["Greece"],
    "options":["Denmark", "The UK", "Ireland", "Spain", "Portugal"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics", "economics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"1 January 1986, Portugal and which other country joined the EU?",
    "answers":["Spain"],
    "options":["Denmark", "The UK", "Ireland", "Greece", "Austria"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics", "economics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"1 January 1986, Spain and which other country joined the EU?",
    "answers":["Portugal"],
    "options":["Denmark", "The UK", "Ireland", "Greece", "Austria"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics", "economics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"On 1 January 1995, 3 countries joined the EU, which of these was not one of them?",
    "answers":["Denmark", "Greece", "Spain"],
    "options":["Finland", "Sweden", "Austria"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics", "economics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"On 1 May 2004, 10 countries joined the EU, which of these was not one of them?",
    "answers":["Romania", "Bulgaria", "Croatia", "Albania"],
    "options":["Cyprus", "Czech Republic", "Estonia", "Hungary", "Latvia", "Lithuania", "Malta", "Poland", "Slovakia", "Slovenia"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["politics", "economics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"On 1 January 2007, 2 countries joined the EU, which of these countries was one of them?",
    "answers":["Romania", "Bulgaria"],
    "options":["Croatia", "Albania", "Malta", "Estonia", "Poland", "Serbia", "Montenegro"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["politics", "economics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of the green photosynthetic pigment found in plants, algae, and cyanobacteria?",
    "answers":["Chlorophyll"],
    "options":["Carotenoids", "Anthocyanins", "Betalains"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["nature", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"1959 which became the 1st craft to leave Earth's gravity?",
    "answers":["Luna 1"],
    "options":["Explorer 1", "Barker 1", "Astroneer 1", "Sputnik 1"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"In 2007, the 110th United States Congress convened & elected who as the 1st female Speaker of the House?",
    "answers":["Nancy Pelosi"],
    "options":["Madeline Albright", "Kamala Harris", "Lisa Murkowski", "Sarah Palin"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Night Court premiered in 1984 starring which actor?",
    "answers":["Harry Anderson"],
    "options":["Don Johnson", "Harry Hamlin", "Scott Bakula", "Richard Dean Anderson", "Corbin Bernsen"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Trees photosynthesize",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["trees", "nature", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Hepatica, due to its resemblance to an organ can be called what?",
    "answers":["Liverleaf"],
    "options":["Heartleaf", "Lungeaf", "Brainleaf", "Kidneyleaf", "Intestineleaf"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["flowers", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Concussion, starring Will Smith, depicts which real world condition associated with repeated blows to the head?",
    "answers":["CTE"],
    "options":["CFR", "CLT", "CPE", "CPL", "CCE", "CCL", "CCR", "CCD", "CFD"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine", "film"]
},
{
    "question":"Rosemary Kennedy, JFK's sister spent most of her time in care after what?",
    "answers":["A lobotomy"],
    "options":["A car accident", "A mental break down", "A near drowning"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"In the brain, which lobe deals with sensory input like touch and temperature?",
    "answers":["Parietal lobe"],
    "options":["Frontal lobe", "Occipital lobe", "Temporal lobe"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"In the brain, which lobe deals with visual information?",
    "answers":["Occipital lobe"],
    "options":["Frontal lobe", "Parietal lobe", "Temporal lobe"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"In the brain, which lobe deals with auditory information?",
    "answers":["Temporal lobe"],
    "options":["Frontal lobe", "Parietal lobe", "Occipital lobe"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is not a lobe of the human briain?",
    "answers":["Olfactory lobe", "The Amygdalobe", "The Pruebalobe"],
    "options":["Frontal lobe", "Parietal lobe", "Occipital lobe", "Temporal lobe"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"How many types of tears are there?",
    "answers":["3"],
    "options":["2", "4", "5", "6", "7", "8", "9"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"What type of tear is for lubrication?",
    "answers":["Basal tears"],
    "options":["Reflex tears", "Man tears", "Emotional tears"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"What type of tear react to smoke/onion?",
    "answers":["Reflex tears"],
    "options":["Basal tears", "Man tears", "Emotional tears"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Who discovered blood types?",
    "answers":["Karl Landsteiner"],
    "options":["William T. G. Morton", "Louis Pasteur", "Joseph Murray", "David Hume"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Karl Landsteiner discovered blood types, where was he from?",
    "answers":["Austria"],
    "options":["Germany", "Estonia", "The United Kingdom", "Australia"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Which blood type can donate to everyone?",
    "answers":["O"],
    "options":["AB", "B", "A"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"A person with blood type A can donate to?",
    "answers":["AB and A"],
    "options":["A", "B", "O", "O and A", "AB and B"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"A person with blood type B can donate to?",
    "answers":["AB and B"],
    "options":["A", "AB", "B", "O and B", "O", "AB and A"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"A person with blood type AB can donate to?",
    "answers":["AB"],
    "options":["A and B", "O", "O, B and A", "AB, B and B"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the Eiffel tower built?",
    "answers":["1887"],
    "options":["1897", "1907", "1917", "1927", "1937"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Puberty starts earlier on average nowadays when compared with the past?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Puberty starts later on average nowadays when compared with the past?",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of the oldest potential ancestor for every known hominin species?",
    "answers":["Lucy"],
    "options":["Mary", "Debrah", "Eileen", "Samantha", "Britney", "Kate", "Rachel"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Based on 2020 United Nations Population Division estimates, which country has the highest life expectancy?",
    "answers":["Hong Kong"],
    "options":["Japan", "Italy", "Ireland", "Switzerland"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Based on 2020 United Nations Population Division estimates, which of these countries has the highest life expectancy?",
    "answers":["Hong Kong", "Japan", "Switzerland", "Singapore"],
    "options":["Italy", "Ireland", "Spain", "Australia", "Iceland", "South Korea"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Upper Volta is the former name of which country?",
    "answers":["Burkina Faso"],
    "options":["Iceland", "Ghana", "Rwanda", "Cameroon", "Tanzania", "Barbados", "Norway", "Sweden", "Myanmar"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president signed The Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act?",
    "answers":["Barak Obama"],
    "options":["Donald Trump", "George W. Bush", "Bill Clinton"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Which journalist published 'Hate Inc.' in 2019?",
    "answers":["Matt Taibbi"],
    "options":["Glenn Greenwald", "Lester Holt", "Fredricka Whitfield", "Christiane Amanpour", "Hu Shuli"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["books", "journalism"]
},
{
    "question":"In Mary Shelley's 'Frankenstein', what is Dr. Frankenstein's first name?",
    "answers":["Victor"],
    "options":["Glenn", "Lester", "Fredrick", "Christopher", "Richard", "Frank"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the first iPhone released?",
    "answers":["2007"],
    "options":["2009", "2006", "2005", "2004", "2008", "2003", "2002"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["technology"]
},
{
    "question":"In Amish culture, what is the name of the period when the adolsecents are allowed to live outside of the community?",
    "answers":["Rumspringa"],
    "options":["Mennonite", "Sugarcree", "Charm Days", "Golden Days", "Holy Columber Week", "Wristatcha"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["technology"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the nearest-known star to our Sun?",
    "answers":["Proxima Centauri"],
    "options":["Polaris", "Sirius", "Betelgeuse", "Vega", "Rigel", "Pleiades"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"What is term for the scenario where the expansion of the universe eventually reverses and the universe recollapses?",
    "answers":["The Big Crunch"],
    "options":["The Second Bang", "The Universal Reversal", "The Big Undoing", "The Reversal", "The Interim Rewind", "The Unbudding"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["astronomy", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"'God does not play dice' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Albert Einstein"],
    "options":["Nelson Mandela", "John Lennon", "Kurt Kobain", "Lao Tzu", "Harry S. Truman", "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Vincent Van Gough", "Douglas Adams", "Friedrich Nietzche", "John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Mohandas Gandhi", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Muhammad Ali", "Karl Marx", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'Lasciate ogne speranza, voi ch'intrate' is most frequently tranlated to mean what?",
    "answers":["Abandon all hope, ye who enter here"],
    "options":["I think, therefore I am", "Through adversity, to the stars", "the die, has already been cast", "I believe it, because it is absurd"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["quotes", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"Who won a Nobel Prize for their uncertainty principle?",
    "answers":["Werner Karl Heisenberg"],
    "options":["Erwin Schrödinger", "Carl David Anderson", "Enrico Fermi", "Otto Stern", "Ernest Orlando Lawrence"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Werner Karl Heisenberg won a Nobel Prize in 1932 in which category?",
    "answers":["Physics"],
    "options":["Chemistry", "Encomic Sciences", "Literature"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Werner Karl Heisenberg win a Nobel Prize for his uncertainty principle?",
    "answers":["1932"],
    "options":["1942", "1922", "1923", "1912", "1933"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the first Nobel Prize awarded?",
    "answers":["1901"],
    "options":["1891", "1881", "1897", "1887", "1892"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Gene comes from 'genos' Greek for what word?",
    "answers":["Birth"],
    "options":["Parent", "Tiny", "Mini", "Grape", "Small planet"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["language", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was the first scientist to be knighted?",
    "answers":["Isaac Newton"],
    "options":["Stephen Hawking", "Charles Darwin", "Alan Turing", "Alexander Fleming", "Albert Einstein"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Italy?",
    "answers":["Rome"],
    "options":["Venice", "Florence", "Milan", "Turin", "Naples"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Germany?",
    "answers":["Berlin"],
    "options":["Munich", "Frankfurt", "Hamburg", "Cologne", "Dresden"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Russia?",
    "answers":["Moscow"],
    "options":["Saint Petersburg", "Kazan", "Volgograd", "Novosibirsk"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Japan?",
    "answers":["Tokyo"],
    "options":["Beijing", "Osaka", "Hiroshima", "Kyoto", "Nagoya"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, who is the godess of the soul?",
    "answers":["Psyche"],
    "options":["Athena", "Aphrodite", "Aura", "Selene", "Styx"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["mythology"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, Psyche is the godess of what?",
    "answers":["The soul"],
    "options":["The mind", "Calmness", "The brain"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["mythology"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, Morpheus is the godess of what?",
    "answers":["Dreams"],
    "options":["War", "The Sea", "Fortune"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["mythology"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, who is the God of the sky?",
    "answers":["Zues"],
    "options":["Morpheus", "Hera", "Demeter", "Ares", "Apollo"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["mythology"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, Poseidon is the godess of what?",
    "answers":["The Sea"],
    "options":["War", "Dreams", "Fortune", "Music", "Fire"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["mythology"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, who is the God of war?",
    "answers":["Ares"],
    "options":["Morpheus", "Hera", "Demeter", "Zues", "Apollo"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["mythology"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, who is the God of the Moon?",
    "answers":["Artemis"],
    "options":["Morpheus", "Hera", "Demeter", "Zues", "Apollo", "Ares"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["mythology"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, who is the God of the Underworld?",
    "answers":["Hades"],
    "options":["Morpheus", "Hera", "Demeter", "Zues", "Apollo", "Ares", "Artemis"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["mythology"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Greek mythology, who is the God of the Revenge?",
    "answers":["Nemesis"],
    "options":["Morpheus", "Hera", "Demeter", "Zues", "Apollo", "Ares", "Artemis", "Hades"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["mythology"]
},
{
    "question":"'Primeval atom' was the original name intended for which scientific term?",
    "answers":["The Big Bang"],
    "options":["DNA", "Quantum theory", "Evolution by natural selection"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science"]
},
{
    "question":"Who played Andy Dufresne in 'The Shawshank Redemption'?",
    "answers":["Tim Robbins"],
    "options":["Harvey Keitel", "Philip Seymour Hoffman", "Tim Roth", "Morgan Freeman", "William H. Macy"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"In the original novel 'The Shawshank Redemption' was based on, what nationality was Red?",
    "answers":["Irish"],
    "options":["English", "American", "Australian", "Italian"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Who directed 'The Godfather' released in 1972?",
    "answers":["Francis Ford Coppola"],
    "options":["Martin Scorsese", "Steven Spielberg", "William Friedkin", "Robert Altman"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"'Leave the gun, take the cannoli' is a quote from which gangster film?",
    "answers":["The Godfather"],
    "options":["Gangs of New York", "Goodfellas", "A Bronx Tale", "American Gangster", "The Departed"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Who directed 2008's 'The Dark Knight'?",
    "answers":["Christopher Nolan"],
    "options":["Paul Thomas Anderson", "David Fincher", "Martin Scorsese", "Quentin Tarantino", "Darren Aronofsky"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Who played Batman in 2008's 'The Dark Knight'?",
    "answers":["Christian Bale"],
    "options":["Edward Cullen", "Ben Aflek", "Russell Crowe", "Viggo Mortensen", "Jake Gyllenhaal"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the first comic book movie to reach the $1 billion mark worldwide?",
    "answers":["The Dark Knight"],
    "options":["The Dark Knight Rises", "Spider-Man", "Iron Man", "Avengers Assemble", "Guardians of the Galaxy"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"A 1957 film features 12 men feeling what?",
    "answers":["Angry"],
    "options":["Happy", "Sad", "Fearful", "Digusted", "Hopeful"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which colour would you least assosiate with 'tawny'?",
    "answers":["Blue", "Red"],
    "options":["Orange", "Yellow", "Brown"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["colours"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find hte Harz Mountains?",
    "answers":["Germany"],
    "options":["Austria", "Sweden", "Finland", "Norway", "France", "Greece"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["colours"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of was the first programmable, electronic, general-purpose digital computer?",
    "answers":["ENIAC"],
    "options":["MANIAC", "ROBNIAC", "LYRIAC", "BORNIAC"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["technology", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was coffee introduced into Europe?",
    "answers":["17th century"],
    "options":["16th century", "15th century", "14th century", "18th century", "13th century", "12th century", "11th century"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["drinks", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"'Fools find no pleasure in understanding but delight in airing their own opinions', is from which Bible verse?",
    "answers":["Proverbs 18:2"],
    "options":["Matthew 18:2", "Genesis 18:2", "Leviticus 18:2", "Exodus 18:2"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["drinks", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"'Fools find no pleasure in understanding but delight in airing their own opinions', is from which Bible verse?",
    "answers":["Proverbs 18:2"],
    "options":["Matthew 18:2", "Genesis 18:2", "Leviticus 18:2", "Exodus 18:2"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["drinks", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"In 1954 the Americans tested their new hydrogen bomb at Bikini Atoll, which is located where?",
    "answers":["Marshall Islands"],
    "options":["Barbados", "The United States", "Canada", "Russia", "Costa Rica", "Bahamas", "Haiti", "Dominican Republic", "St Kitts and Nevis"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"The designer of the bikini was from which country?",
    "answers":["France"],
    "options":["Barbados", "The United States", "Canada", "Italy", "Greece", "Dominican Republic", "Japan"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["fashion"]
},
{
    "question":"The bikini was named after what?",
    "answers":["An island"],
    "options":["A tribe", "A star", "A beach", "A fruit", "A queen"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["fashion"]
},
{
    "question":"Which country was previously called Ceylon and before that Serendip?",
    "answers":["Sri Lanka"],
    "options":["Barbados", "Estonia", "Canada", "Russia", "Costa Rica", "Bahamas", "Haiti", "Dominican Republic", "St Kitts and Nevis", "Lethoso", "Liberia"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"Sappho was best known for what?",
    "answers":["Her poetry"],
    "options":["Her philosophy", "Her music", "Her cooking"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Lesbos is an island off the coast of which country?",
    "answers":["Turkey"],
    "options":["Greece", "Eritrea", "Cameroon", "Equitorial Guinea", "Gabon", "Ecuador"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Margherita pizza was named after what?",
    "answers":["A queen"],
    "options":["A tribe", "A star", "A beach", "A fruit", "An island"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["food", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"Raffaele Esposito is considered by some, the father or modern what?",
    "answers":["Pizza"],
    "options":["Football", "Fashion", "Philosophy", "Facism", "Socialism"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Raffaele Esposito is considered by some, the father or modern what?",
    "answers":["Pizza"],
    "options":["Football", "Fashion", "Philosophy", "Facism", "Socialism"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"'Let Hercules himself do what he may; The cat will mew and the dog will have his day' is a quote from which Shakespeare work?",
    "answers":["Hamlet"],
    "options":["Macbeth", "Romeo and Juliet", "The Tempest", "Measure for Measure"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes", "books"]
},
{
    "question":"As of 2020, which of these are the most produced food commodities in the world?",
    "answers":["Sugar cane", "Corn"],
    "options":["Rice", "Wheat", "Milk", "Potatoes"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Tuskegee Syphilis Study finally end?",
    "answers":["October 1972"],
    "options":["April 1952", "November 1932", "December 1912", "January 1882", "May 1862"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the term for a greyish-white crystalline deposit of frozen water vapour formed in clear still weather on vegetation, fences, etc.?",
    "answers":["Hoar frost"],
    "options":["Moar frost", "Boar frost", "Toar frost", "Soar frost", "Yoar frost"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["weather", "language"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the death penalty was abolished in the UK?",
    "answers":["1965"],
    "options":["1945", "1955", "1975", "1985", "1995", "1935", "1925", "1915"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["law", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the Old Bailey in London built?",
    "answers":["1965"],
    "options":["1945", "1955", "1975", "1985", "1995", "1935", "1925", "1915"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["architecture", "law", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the Old Bailey in London built?",
    "answers":["February 27th, 1907"],
    "options":["February 27th, 1807", "February 27th, 1707", "February 27th, 1937", "February 27th, 1737", "February 27th, 1837"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["architecture", "law", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"'Never attribute to malice that which is adequately explained by stupidity' is known as what?",
    "answers":["Hanlon's razor"],
    "options":["Occam's razor", "Hitchen's razor", "Hume's razor"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["proverb"]
},
{
    "question":"Jannet Parker was the to die of what?",
    "answers":["Smallpox"],
    "options":["MERS", "The Spanish Flu", "Rinderpest"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the Battle of Hastings fought?",
    "answers":["1066"],
    "options":["866", "966", "566", "766"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["war", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"The English faught in the Battle of Hastings under which King?",
    "answers":["Harold II"],
    "options":["William I", "William II", "Henry I", "Stephen", "Henry II"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["war", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Magna Carta is a royal charter of rights agreed to by which King?",
    "answers":["John"],
    "options":["William I", "William II", "Henry I", "Stephen", "Henry II"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["law", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Magna Carta originally published?",
    "answers":["13th century"],
    "options":["14th century", "12th century", "11th century", "10th century", "15th century"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["law", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What document was published in 1215 which, delineated a series of laws establishing the rights of English barons?",
    "answers":["Magna Carta"],
    "options":["Magnam Opus", "Magna Rechas", "Magna Derecha", "Magna Veritas"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["law", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"How many wives did Henry VIII have?",
    "answers":["6"],
    "options":["5", "4", "3", "2", "7", "8"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"How many of Henry VIII's wives were beheaded?",
    "answers":["2"],
    "options":["3", "4", "5", "1"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Martin Luther post his 95 Theses in Wittenberg?",
    "answers":["October 31st 1517"],
    "options":["July 20th 1417", "November 2nd 1617", "March 12th 1567", "April 3rd 1767", "April 13th 1667"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["religion", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"How many Theses did Martin Luther post in Wittenberg in 1517?",
    "answers":["95"],
    "options":["65", "75", "85", "90", "80", "70"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["religion", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the Great Bear Rainforest?",
    "answers":["Canada"],
    "options":["The United States", "Russia", "Poland", "Australia", "Scotland"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["religion", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which US President made the 'Four Freedoms' speech?",
    "answers":["Franklin Roosevelt"],
    "options":["Ronald Regan", "Gerald Fort", "John F. Kennedy", "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "Harry S. Truman"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Which US President made the 'Four Freedoms' speech?",
    "answers":["Franklin Roosevelt"],
    "options":["Ronald Regan", "Gerald Fort", "John F. Kennedy", "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "Harry S. Truman"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Which game show debuted on NBC-TV in 1975?",
    "answers":["Wheel Of Fortune"],
    "options":["Jeopardy!", "Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?", "Password"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Who has a leading role in the assassination of Julius Caeser?",
    "answers":["Brutus"],
    "options":["Glaucon", "Augustus", "Titus", "Vitus", "Albus"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the mythical substance that could turn ordinary metals such as iron, tin, lead, zinc, nickel or copper into precious metals like gold and silver?",
    "answers":["The philosopher's stone"],
    "options":["Manna", "Alien metal", "Tears of Ra"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["mythology"]
},
{
    "question":"The House of Lancaster was represented by what?",
    "answers":["A red rose"],
    "options":["A white rose", "A pink rose", "A peach rose"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["symbols", "flowers"]
},
{
    "question":"The House of York was represented by what?",
    "answers":["A white rose"],
    "options":["A red rose", "A pink rose", "A peach rose"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["symbols", "flowers"]
},
{
    "question":"During 1455 – 1485, a series of English civil wars between the House of Lancaster and the House of York is known as what?",
    "answers":["The Wars of the Roses"],
    "options":["The Wars of the Buttons", "The Wars of the Worlds", "The Wars of the Buckets"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["war", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Cromwell's men in 1649 killed 3500 people, known as 'The Siege of' what?",
    "answers":["The Siege of Drogheda"],
    "options":["The Siege of Kinsale", "The Siege of Westport", "The Siege of Dingle", "The Siege of Louth"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Where did the Great Fire of London start?",
    "answers":["Pudding Lane"],
    "options":["Threadneedle Street", "Savile Row", "Richmond Road", "Kingsway", "North Road", "Manor Road", "Queen Street"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"Where did the Great Fire of London start?",
    "answers":["Thomas Farriner's bakery"],
    "options":["Thomas Farriner's resturaunt", "Thomas Farriner's tavern", "Thomas Farriner's lightbulb store", "Thomas Farriner's candle shop"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Great Fire of London start?",
    "answers":["1666"],
    "options":["1766", "1566", "1466", "1366", "1316", "1416", "1516"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was carved into a fence on Roanoke Island after the dissapearance of the Lost Colony?",
    "answers":["CROATOAN"],
    "options":["ROANOKE", "A map of where they went", "MANTEO", "WANCHESE", "KILL DEVIL"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"1773 a protest by the Sons of Liberty became known as what?",
    "answers":["The Boston Tea Party"],
    "options":["The Boston Meat Party", "The Boston Mountain Dew Party", "The Boston Crab Party", "The Boston Caramel Party", "The Boston Watch Party"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did The Boston Tea Party take place?",
    "answers":["December 16, 1773"],
    "options":["December 16, 1673", "December 16, 1573", "December 16, 1873", "December 16, 1623", "December 16, 1723", "December 16, 1823"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"The Boston Tea Party was organized by which group?",
    "answers":["Sons of Liberty"],
    "options":["Black Panthers", "Paper Soldeirs", "Original Freedom Fighters", "Radical Nothings"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"The Sons of Liberty organized The Boston Tea Party, led by who?",
    "answers":["Samuel Adams"],
    "options":["James Otis", "Benjamin Rush", "Isaac Sears", "James Swan"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Slavery Abolition Act banned slavery in all British colonies?",
    "answers":["1833"],
    "options":["1933", "1733", "1633", "1683", "1783", "1983"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["law"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Slavery Abolition Act banned slavery in all British colonies?",
    "answers":["1833"],
    "options":["1933", "1733", "1633", "1683", "1783", "1983"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["law", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries was first to ban slavery?",
    "answers":["Britain"],
    "options":["Brazil", "Portugal", "Cuba"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["law", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Scurvy is caused by a lack of which vitamin?",
    "answers":["Vitamin C"],
    "options":["Vitamin K", "Vitamin A", "Vitamin D"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Scurvy is caused by a lack of which vitamin?",
    "answers":["Vitamin C"],
    "options":["Vitamin K", "Vitamin A", "Vitamin D"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"The Great Exhibition, an international exhibition, took place from 1 May from 15 October 1851, where?",
    "answers":["London"],
    "options":["Paris", "Liverpool", "Amsterdam"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the first scheduled train service opened in Britain?",
    "answers":["1830"],
    "options":["1850", "1870", "1820", "1800", "1780", "1760", "1740", "1720"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["transport", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the first scheduled train service opened in Britain?",
    "answers":["1830"],
    "options":["1850", "1870", "1820", "1800", "1780", "1760", "1740", "1720"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["transport", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Voltaire, 'No snowflake' in what 'ever feels responsible'?",
    "answers":["An avalanche"],
    "options":["A snowstorm", "A snowman", "A snowball", "A storm"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Carl Jung, 'The foundation of all mental illness is the avoidance of true' what?",
    "answers":["Suffering"],
    "options":["Acceptance", "Help", "Therapy", "Goodness", "Benevolence"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'Man often becomes what he believes himself to be' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Mohandas Gandhi"],
    "options":["Nelson Mandela", "John Lennon", "Kurt Kobain", "Lao Tzu", "Harry S. Truman", "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Vincent Van Gough", "Douglas Adams", "Friedrich Nietzche", "John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Albert Einstein", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Muhammad Ali", "Karl Marx", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"'Change is the only constant' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Heraclitus"],
    "options":["Shakespeare", "Herodotus", "Plato", "Karl Marx", "Aristotle", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Anazimander", "Socrates", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"According to Heraclitus, what 'Change 'Is the only constant'?",
    "answers":["Change"],
    "options":["Love", "Time", "Friendship", "Humanity", "Nothing"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Which scientist wrote Principia?",
    "answers":["Isaac Newton"],
    "options":["Stephen Hawking", "Charles Darwin", "Alan Turing", "Alexander Fleming", "Albert Einstein"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["books", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Principia, by Isaac Newton, published?",
    "answers":["1687"],
    "options":["1787", "1707", "1727", "1747", "1767"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["books", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Principia, by Isaac Newton, was written in which language?",
    "answers":["Latin"],
    "options":["English", "Spanish", "French", "German"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["books", "language", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"The Big Splash is a hypothesis that a large object/planet hit the Earth causing to debree to shoot off into space, what is the large object known as?",
    "answers":["Theia"],
    "options":["Favus", "Gallina", "Motus", "Corpus", "Terra", "Caeleb", "Merces"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of the hypothesis that a large object/planet called Theia hit the Earth causing to debree to shoot off into space, what is the large object known as?",
    "answers":["The Big Splash"],
    "options":["The Big Crunch", "The Big Bang", "The Big Whip", "The Big Crash", "The Big Wrecking", "The Big Wreckingball"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["astronomy", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Is the moon moving farther from the Earth?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["astronomy", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Is the moon moving closer to the Earth?",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["astronomy", "science"]
},
{
    "question":"Approximately how often does the moon orbit the Earth?",
    "answers":["27 days"],
    "options":["1 day", "8 days", "15 days", "22 days", "25 days", "1 year"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the largest moon in the solar system?",
    "answers":["Ganynede"],
    "options":["Titan", "Callisto", "Io", "Moon", "Europa"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"The largest moon in the solar system, belongs to which planet?",
    "answers":["Jupiter"],
    "options":["Saturn", "Neptune", "Earth", "Uranus"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is not a moon of Jupiter?",
    "answers":["Titan", "Callisto", "Triton", "Ariel"],
    "options":["Ganynede", "Io", "Europa"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["astronomy"]
},
{
    "question":"Who wrote the Great Gatsby?",
    "answers":["F. Scott Fitzgerald"],
    "options":["Anthony Burgess", "Virginia Woolf", "Ernest Hemingway", "John Steinbeck", "D. H. Lawrence", "Aldous Huxley"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"Who wrote 'Brave New World'?",
    "answers":["Aldous Huxley"],
    "options":["Anthony Burgess", "Virginia Woolf", "Ernest Hemingway", "John Steinbeck", "D. H. Lawrence", "F. Scott Fitzgerald"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"When was the Great Gatsby published?",
    "answers":["1925"],
    "options":["1955", "1975", "1985", "1965", "1945"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Spanish Flu start?",
    "answers":["1918"],
    "options":["1916", "1914", "1920", "1922", "1924"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Spanish Flu end?",
    "answers":["1920"],
    "options":["1916", "1914", "1918", "1922", "1924"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Where is the city of Odessa?",
    "answers":["Ukraine"],
    "options":["Russia", "Romania", "Poland", "Slovakia", "Lithuania", "Belarus"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What Indian city was previously called Bombay?",
    "answers":["Mumbai"],
    "options":["Kolkata", "Bengaluru", "Hyderabad", "New Delhi"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"To what religion does the Talmud belong to?",
    "answers":["Judaism"],
    "options":["Islam", "Hinduism", "Buddhism"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["religion"]
},
{
    "question":"Where is the Ebola River?",
    "answers":["Democratic Republic of the Congo"],
    "options":["Lesotho", "Burundi", "Guinea-Bissau", "Central African Republic", "Cameroon"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"What spreads Dengue fever?",
    "answers":["Mosquitos"],
    "options":["Flies", "Dogs", "Mites", "Fleas", "Rodents"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these South American countries does the Andes not extend through?",
    "answers":["Brazil", "Peru", "Guyana", "Uruguay", "Paraguay"],
    "options":["Venezuela", "Colombia", "Ecuador", "Bolivia", "Chile", "Argentina"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"The Boxer Rebellion was an uprising in which country?",
    "answers":["China"],
    "options":["Brazil", "Germany", "The United States", "Australia", "Britain", "Whales"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["history"]
},
{
    "question":"The Family is an unfinished 1918 painting by who?",
    "answers":["Egon Schiele"],
    "options":["David Smith", "Paul Cézanne", "Alberto Giacometti", "Henry Moore"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"Who painted 'The Scream' in 1893?",
    "answers":["Edward Munch"],
    "options":["David Smith", "Paul Cézanne", "Alberto Giacometti", "Henry Moore", "Charles C. Ingham"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the opposite effect of placebo?",
    "answers":["Nocebo effect"],
    "options":["Anticebo effect", "Sincebo effect", "Noncebo effect", "Neincebo effect"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Alaska was purchased by the United States from which country?",
    "answers":["Russia"],
    "options":["China", "Canada", "Mexico", "The United Kingdom"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When was Alaska purchased by the United States from Russia?",
    "answers":["1867"],
    "options":["1887", "1877", "1897", "1907", "1917", "1927"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"The first recorded case of Spanish flu was from where?",
    "answers":["The United States"],
    "options":["The United Kingdom", "France", "Germany", "Libya", "Tunisia", "China", "Taiwan"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["medicine", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"The first recorded case of Spanish flu was from which state?",
    "answers":["Kansas"],
    "options":["Georgia", "Pennsylvania", "Michigan", "Nevada", "Colorado", "Alabama", "Indiana", "Utah", "Wyonming", "Nebraska", "Oklahoma", "North Dakota"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["medicine", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"The first recorded was from which month?",
    "answers":["January"],
    "options":["Febuary", "March", "April", "May", "June", "July", "August", "September", "October", "November", "December"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["medicine", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"The Battle of the Somme was faught during which war?",
    "answers":["World War 1"],
    "options":["World War 2", "Vietnam War", "Korean War"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["war", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"In what year did The Battle of the Somme take place?",
    "answers":["1916"],
    "options":["1914", "1915", "1917", "1918", "1919"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["war", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which capital was previously called Kristiania?",
    "answers":["Oslo, Norway"],
    "options":["Abuja, Nigeria", "Monrovia, Liberia", "Mogadishu, Somalia", "St. John's, Antigua and Barbuda", "Vientiane, Laos", "Lisbon, Portugal", "Kigali, Rwanda"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Somalia?",
    "answers":["Mogadishu"],
    "options":["Merca", "Bosaso", "Kismayo", "Galkayo", "Hargeisa", "Garowe", "Baidoa"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the capital of Liberia?",
    "answers":["Monrovia"],
    "options":["Zwedru", "Ganta", "Kakata", "Harper"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Einstein publish his theory of relativity?",
    "answers":["1915"],
    "options":["1925", "1935", "1945"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["science", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Samoa gained independence from which country in 1962?",
    "answers":["New Zealand"],
    "options":["The United States", "The United Kingdom", "France", "Portugal", "Sweden"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"What was the name of the non-violent movement for Samoa independence?",
    "answers":["Mau"],
    "options":["Sau", "Lau", "Pau", "Vau", "Zau", "Tau", "Bau", "Cau"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Samoa gain independence from New Zealand?",
    "answers":["1962"],
    "options":["1952", "1942", "1932", "1922", "1912", "1902"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Egypt gained independence from which country in 1922?",
    "answers":["Britain"],
    "options":["The United States", "France", "Portugal", "Sweden"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"When did Egypt gain independence from Britain?",
    "answers":["1922"],
    "options":["1912", "1932", "1942", "1952", "1962"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which was president was Woodrow Wilson?",
    "answers":["28th"],
    "options":["29th", "30th", "31st", "32nd", "27th"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"Which president had a stroke in office?",
    "answers":["Woodrow Wilson"],
    "options":["Thomas Jefferson", "William McKinley", "Herbert Hoover", "Harry S. Truman", "Lydon B. Johnson"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics", "history"]
},
{
    "question":"'There is nothing either good or bad, but thinking makes it so' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Shakespeere"],
    "options":["Heraclitus", "Herodotus", "Plato", "Karl Marx", "Aristotle", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Anazimander", "Socrates", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"What connects the two hemispheres of the brain?",
    "answers":["Corpus callosum"],
    "options":["Brain Stem", "Pons", "Central sulcus", "Pineal body"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of the symptom of various memory disorders in which made-up stories fill in any gaps in memory?",
    "answers":["Confabulation"],
    "options":["Palaver", "Byzabtube", "Sulcus", "Discountenance"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"What hand syndrome is a phenomenon in which one hand is not under control of the mind?",
    "answers":["Alien"],
    "options":["Foreign", "Stranger", "External", "Novel", "Odd", "Non-native"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"'Things won are done; joy's soul lies in the doing' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Shakespeere"],
    "options":["Heraclitus", "Herodotus", "Plato", "Karl Marx", "Aristotle", "Confucius", "Damascus", "René Descartes", "Epictetus", "Anazimander", "Socrates", "Anaxagoras", "Lao Tzu"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Which hormone is known as 'The love drug'?",
    "answers":["Oxytocin"],
    "options":["Prolactin", "Testosterone", "Thyroxine", "Leptin", "Kisspeptin", "Cortisol"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["medicine"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these is not a book by Johnathon Haidt?",
    "answers":["Entangled Life"],
    "options":["The Righteous Mind", "The Happiness Hypothesis", "The Coddling of the American Mind"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"In January 2020, Netflix released a controversial film by Maïmouna Doucouré, called what?",
    "answers":["Cuties"],
    "options":["Babes", "Chics", "Dolls", "Honies", "Little angels"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"'A lie gets halfway around the world before the truth has a chance to get its pants on' is a quote from whom?",
    "answers":["Winston Churchill"],
    "options":["Mohandas Gandhi", "Nelson Mandela", "John Lennon", "Kurt Kobain", "Lao Tzu", "Harry S. Truman", "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Vincent Van Gough", "Douglas Adams", "Friedrich Nietzche", "John Steinbeck", "Indira Gandi", "Arthur C. Clarke", "Ursula Le Guin", "Albert Einstein", "Ella Wheller Wilcox", "Charles Darwin", "René Descartes", "Isaac Newton", "Stephen Hawking", "Marthin Luther King Jr.", "Ronald Regan", "George Orwell", "Muhammad Ali", "Karl Marx", "Stephen Jobs", "Bill Gates"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"Farmatodo is a pharmacy founded in which country?",
    "answers":["Venezuela"],
    "options":["Spain", "Brazil", "Portugal", "Sweden", "Norway", "Colombia", "Guyana"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Hugo Chavez became president of which country in 1998?",
    "answers":["Venezuela"],
    "options":["Spain", "Brazil", "Portugal", "Colombia", "Guyana"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"How did Hugo Chavez die in 2013?",
    "answers":["Cancer"],
    "options":["Hanging", "Assassination", "Poisoning", "Car crash", "Plane crash", "Heart attack"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Who became president of Venezuela in 1998?",
    "answers":["Hugo Chavez"],
    "options":["Nicolás Maduro", "Rafael Caldera", "Carlos Andrés Pérez"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Harina P.A.N. is a flour often used to make which Venezuelan dish?",
    "answers":["Arepa"],
    "options":["Moqueca", "Quindim", "Feijoada"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["food"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these countries is not a part of Opec (Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries)?",
    "answers":["Brazil", "Mexico", "Uganda", "Tanzania", "Bahrain", "Vietnam", "Botswana", "Oman", "Senegal", "Colombia", "Peru"],
    "options":["Algeria", "Angola", "Congo", "Ecuador", "Equatorial Guinea", "Gabon", "Iran", "Iraq", "Kuwait", "Libya", "Nigeria", "Qatar", "Saudi Arabia", "United Arab Emirates", "Venezuela"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Second Congo War start?",
    "answers":["1998"],
    "options":["1988", "1978", "1968", "1958", "1948", "1938"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["war"]
},
{
    "question":"When did the Second Congo War end?",
    "answers":["2003"],
    "options":["1993", "1983", "1973", "1963", "1953", "1943", "1933"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["war"]
},
{
    "question":"Who directed Schindler's List?",
    "answers":["Steven Spielberg"],
    "options":["David Fincher", "Peter Weir", "Gus Van Sant", "Robert Zemeckis", "Michael Mann"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Steven Spielberg offered the Schindler's List directors job to which director?",
    "answers":["Roman Polanski"],
    "options":["David Fincher", "Peter Weir", "Gus Van Sant", "Robert Zemeckis", "Michael Mann"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Gandalf and Aragorn are characters in which film series?",
    "answers":["The Lord of the Rings"],
    "options":["Harry Potter", "Star Wars", "The Avengers", "X-Men"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"The last spoken line of which 'The Lord of the Rings' movies is 'Well, I'm back'?",
    "answers":["The Return of the King"],
    "options":["The Two Towers", "The Fellowship of the Ring", "The Hobbit"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"In the Lord of the Rings, what is Frodo's second name?",
    "answers":["Baggins"],
    "options":["Broggins", "Bleggings", "Biggins", "Buggings"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"In the Lord of the Rings, what is Bilbo's relationship to Frodo?",
    "answers":["Uncle"],
    "options":["Brother", "Cousin", "Grandfather", "Father"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Was 'Pulp Fiction' nominated for Best Picture at the Oscars?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Was 'Interview With a Vampire' nominated for Best Picture at the Oscars?",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which of these actors was not in Pulp Fiction?",
    "answers":["Nicolas Cage"],
    "options":["John Travolta", "Uma Thurman", "Samuel L. Jackson"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"In which of these Quentin Tarantino films did he not make a visual cameo?",
    "answers":["Once Upon A Time in Hollywood"],
    "options":["Django Unchained", "Reservoir Dogs", "Pulp Fiction", "Inglourious Basterds"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["film"]
},
{
    "question":"Which country is shaped like a stiletto boot?",
    "answers":["Italy"],
    "options":["Hungary", "Eswatini", "Puerto Rico", "United Arab Emirates", "Bosnia and Herzegovina", "Poland"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["geography"]
},
{
    "question":"When Henry Kissinger said 'A dagger pointed at the heart of Antarctica', which country was he referring to?",
    "answers":["Chile"],
    "options":["Hungary", "Argentina", "Puerto Rico", "United Arab Emirates", "Bosnia and Herzegovina", "Namibia", "Madagascar", "India"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["geography", "quotes"]
},
{
    "question":"CHON is an acronym for the four most common elements in living ogranisms, what is the C?",
    "answers":["Carbon"],
    "options":["Calcium", "Chlorine", "Cobalt", "Curium"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"CHON is an acronym for the four most common elements in living ogranisms, what is the H?",
    "answers":["Hydrogen"],
    "options":["Helium", "Hassium", "Hafnium"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"CHON is an acronym for the four most common elements in living ogranisms, what is the O?",
    "answers":["Oxygen"],
    "options":["Osmium", "Oganesson", "Orange peel"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["science", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"CHON is an acronym for the four most common elements in living ogranisms, what is the N?",
    "answers":["Nitrogen"],
    "options":["Neon", "Nickel", "Nihonium"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"There is an element called Neon?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"There is an element called Nearium?",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"There is an element called Niobium?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["science", "nature"]
},
{
    "question":"Who wrote Les Miserables?",
    "answers":["Victor Hugo"],
    "options":["George Elio", "Nathaniel Hawthorne", "Leo Tolstoy", "Gustav Flaubert", "Giacomo Leopardi"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"Where is Les Miserables mainly set?",
    "answers":["Paris"],
    "options":["Rome", "Berlin", "Dublin", "Madrid"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["books"]
},
{
    "question":"Guano is the feces of which of these animals used as ferilizer?",
    "answers":["Seabird", "Bats"],
    "options":["Bear", "Oryx", "Deer", "Elephant", "Kangaroo", "Squirrel", "Lion"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Who was the first president of the United States?",
    "answers":["George Washingston"],
    "options":["John Adams", "Thomas Jefferson", "Abraham Lincoln", "Benjamin Franklin"],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "categories":["politics"]
},
{
    "question":"Who replaced Jay Leno as the host of 'The Tonight Show'?",
    "answers":["Jimmy Fallon"],
    "options":["David Letterman", "Jimmy Kimmel", "Bill Maher", "Conan O’Brien", "Stephen Colbert"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"In 2008, Johnathon Ross left the BBC after he and which comedian prank called Andrew Sachs?",
    "answers":["Russel Brand"],
    "options":["Frankie Boyle", "Sarah Silverman", "Dave Chappelle", "Louis C.K", "Stephen Colbert", "Joe Rogan"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["TV"]
},
{
    "question":"Polygamy is having more than one wife or husband at a time?",
    "answers":["True"],
    "options":["False"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Monogamy is having more than one wife or husband at a time?",
    "answers":["False"],
    "options":["True"],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"Who shot and killed Billy the Kid?",
    "answers":["Sheriff Pat Garrett"],
    "options":["Sheriff Arlo Mcfarland", "Sheriff Emmett Morgan", "Sheriff William Woodcock", "Sheriff Frankie Turner", "Sheriff Oscar Gilbert"],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "categories":["misc"]
},
{
    "question":"What is the name of the piece at the start of an opera or play?",
    "answers":["Overture"],
    "options":["Coda", "Opus", "Rhapsody", "Sonata"],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories":["art"]
},
{
    "question":"Where would you find the city of Sacramento?",
    "answers":["California"],
    "options":["Illinois", "Massachusetts", "Washingston", "Pennsylvania", "Michigan", "Louisiana", "Colorado", "Texas", "Oregan", "Arizona", "Tennessee", "Florida", "North Carolina", "Georgia", "Minnesota", "Nevada"],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories":["geography"]
}


]
